<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ead PUBLIC "+//ISBN 1-931666-00-8//DTD ead.dtd (Encoded Archival Description (EAD) Version 2002)//EN" "http://www.asu.edu/asuns/dtd/ead.dtd">
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="displaytemplate.xsl"?>
<?filetitle Udall, Jesse A. papers?>
<ead relatedencoding="MARC21">
<eadheader audience="internal" findaidstatus="edited-full-draft"
 langencoding="iso639-2b">
	<eadid encodinganalog="856$u">PUBLIC "-//University of Arizona Library Special Collections//text(US::AzU::Jesse A. Udall Papers)//en"
	 "UAMS311.xml"</eadid>
  <filedesc> 
	 <titlestmt> 
		<titleproper encodinganalog="245$a">Jesse A. Udall papers, 
		  <date>circa. 1882-1981 (bulk, 1935-1978)</date></titleproper> 
		<author encodinganalog="245$c">Inventory prepared by Peter Steere and
		  Penny Whitten.</author>
	 </titlestmt>
	 <publicationstmt>
	 	<publisher encodinganalog="260$b">University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections</publisher> 
		<address>
		  <addressline>PO Box 210055</addressline> 
		  <addressline>Tucson, AZ 85721-0055</addressline>
		  <addressline>Phone: 520-621-6423</addressline>
		  <addressline>Fax: 520-621-9733</addressline>
		  <addressline>URL: http://speccoll.library.arizona.edu/</addressline>
		</address>
		<date>&#x00A9; 2001</date> 
		<p>Arizona Board of Regents. All Rights Reserved.</p>
	 </publicationstmt> 
  </filedesc> 
  <profiledesc>
	 <creation encodinganalog="500">Encoded by Shan Sutton.
		<date>December 13, 2000</date></creation> 
	 <langusage>Inventory is in<language langcode="en"
		encodinganalog="546">English.</language></langusage> 
  </profiledesc> 
</eadheader> 
<frontmatter>
  <titlepage>
	 <titleproper encodinganalog="245$a">Jesse A. Udall papers, 
		<date>circa. 1882-1981 (bulk, 1935-1978)</date></titleproper>
	 <num>Collection Number: MS 311</num>
  	<publisher encodinganalog="260$b">University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections</publisher>
	 <list>
		<defitem>
		  <label>Processed by: </label>
		  <item>Peter Steere and Penny Whitten</item>
		</defitem>
		<defitem>
		  <label>Date completed:</label>
		  <item>
			 <date>May, 1994</date></item>
		</defitem>
		<defitem>
		  <label>Finding aid encoded by:</label>
		  <item>Shan Sutton</item>
		</defitem>
	 </list>
	 <p>&#x00A9; 2001 Arizona Board of Regents. All rights reserved.</p>
  </titlepage>
</frontmatter>
<archdesc level="collection"> 
  <did id="a1">
	 <head>Collection Summary</head>
	 <unittitle encodinganalog="245" label="Collection Name:">Jesse A. Udall
		papers, 
		<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="NaN/NaN">circa. 1882-1981 (bulk,
		  1935-1978)</unitdate></unittitle>
	 <unitid label="Collection Number:" encodinganalog="099"
	  repositorycode="AzU" countrycode="us">MS 311</unitid> 
	 <origination label="Creator:"> 
		<persname encodinganalog="100">Udall, Jesse Addison,
		  1893-1980</persname></origination>
	 <abstract label="Abstract:">This collection is organized into two series:
		Personal and Family Papers; and Professional Papers. The Personal and Family
		Papers series includes biographical summaries; clippings documenting honors and
		personal and family achievements; a few miscellaneous church related items;
		retirement records and correspondence; certificates and awards from various
		civic organizations; and correspondence and clippings pertaining to son Addison
		Udall's World War II experiences. </abstract>
	 <physdesc encodinganalog="300$a" label="Physical Description:"><extent
		encodinganalog="300">.75 linear feet</extent></physdesc>
	 <repository label="Repository:">
	 	<corpname encodinganalog="110">University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections</corpname>
		<address>
		  <addressline>University of Arizona </addressline>
		  <addressline>PO Box 210055</addressline> 
		  <addressline>Tucson, AZ 85721-0055</addressline>
		  <addressline>Phone: 520-621-6423</addressline>
		  <addressline>Fax: 520-621-9733</addressline>
		  <addressline>URL: http://speccoll.library.arizona.edu/</addressline>
		</address></repository>
  </did> 
  <accessrestrict encodinganalog="506">
	 <head>Restrictions</head>
	 <p>None.</p>
  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict encodinganalog="540">
	 <head>Copyright</head>
	 <p>It is the responsibility of the user to obtain permission to publish
		from the owner of the copyright (the institution, the creator of the record,
		the author or his/her transferees, heirs, legates, or literary executors). The
		user agrees to indemnify and hold harmless the Arizona Board of Regents for the
		University of Arizona, its officers, employees, and agents from and against all
		claims made by any person asserting that he or she is an owner of
		copyright.</p>
  </userestrict>
  <prefercite encodinganalog="524">
	 <head>Credit Line</head>
	 <p>Jesse A. Udall papers(MS 311). Special Collections, University of Arizona Libraries.</p>
  </prefercite>
  <bioghist id="a2" encodinganalog="545"> 
	 <head>Biographical Note</head>
	 <p>Jesse Udall was born on June 24, 1893 in Eagar, Arizona, one of six
		children of Mormon settlers David King Udall and Ida Hunt. He attended
		elementary and high schools in St. Johns, Hunt, and Snowflake, Arizona, and
		graduated in 1914 from Gila Academy (now Eastern Arizona Junior College) in
		Thatcher, Arizona. In 1917 he wed Lela Lee (1895-1976). They had six
		children.</p> 
	 <p>Following service as an Army ambulance driver in France during World War
		I, Udall graduated from the University of Arizona Law School in 1924, and
		established a private practice in Safford. A Republican, he was elected County
		Attorney for Graham County, a position he held in 1925 and 1926. Returning to
		private practice, he served as a state legislator from Graham County from 1931
		to 1935. He was elected Graham County Superior Court Judge in November
		1938.</p>
	 <p>In 1926 and 1927, Udall helped organize a National Guard unit, 158th
		Infantry Company G, in Safford. He became captain of the unit in 1928, and five
		years later was promoted to major in the Judge Advocate Department. As
		Lieutenant Colonel in 1942 he was called to active duty in Washington, D. C.,
		where he served as Chief of the Review Section of the Internal Security
		Division, and later as a member of the Industrial Employment Review Board.
		Returning to Safford in 1945, Udall resumed his private law practice. He was a
		member of the Arizona Interstate Stream Commission from 1948 to 1953, and was
		appointed Graham County Superior Court Judge from 1953 to 1958. He served the
		Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-Day Saints in the presidency of it's Southern
		California Mission from 1958 to 1960. He resigned that position when he was
		appointed to fill the Arizona Supreme Court seat vacated by the death of Levi
		Udall. He was elected to that seat in 1960, 1964 and 1970, and retired in 1972
		due to the poor health of his wife Lela. He served as Chief Justice in 1964 and
		1969.</p>
	 <p>Udall married Lillian Cliff Jenkins in 1977. Throughout his life he was
		active in the Mormon Church, serving as bishop of Thatcher Ward, president of
		St. Joseph Stake, and patriarch of Tempe Stake. He was also active in a number
		of service organizations, including the Boy Scouts and Rotary Club. He died of
		heart failure on May 11, 1980.</p>
  </bioghist> 
  <arrangement> 
	 <head>Organization</head> 
	 <p>This collection is organized into two series:</p> 
	 <list> 
		<item>I. Personal and Family Papers, 
		  <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="NaN/1981">circa.
			 1882-1981</unitdate></item> 
		<item>II. Professional Papers, 
		  <unitdate type="inclusive"
			normal="1918/1979">1918-1979</unitdate></item>
	 </list> 
  </arrangement>
  <scopecontent id="a3" encodinganalog="520"> 
	 <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
	 <p>This collection is organized into two series: Personal and Family
		Papers; and Professional Papers. The Personal and Family Papers series includes
		biographical summaries; clippings documenting honors and personal and family
		achievements; a few miscellaneous church related items; retirement records and
		correspondence; certificates and awards from various civic organizations; and
		correspondence and clippings pertaining to son Addison Udall's World War II
		experiences. </p> 
	 <p>The Professional Papers series relates to his military and legal
		careers, and contains primarily correspondence, clippings, and speeches. Other
		miscellaneous documents include military orders, certificates, Arizona election
		results from 1960 to 1970, a list of opinions authored by Jesse Udall, and
		documents pertaining to the operation of the Arizona National Guard Unit in
		Safford between 1930 and 1940.</p>
	 <p>Most of the material in this series covers either the span of Udall's
		National Guard and subsequent Army involvement, 1930 to 1945, or his tenure on
		the Arizona State Supreme Court, 1960 to 1972. There is little relating to his
		legal career prior to 1960. Other events falling within the scope of this
		subgroup are his service on the Arizona Interstate Stream Commission and a
		post-retirement effort to persuade some U. S. Congressmen of the merits of
		purchasing a corridor through Mexico from Arizona to the Gulf of California.
		This collection contains none of the correspondence or papers generated by
		Udall in his capacity as lawyer or judge.</p>
  </scopecontent> 
  <controlaccess id="a12">
	 <head>Access Terms</head>
	 <list>
		<item>
		  <persname encodinganalog="100">Udall, Jesse Addison, 1893-1980 --
			 Archives</persname></item>
		<item>
		  <persname encodinganalog="100">Udall, Lela Lee,
			 1895-1976</persname></item>
		<item>
		  <famname encodinganalog="100">Udall Family -- Archives</famname></item>
		<item>
		  <corpname encodinganalog="110">Arizona -- Supreme
			 Court</corpname></item>
		<item>
		  <corpname encodinganalog="110">Arizona -- National
			 Guard</corpname></item>
		<item>
		  <subject>Mormons -- Arizona</subject></item>
		<item>
		  <subject>Judges -- Arizona -- Archives</subject></item>
		<item>
		  <genreform>Clippings</genreform></item>
		<item>
		  <genreform>Correspondence</genreform></item>
		<item>
		  <genreform>Speeches</genreform></item>
		<item>
		  <genreform>Photographs</genreform></item>
	 </list>
  </controlaccess> 
  <separatedmaterial encodinganalog="544$2">
	 <head>Separated Material</head>
	 <p>Some duplicate printed material and six military charge sheets were
		deaccessioned from the collection. One photo postcard was removed and put into
		the Arizona Southwest Collection under Fort Tuthill. Three items relating to
		other Udall family members were transferred to the Special Collections
		biographical files.</p>
  </separatedmaterial>
  <dsc type="combined" id="a23"> 
	 <head>Container List</head>
	 <c01 level="series" id="ser1"> 
		<did>
		  <unittitle>Series I: Personal and Family Papers, 
			 <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="NaN/1981">circa.
				1882-1981</unitdate></unittitle> 
		</did> 
		<c02>
		  <did><container type="box">1</container><container
			 type="folder">1</container>
			 <unittitle>Biographical information.
				<unitdate type="inclusive"
				 normal="1893/1981">1893-1981</unitdate></unittitle>
		  </did>
		  <scopecontent>
			 <p>Contains summaries of Udall's life, some in newspaper clippings
				and some apparently prepared by Udall himself. Also contains bibliographic
				information.</p>
		  </scopecontent>
		</c02>
		<c02>
		  <did><container type="box">1</container><container
			 type="folder">2</container>
			 <unittitle>Clippings.
				<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="">1942-1979 and
				  undated</unitdate></unittitle>
		  </did>
		  <scopecontent>
			 <p>Contains clippings, the bulk from 1960 and later, relating to
				Udall's awards and speeches. Activities of Lela and son David, as well as
				members of his extended family, are also included.</p>
		  </scopecontent>
		</c02>
		<c02>
		  <did><container type="box">1</container><container
			 type="folder">3</container>
			 <unittitle>Addison Udall: Letters and clippings.
				<unitdate type="inclusive"
				 normal="1945">1945</unitdate></unittitle>
		  </did>
		  <scopecontent>
			 <p>Contains two letters from son Addison while stationed in San
				Francisco, plus clippings about the war effort in the Pacific.</p>
		  </scopecontent>
		</c02>
		<c02>
		  <did><container type="box">1</container><container
			 type="folder">4</container>
			 <unittitle>Retirement.
				<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1976">1972,
				  1976</unitdate></unittitle>
		  </did>
		  <scopecontent>
			 <p>Contains Udall's letter of resignation from the Supreme Court, his
				request for retirement benefits, and letters of appreciation and support from
				friends and associates, most written in early 1972.</p>
		  </scopecontent>
		</c02>
		<c02>
		  <did><container type="box">1</container><container
			 type="folder">5</container>
			 <unittitle>Miscellaneous church material.
				<unitdate type="inclusive"
				normal="1926/1970">1926-1970</unitdate></unittitle>
		  </did>
		  <scopecontent>
			 <p>Contains a membership certificate, a dedicatory service program to
				the Thatcher Ward Chapel, two clippings on his California Mission presidency,
				and a program and clipping relating to a Master M Man youth service award.</p>
		  </scopecontent>
		</c02>
		<c02>
		  <did><container type="box">1</container><container
			 type="folder">6</container>
			 <unittitle>Awards and certificates.
				<unitdate type="inclusive"
				normal="1940/1970">1940-1970</unitdate></unittitle>
		  </did>
		  <scopecontent>
			 <p>Contains awards and certificates from various organizations
				including the Selective Service System, Kiwanis, Boy Scouts, American
				Judicature Society, and Rotary Club.</p>
		  </scopecontent>
		</c02>
		<c02>
		  <did><container type="box">1</container><container
			 type="folder">7</container>
			 <unittitle>Photographs.
				<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="NaN/1975">circa.
				  1882-1975</unitdate></unittitle>
		  </did>
		  <scopecontent>
			 <p>Contains one color and twenty-three black and white photographs.
				The earliest photo of Jesse Udall is from 1912. Included are school photos,
				family photos, and individual portraits.</p>
		  </scopecontent>
		</c02>
	 </c01> 
	 <c01 level="series">
		<did>
		  <unittitle>Series II: Professional Papers, 
			 <unitdate type="inclusive"
			 normal="1918/1979">1918-1979</unitdate></unittitle>
		</did>
		<c02>
		  <did><container type="box">2</container><container
			 type="folder">1</container>
			 <unittitle>Correspondence.
				<unitdate type="inclusive"
				normal="1938/1978">1938-1978</unitdate></unittitle>
		  </did>
		  <scopecontent>
			 <p>Mostly incoming letters during his tenure on the Arizona Supreme
				Court, consisting primarily of congratulatory messages for his initial
				appointment, elections, and attainment of Chief Justice in 1964. Other
				correspondence includes invitations, thanks for various public services and
				personal favors, and a few letters relating to church activities.</p>
		  </scopecontent>
		</c02>
		<c02>
		  <did><container type="box">2</container><container
			 type="folder">2</container>
			 <unittitle>Materials related to legal profession and service as
				district and Arizona Supreme Court Judge.
				<unitdate type="inclusive"
				normal="1924/1972">1924-1972</unitdate></unittitle>
		  </did>
		  <scopecontent>
			 <p>Contains certificates (including certificates of nomination),
				commissions, notice of appointment, and oaths of office. Other items include
				official election results, miscellaneous campaign material, and a list of
				opinions authored by Justice Udall.</p>
		  </scopecontent>
		</c02>
		<c02>
		  <did><container type="box">2</container><container
			 type="folder">3</container>
			 <unittitle>Speeches and article.
				<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="">1940-1971, and
				  undated</unitdate></unittitle>
		  </did>
		  <scopecontent>
			 <p>Contains typewritten and handwritten texts and notes for speeches
				and talks given by Udall at holiday gatherings, dedications, church services,
				club and association meetings, mostly in the 1960s. Also contains background
				materials of newspaper clippings about famous people and historic events, texts
				of other people's talks, and information or inspirational material taken from
				other sources.</p>
		  </scopecontent>
		</c02>
		<c02>
		  <did><container type="box">2</container><container
			 type="folder">3-4</container>
			 <unittitle>Clippings.
				<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="NaN/1972">circa.
				  1930-1972</unitdate></unittitle>
		  </did>
		  <scopecontent>
			 <p>Clippings documenting Udall's legal career, all but one from the
				period of his tenure on the Arizona Supreme Court. Includes a number of
				clippings from the 1964 impeachment trial of corporation commissioners, A. P.
				(Jack) Buzard and E. T. (Eddie) Williams Jr.</p>
		  </scopecontent>
		</c02>
		<c02>
		  <did><container type="box">2</container><container
			 type="folder">5</container>
			 <unittitle>Arizona National Guard: Safford.
				<unitdate type="inclusive"
				normal="1930/1940">1930-1940</unitdate></unittitle>
		  </did>
		  <scopecontent>
			 <p>Contains a few records of the Safford Guard (e.g. a memorandum of
				agreement), but consists mostly of copies of Bulletins, Memorandums, General
				Orders, and Special Orders sent to the Safford Guard by the State Adjutant
				General. The majority of the material dates to 1940.</p>
		  </scopecontent>
		</c02>
		<c02>
		  <did><container type="box">2</container><container
			 type="folder">6</container>
			 <unittitle>National Guard/U.S. Army: Miscellaneous service records
				and correspondence.
				<unitdate type="inclusive"
				normal="1918/1945">1918-1945</unitdate></unittitle>
		  </did>
		  <scopecontent>
			 <p>Contains miscellaneous papers including an induction order for
				WWI, clothing orders, a physical exam record, requests for a change of status,
				notification of promotion, and orders to proceed. All but the induction order
				are from the period 1935-1945.</p>
		  </scopecontent>
		</c02>
		<c02>
		  <did><container type="box">2</container><container
			 type="folder">7</container>
			 <unittitle>Interstate Stream Commission.
				<unitdate type="inclusive"
				normal="1948/1953">1948-1953</unitdate></unittitle>
		  </did>
		  <scopecontent>
			 <p>Contains Notices of Appointment, accompanying correspondence,
				acceptance of his resignation from the Commission, a letter of appreciation,
				and two clippings.</p>
		  </scopecontent>
		</c02>
		<c02>
		  <did><container type="box">2</container><container
			 type="folder">8</container>
			 <unittitle>Mexico project.
				<unitdate type="inclusive"
				normal="1977/1978">1977-1978</unitdate></unittitle>
		  </did>
		  <scopecontent>
			 <p>Contains background material, two road maps, correspondence, and a
				written proposal relating to his idea that the United States purchase a
				corridor through Mexico from Arizona to the Gulf of California.</p>
		  </scopecontent>
		</c02>
	 </c01>
  </dsc> 
</archdesc></ead>