<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ead PUBLIC "+//ISBN 1-931666-00-8//DTD ead.dtd (Encoded Archival Description (EAD) Version 2002)//EN" "http://www.asu.edu/asuns/dtd/ead.dtd">
<?filetitle Commonwealth Mine Records?>
<ead relatedencoding="MARC21">
<eadheader audience="internal" findaidstatus="edited-full-draft"
 langencoding="iso639-2b">
	<eadid encodinganalog="856$u">PUBLIC "-//University of Arizona Library
		Special Collections//text(US::AzU::Commonwealth Mine, Cochise County, Arizona
	 Records)//en" "UAMS270.xml"</eadid>
  <filedesc> 
	 <titlestmt> 
		<titleproper encodinganalog="245$a">Commonwealth Mine records
		  <date>1895-1938</date></titleproper> 
		<author encodinganalog="245$c">Inventory prepared by Shelley Olson and
		  Roger Myers</author>
	 </titlestmt>
	 <publicationstmt>
	 	<publisher encodinganalog="260$b">University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collection</publisher> 
		<address>
		  <addressline>PO Box 210055</addressline> 
		  <addressline>Tucson, AZ 85721-0055</addressline>
		  <addressline>Phone: 520-621-6423</addressline>
		  <addressline>Fax: 520-621-9733</addressline>
		  <addressline>URL: http://speccoll.library.arizona.edu/</addressline>
		</address>
		<date>&#x00A9; 2001</date> 
		<p>Arizona Board of Regents. All Rights Reserved.</p>
	 </publicationstmt> 
  </filedesc> 
  <profiledesc>
	 <creation encodinganalog="500">Finding aid encoded by Jan Marie Payne 
		<date>October 7, 2001</date></creation> 
	 <langusage>Finding aid is in<language langcode="en"
		encodinganalog="546">English.</language></langusage> 
  </profiledesc> 
</eadheader> 
<frontmatter>
  <titlepage>
	 <titleproper encodinganalog="245$a">Commonwealth Mine records,
		<date>1895-1938</date></titleproper>
	 <num>Collection Number: MS 270</num>
  	<publisher encodinganalog="260$b">University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collection</publisher>
	 <list>
		<defitem>
		  <label>Processed by:</label>
		  <item>Shelley Olson and Roger Myers</item>
		</defitem>
		<defitem>
		  <label>Date completed:</label>
		  <item>
			 <date>1989</date></item>
		</defitem>
		<defitem>
		  <label>Encoded by:</label>
		  <item>Jan Marie Payne</item>
		</defitem>
	 </list>
	 <p>&#x00A9; 2001. Arizona Board of Regents. All rights reserved.</p>
  </titlepage>
</frontmatter>
<archdesc level="collection"> 
  <did id="a1">
	 <head>Collection Summary</head>
	 <unittitle encodinganalog="245" label="Collection Name:">Commonwealth Mine,
		Cochise County, Arizona records, 
		<unitdate type="inclusive"
		 normal="1895/1938">1895-1938</unitdate></unittitle>
	 <unitid label="Collection Number:" encodinganalog="099"
	  repositorycode="AzU" countrycode="us">MS 270</unitid> 
	 <origination label="Creator:"> 
		<corpname encodinganalog="110">Commonwealth Mine</corpname></origination>
	 <abstract label="Abstract:">The bulk of the Commonwealth Mine records document its activities
		from 1910 until 1930. Many of its earlier and later records were lost or
		destroyed between the closing of the mine in the 1940s and the salvaging of the
		records in 1960. Many of the remaining records are fragile and fragmentary;
		several important series, such as Board of Directors minutes, contain only
		scarred and scattered remnants of their original contents.</abstract>
	 <physdesc encodinganalog="300$a" label="Physical Decsription:"><extent
		encodinganalog="300">4.2 linear feet</extent></physdesc>
	 <repository label="Repository:">
	 	<corpname encodinganalog="110">University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collection</corpname>
		<address>
		  <addressline>University of Arizona</addressline>
		  <addressline>PO Box 210055</addressline> 
		  <addressline>Tucson, AZ 85721-0055</addressline>
		  <addressline>Phone: 520-621-6423</addressline>
		  <addressline>Fax: 520-621-9733</addressline>
		  <addressline>URL: http://speccoll.library.arizona.edu/</addressline>
		</address></repository>
  </did> 
  <accessrestrict encodinganalog="506">
	 <head>Restrictions</head>
	 <p>None.</p>
  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict encodinganalog="540">
	 <head>Copyright</head>
	 <p>It is the responsibility of the user to obtain permission to publish
		from the owner of the copyright (the institution, the creator of the record,
		the author or his/her transferees, heirs, legates, or literary executors). The
		user agrees to indemnify and hold harmless the Arizona Board of Regents for the
		University of Arizona, its officers, employees, and agents from and against all
		claims made by any person asserting that he or she is an owner of
		copyright.</p>
  </userestrict>
  <prefercite encodinganalog="524">
	 <head>Credit Line</head>
	 <p>Commonwealth Mine records(MS 270).Special Collections, University of Arizona Libraries.</p>
  </prefercite>
  <bioghist id="a2" encodinganalog="545"> 
	 <head>Historical Note</head>
	 <p>Located in the Pearce Mining District, Cochise County, Arizona, the
		Commonwealth Mine was discovered by John Pearce in 1895. Later that year he
		formed a partnership with John Brockman, R.A.F. Penrose, and D.M. Barringer and
		organized Commonwealth Mining and Milling Company. Stock was issued and sold in
		America and Europe. A 60 stamp mill was built in 1898; it burned down in June
		1900 and was replaced by a 80 stamp mill by January 1901. By 1905, the
		high-grade ore had played out and the shaft collapsed. The company leased the
		tailings to D.T. Swatling (-1910) and A.Y. Smith (-1931). They constructed a
		cyanide leaching plant and worked the tailings for several years.</p> 
	 <p>The mine was purchased by Montana Tonopah Mines Company in 1910. The new
		officers of the Commonwealth were Charles E. Know, A.Y. Smith, and Frank L.
		Bryant. A new mill was constructed in 1913 and operated until 1917 when the ore
		was again too poor to support a profitable operation. A.Y. Smith then leased
		the mine under the name of Commonwealth Development Company which had been
		operating earlier as the Worlds Fair Mine Development Company with properties
		in Patagonia, Arizona.</p>
	 <p>The later records seem to indicate that the mine was controlled by the
		Commonwealth Owners, Fred and Thomas F. Cole (-1939), during the 1930s and
		early 1940s. The Pearce Mining Company leased the operations from them during
		those years.</p>
	 <p>During its forty year existence, the mine produced $8 million worth of
		silver and $2.5 million in gold at a time when silver was priced around 50
		cents an ounce, and gold was $20 an ounce. The state statistics relating to the
		production of the mine were often included with those for the Turquoise Mining
		District.</p>
  </bioghist> 
  <arrangement> 
	 <head>Organization</head> 
	 <p>This collection is organized into two subgroups:</p> 
	 <list> 
		<item>Subgroup I: Commonwealth Mine</item> 
	 </list> 
	 <list> 
		<item>Subgroup II: Supplemental Companies and Activities</item> 
	 </list>
  </arrangement>
  <scopecontent id="a3" encodinganalog="520"> 
	 <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
	 <p>The bulk of the Commonwealth Mine records document its activities from
		1910 until 1930. Many of its earlier and later records were lost or destroyed
		between the closing of the mine in the 1940s and the salvaging of the records
		in 1960. Many of the remaining records are fragile and fragmentary; several
		important series, such as Board of Directors minutes, contain only scarred and
		scattered remnants of their original contents. When the records finally arrived
		for processing, they were totally disorganized and housed in forty-one
		cardboard cartons of sundry sizes. The present arrangement is by record types,
		and some overlap is evident in the manager's and supplies correspondence. </p> 
	 <p>These remaining records best characterize the daily operations of the
		mine and its managers between 1910 and 1930 as they leased the tailings and
		attempted to develop additional shafts. Unfortunately, the period during which
		the richest veins were worked, 1896 to 1905, is not represented in these
		records. Documentation of the last decade of the operation of the mine is also
		poor. The broad themes of this collection outline the managerial and financial
		skills which kept the mine operating. Balancing the shifting market prices of
		silver, gold, and oil, of railroad fright charges, and of smelting costs, the
		operators strove to pay interest charges on bond indebtedness while assuring
		that the leasing activities and milling equipment functioned smoothly. </p>
	 <p>The managers correspondence highlights the business acumen of Charles
		Knox, A.Y. Smith, Frank Bryant and others. The interplay between Knox, as an
		executive of the parent Montana Tonopah organization, and the executives of the
		Commonwealth is rich with decisive memos and directives aimed at continuing
		operations. Knox was in constant contact with Smith and Bryant. Topics of
		ongoing concern were discovery of new veins, richness of ore beds, development
		of the physical plant, payment of bond interest, equipment problems and
		purchases, discussions of monthly reports, market conditions, labor problems
		and the reorganization of the Montana Tonopah Company in 1929. Legal and tax
		matters between Commonwealth and Montana Tonopah are discussed in the
		correspondence with Montana Tonopah's lawyer, Hugh Brown. Other correspondence
		reflects business communications with smelters and refining companies in
		Douglas, Arizona; bankers, lawyers, state and county officials, and nearby
		mining company officials. Later correspondence between T.B. Smith, mine
		operator, and Fred Cole, mine owner, pertains to the operations, leasing, and
		financial condition of the mine.</p>
	 <p>There are also several subject files, titled Automobiles, Cyanide, and
		Insurance which may represent the original filing systems used in the office. A
		sample of correspondence with suppliers from 1906 to 1935 was retained. These
		routine letters delineate shipments, prices, and purveyors of equipment and
		goods to the mine, its leaching operation, and its power plant and mill. Of
		interest are a file of equipment and supplies advertisements and brochures, ca.
		1905-1936, and equipment inventories, ca. 1908 to 1912, of machinery used in
		the mine and mill. </p>
	 <p>The financial files are mainly monthly account statements designating
		debits and credits for the company which outline the cash flow of the mine and
		its operational status. A small sample of the insurance paperwork for employee
		accidents was retained. Included are correspondence and reports between the
		mine and its insurance companies outlining the nature of the accident, and
		prognostications for recovery. There are also copies of various insurance
		policies, some containing itemized lists of buildings and structures covered by
		the policy.</p>
	 <p>The legal files consist largely of contracts, agreements, and deeds
		relating to structural improvements at the mine, railroad right-of ways,
		leasing operations, smelting arrangements, equipment purchases, and mining
		claims.</p>
	 <p>The tax files consist of annual and monthly reporting forms from the
		mine to the federal, state, and county offices. There is correspondence
		relating to audits by the Treasury Department on allowances and depletions
		claimed by the mine and the mine operators defense of those claims. The 1926
		audit provides some information on the relationships and activities of the
		Worlds Fair Mine and the Commonwealth. Correspondence relating to the filing of
		the new tax forms is found in the manager's correspondence files.</p>
	 <p>The directors of the Commonwealth Mine ventured into several other
		businesses in Pearce and the nearby communities. Fragments of records
		pertaining to the B.S.B. Egg Farm, Coronado Cattle Company, Glenn Land and
		Cattle Company, Midwest Sugar Company, and Worlds Fair Mine are present. Most
		of the records for each company occupy one folder and consist of
		correspondence, financial, and legal records. Although the Commonwealth
		provided water for the town of Pearce, there are little evidence of that
		activity in the records.</p>
	 <p>A.Y. Smith was active on the Cochise County Highway Commission in 1919.
		The files contain minutes, reports, and correspondence of the Commission
		relating to a $1 million bond issue to construct and repair various roads in
		Cochise County.</p>
	 <p>Additional files document the activities of the Sulfur Springs branch of
		the American National Red Cross, 1923-1927, and a Pearce social and
		recreational association, the Town and Country Club, 1914 to 1922.</p>
  </scopecontent> 
  <controlaccess id="a12">
	 <head>Access Terms</head>
	 <list>
		<item>
		  <persname encodinganalog="100">Cole, Thomas F., d.
			 1939</persname></item>
	 </list>
	 <list>
		<item>
		  <persname encodinganalog="100">Pearce, John</persname></item>
	 </list>
	 <list>
		<item>
		  <persname encodinganalog="100">Swatling, D. T., d.
			 1910</persname></item>
	 </list>
	 <list>
		<item>
		  <persname encodinganalog="100">Smith, Andrew Y., d.
			 1931</persname></item>
	 </list>
	 <list>
		<item>
		  <persname encodinganalog="100">Knox, Charles E.</persname></item>
	 </list>
	 <list>
		<item>
		  <corpname encodinganalog="110">Cochise County (Ariz.) -- Highway
			 Commission</corpname></item>
	 </list>
	 <list>
		<item>
		  <corpname encodinganalog="110">Commonwealth Mine (Pearce,
			 Ariz.)</corpname></item>
	 </list>
	 <list>
		<item>
		  <corpname encodinganalog="110">Montana Tonopah Mines
			 Co.</corpname></item>
	 </list>
	 <list>
		<item>
		  <corpname encodinganalog="110">Commonwealth Development Co.
			 (Ariz.)</corpname></item>
	 </list>
	 <list>
		<item>
		  <corpname encodinganalog="110">Worlds Fair Mine Development
			 Co.</corpname></item>
	 </list>
	 <list>
		<item>
		  <subject>Cattle trade -- Arizona</subject></item>
	 </list>
	 <list>
		<item>
		  <subject>Mines and mineral resources - Arizona -- Cochise
			 County</subject></item>
	 </list>
	 <list>
		<item>
		  <subject>Roads -- Arizona -- Cochise County</subject></item>
	 </list>
	 <list>
		<item>
		  <geogname>Pearce (Ariz.) -- History</geogname></item>
	 </list>
	 <list>
		<item>
		  <genreform>Correspondence</genreform></item>
	 </list>
	 <list>
		<item>
		  <genreform>Minutes</genreform></item>
	 </list>
	 <list>
		<item>
		  <geogname>Reports</geogname></item>
	 </list>
  </controlaccess> 
  <relatedmaterial encodinganalog="544$1"> 
	 <head>Related Material</head>
	 <p>Other materials on mining in Cochise County, Arizona are located in the
		Papers of the Monmonier family, call number AZ 371. </p>
  </relatedmaterial>
  <dsc type="combined" id="a23"> 
	 <head>Container List</head>
	 <c01 level="subgrp">
		<did>
		  <unittitle>Subgroup I: Commonwealth Mine</unittitle> 
		</did> 
		<c02 level="series">
		  <did>
			 <unittitle>Series I: Board of Director's Minutes, 
				<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="">1912-1913,
				  1927</unitdate></unittitle>
		  </did>
		  <scopecontent>
			 <p>Contains minutes from a few of the board meetings.</p>
		  </scopecontent>
		  <c03 level="file">
			 <did><container type="box">1</container><container
				type="folder">1</container>
				<unittitle>Minutes. 
				  <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="">1912-1913,
					 1927</unitdate></unittitle>
			 </did>
		  </c03>
		</c02>
		<c02 level="series">
		  <did>
			 <unittitle>Series II: Stockholders lists and correspondence, 
				<unitdate type="inclusive"
				 normal="1909/1932">1909-1932</unitdate></unittitle>
		  </did>
		  <scopecontent>
			 <p>Contains names of investors in the mine and correspondence
				relating to meetings, payments of obligations, and dividends.</p>
		  </scopecontent>
		  <c03 level="file">
			 <did><container type="box">1</container><container
				type="folder">2</container>
				<unittitle>Lists. 
				  <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="NaN">No
					 Date</unitdate></unittitle>
			 </did>
		  </c03>
		  <c03 level="file">
			 <did><container type="box">1</container><container
				type="folder">3-6</container>
				<unittitle>Correspondence. 
				  <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="NaN">No
					 Date</unitdate></unittitle>
			 </did>
		  </c03>
		</c02>
		<c02 level="series">
		  <did>
			 <unittitle>Series III: Correspondence, 
				<unitdate type="inclusive"
				 normal="1907/1934">1907-1934</unitdate></unittitle>
		  </did>
		  <scopecontent>
			 <p>Contains incoming and outgoing letters documenting daily
				activities of the mine, its physical plant, and its administration and
				management.</p>
		  </scopecontent>
		  <c03 level="subseries">
			 <did>
				<unittitle>Manager's Correspondence</unittitle>
			 </did>
			 <c04 level="file">
				<did><container type="box">1</container><container
				  type="folder">7</container>
				  <unittitle>Unidentified. 
					 <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="NaN">No
						Date</unitdate></unittitle>
				</did>
			 </c04>
			 <c04 level="file">
				<did><container type="box">1</container><container
				  type="folder">8</container>
				  <unittitle>A. 
					 <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="NaN">No
						Date</unitdate></unittitle>
				</did>
			 </c04>
			 <c04 level="file">
				<did><container type="box">1</container><container
				  type="folder">9</container>
				  <unittitle>Anglo and London Paris National Bank (Calif.). 
					 <unitdate type="inclusive"
					 normal="1914/1920">1914-1920</unitdate></unittitle>
				</did>
			 </c04>
			 <c04 level="file">
				<did><container type="box">1</container><container
				  type="folder">10</container>
				  <unittitle>Arizona Eastern Railroad. 
					 <unitdate type="inclusive"
					 normal="1919/1921">1919-1921</unitdate></unittitle>
				</did>
			 </c04>
			 <c04 level="file">
				<did><container type="box">1</container><container
				  type="folder">11</container>
				  <unittitle>Arizona state agencies. 
					 <unitdate type="inclusive"
					 normal="1910/1931">1910-1931</unitdate></unittitle>
				</did>
			 </c04>
			 <c04 level="file">
				<did><container type="box">1</container><container
				  type="folder">12</container>
				  <unittitle>Ashurst, Henry F. 
					 <unitdate type="inclusive"
					 normal="1922">1922</unitdate></unittitle>
				</did>
			 </c04>
			 <c04 level="file">
				<did><container type="box">1</container><container
				  type="folder">13</container>
				  <unittitle>B. 
					 <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="NaN">No
						Date</unitdate></unittitle>
				</did>
			 </c04>
			 <c04 level="file">
				<did><container type="box">1</container><container
				  type="folder">14</container>
				  <unittitle>C. 
					 <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="NaN">No
						Date</unitdate></unittitle>
				</did>
			 </c04>
			 <c04 level="file">
				<did><container type="box">1</container><container
				  type="folder">15</container>
				  <unittitle>Calumet and Arizona Mining Co. 
					 <unitdate type="inclusive"
					 normal="1909/1930">1909-1930</unitdate></unittitle>
				</did>
			 </c04>
			 <c04 level="file">
				<did><container type="box">1</container><container
				  type="folder">16</container>
				  <unittitle>Chautauqua. 
					 <unitdate type="inclusive"
					 normal="1920/1924">1920-1924</unitdate></unittitle>
				</did>
			 </c04>
			 <c04 level="file">
				<did><container type="box">1</container><container
				  type="folder">17</container>
				  <unittitle>Cole, Fred L. and Thomas. 
					 <unitdate type="inclusive"
					 normal="1922/1936">1922-1936</unitdate></unittitle>
				</did>
			 </c04>
			 <c04 level="file">
				<did><container type="box">2</container><container
				  type="folder">1</container>
				  <unittitle>Commonwealth Development Co. 
					 <unitdate type="inclusive"
					 normal="1918/1934">1918-1934</unitdate></unittitle>
				</did>
			 </c04>
			 <c04 level="file">
				<did><container type="box">2</container><container
				  type="folder">2-4</container>
				  <unittitle>Commonwealth Mining and Milling Co. 
					 <unitdate type="inclusive"
					 normal="1910/1931">1910-1931</unitdate></unittitle>
				</did>
			 </c04>
			 <c04 level="file">
				<did><container type="box">2</container><container
				  type="folder">5</container>
				  <unittitle>D, E, F. 
					 <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="NaN">No
						Date</unitdate></unittitle>
				</did>
			 </c04>
			 <c04 level="file">
				<did><container type="box">2</container><container
				  type="folder">6</container>
				  <unittitle>Employment inquiries. 
					 <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="NaN">No
						Date</unitdate></unittitle>
				</did>
			 </c04>
			 <c04 level="file">
				<did><container type="box">2</container><container
				  type="folder">7</container>
				  <unittitle>G, H. 
					 <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="NaN">No
						Date</unitdate></unittitle>
				</did>
			 </c04>
			 <c04 level="file">
				<did><container type="box">2</container><container
				  type="folder">8</container>
				  <unittitle>I, J, K. 
					 <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="NaN">No
						Date</unitdate></unittitle>
				</did>
			 </c04>
			 <c04 level="file">
				<did><container type="box">2</container><container
				  type="folder">9</container>
				  <unittitle>Insurance. 
					 <unitdate type="inclusive"
					 normal="1910/1932">1910-1932</unitdate></unittitle>
				</did>
			 </c04>
			 <c04 level="file">
				<did><container type="box">2</container><container
				  type="folder">10-12</container>
				  <unittitle>Knox, Charles E. 
					 <unitdate type="inclusive"
					 normal="1910/1925">1910-1925</unitdate></unittitle>
				</did>
			 </c04>
			 <c04 level="file">
				<did><container type="box">2</container><container
				  type="folder">13</container>
				  <unittitle>L, M. 
					 <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="NaN">No
						Date</unitdate></unittitle>
				</did>
			 </c04>
			 <c04 level="file">
				<did><container type="box">2</container><container
				  type="folder">14</container>
				  <unittitle>Montana Tonopah Mines Co. 
					 <unitdate type="inclusive"
					 normal="1912/1919">1912-1919</unitdate></unittitle>
				</did>
			 </c04>
			 <c04 level="file">
				<did><container type="box">3</container><container
				  type="folder">1</container>
				  <unittitle>Montana Tonopah Mines Co. 
					 <unitdate type="inclusive"
					 normal="1920/1929">1920-1929</unitdate></unittitle>
				</did>
			 </c04>
			 <c04 level="file">
				<did><container type="box">3</container><container
				  type="folder">2</container>
				  <unittitle>Montana Tonopah Mines Co. Lawyer. 
					 <unitdate type="inclusive"
					 normal="1920/1929">1920-1929</unitdate></unittitle>
				</did>
			 </c04>
			 <c04 level="file">
				<did><container type="box">3</container><container
				  type="folder">3</container>
				  <unittitle>N, O. 
					 <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="NaN">No
						Date</unitdate></unittitle>
				</did>
			 </c04>
			 <c04 level="file">
				<did><container type="box">3</container><container
				  type="folder">4</container>
				  <unittitle>P. 
					 <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="NaN">No
						Date</unitdate></unittitle>
				</did>
			 </c04>
			 <c04 level="file">
				<did><container type="box">3</container><container
				  type="folder">5</container>
				  <unittitle>R. 
					 <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="NaN">No
						Date</unitdate></unittitle>
				</did>
			 </c04>
			 <c04 level="file">
				<did><container type="box">3</container><container
				  type="folder">6</container>
				  <unittitle>S. 
					 <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="NaN">No
						Date</unitdate></unittitle>
				</did>
			 </c04>
			 <c04 level="file">
				<did><container type="box">3</container><container
				  type="folder">7</container>
				  <unittitle>T, U, V. 
					 <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="NaN">No
						Date</unitdate></unittitle>
				</did>
			 </c04>
			 <c04 level="file">
				<did><container type="box">3</container><container
				  type="folder">8</container>
				  <unittitle>W, Y, Z. 
					 <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="NaN">No
						Date</unitdate></unittitle>
				</did>
			 </c04>
		  </c03>
		  <c03 level="subseries">
			 <did>
				<unittitle>Supplies Correspondence</unittitle>
			 </did>
			 <c04 level="file">
				<did><container type="box">3</container><container
				  type="folder">9</container>
				  <unittitle>Supplies/equipment advertisements. 
					 <unitdate type="inclusive"
					 normal="1905/1936">1905-1936</unitdate></unittitle>
				</did>
			 </c04>
			 <c04 level="file">
				<did><container type="box">3</container><container
				  type="folder">10</container>
				  <unittitle>Equipment/inventories/drawings. 
					 <unitdate type="inclusive"
					 normal="1908/1918">1908-1918</unitdate></unittitle>
				</did>
			 </c04>
			 <c04 level="file">
				<did><container type="box">3</container><container
				  type="folder">11</container>
				  <unittitle>Automobiles. 
					 <unitdate type="inclusive"
					 normal="1906/1910">1906-1910</unitdate></unittitle>
				</did>
			 </c04>
			 <c04 level="file">
				<did><container type="box">3</container><container
				  type="folder">12</container>
				  <unittitle>Cyanide. 
					 <unitdate type="inclusive"
					 normal="1908/1917">1908-1917</unitdate></unittitle>
				</did>
			 </c04>
			 <c04 level="file">
				<did><container type="box">3</container><container
				  type="folder">13-29</container>
				  <unittitle>Supplies. 
					 <unitdate type="inclusive"
					 normal="1906/1935">1906-1935</unitdate></unittitle>
				</did>
			 </c04>
		  </c03>
		</c02>
		<c02 level="series">
		  <did>
			 <unittitle>Series IV: Financial files, 
				<unitdate type="inclusive"
				normal="1911/1935">1911-1935</unitdate></unittitle>
		  </did>
		  <scopecontent>
			 <p>Bulk are monthly trial balances and operating statements for the
				mine, some are annual statements or summary statements of receipts and
				disbursements. There are many gaps in all types of documents, and there are no
				summary ledgers available for operations.</p>
		  </scopecontent>
		  <c03 level="file">
			 <did><container type="box">4</container><container
				type="folder">1-4</container>
				<unittitle>Statements. 
				  <unitdate type="inclusive"
				  normal="1911/1935">1911-35</unitdate></unittitle>
			 </did>
		  </c03>
		</c02>
		<c02 level="series">
		  <did>
			 <unittitle>Series V: Legal files, 
				<unitdate type="inclusive"
				normal="1895/1938">1895-1938</unitdate></unittitle>
		  </did>
		  <scopecontent>
			 <p>Contains insurance files relating to employee accidents and
				policies on the mine and its physical plant with listings of existing buildings
				and their valuations; legal documents including contracts, agreements, and
				deeds; and tax statements required by federal and state agencies.</p>
		  </scopecontent>
		  <c03 level="file">
			 <did><container type="box">4</container><container
				type="folder">5</container>
				<unittitle>Employee accidents. 
				  <unitdate type="inclusive"
				  normal="1913/1935">1913-1935</unitdate></unittitle>
			 </did>
		  </c03>
		  <c03 level="file">
			 <did><container type="box">4</container><container
				type="folder">6</container>
				<unittitle>Insurance policies. 
				  <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="NaN/1930">1913,
					 1925-1930</unitdate></unittitle>
			 </did>
		  </c03>
		  <c03 level="file">
			 <did><container type="box">4</container><container
				type="folder">7-10</container>
				<unittitle>Legal documents. 
				  <unitdate type="inclusive"
				  normal="1895/1938">1895-1938</unitdate></unittitle>
			 </did>
		  </c03>
		  <c03 level="file">
			 <did><container type="box">4</container><container
				type="folder">11-12</container>
				<unittitle>Tax statements. 
				  <unitdate type="inclusive"
				  normal="1909/1937">1909-1937</unitdate></unittitle>
			 </did>
		  </c03>
		</c02>
		<c02 level="series">
		  <did>
			 <unittitle>Series VI: Operations reports, 
				<unitdate type="inclusive"
				normal="1906/1937">1906-1937</unitdate></unittitle>
		  </did>
		  <scopecontent>
			 <p>Contains selected samples of assay reports, bullion reports, churn
				drill reports, cyanide reports, mine inspector's report, mill report, smelter
				reports, payroll ledgers, and time books; and larger samples of weekly mine
				operating reports, and ore settlements.</p>
		  </scopecontent>
		  <c03 level="file">
			 <did><container type="box">4</container><container
				type="folder">13-14</container>
				<unittitle>Reports, sampled. 
				  <unitdate type="inclusive"
					normal="1906/1935">1906-1935</unitdate></unittitle>
			 </did>
		  </c03>
		  <c03 level="file">
			 <did><container type="box">4</container><container
				type="folder">15</container>
				<unittitle>Mine operating reports, weekly. 
				  <unitdate type="inclusive"
					normal="1912/1916">1912-1916</unitdate></unittitle>
			 </did>
		  </c03>
		  <c03 level="file">
			 <did><container type="box">4</container><container
				type="folder">16</container>
				<unittitle>Ore settlements. 
				  <unitdate type="inclusive"
					normal="1914/1931">1914-1931</unitdate></unittitle>
			 </did>
		  </c03>
		  <c03 level="file">
			 <did><container type="box">4</container><container
				type="folder">17</container>
				<unittitle>Ore settlements, Black Diamond. 
				  <unitdate type="inclusive"
					normal="1929/1930">1929-1930</unitdate></unittitle>
			 </did>
		  </c03>
		  <c03 level="file">
			 <did><container type="box">4</container><container
				type="folder">18</container>
				<unittitle>Payroll ledgers. 
				  <unitdate type="inclusive"
					normal="1915/1916">1915-1916</unitdate></unittitle>
			 </did>
		  </c03>
		  <c03 level="file">
			 <did><container type="box">4</container><container
				type="folder">19</container>
				<unittitle>Smelting department. 
				  <unitdate type="inclusive"
					normal="1912/1921">1912-1921</unitdate></unittitle>
			 </did>
		  </c03>
		  <c03 level="file">
			 <did><container type="box">4</container><container
				type="folder">20</container>
				<unittitle>Time books. 
				  <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1916">1914,
					 1916</unitdate></unittitle>
			 </did>
		  </c03>
		</c02>
		<c02 level="series">
		  <did>
			 <unittitle>Series VII: Vouchers, 
				<unitdate type="inclusive"
				 normal="1905/1926">1905-1926</unitdate></unittitle>
		  </did>
		  <scopecontent>
			 <p>Contains selected samples of vouchers for purchases over $100, the
				bulk of which pertain to storehouse acquisitions, fuels, payroll, equipment and
				construction.</p>
		  </scopecontent>
		  <c03 level="file">
			 <did><container type="box">5</container><container
				type="folder">1</container>
				<unittitle>Commonwealth Development Co., 1918-25
				  <unitdate type="inclusive"
					normal="1918/1925">1918-1925</unitdate></unittitle>
			 </did>
		  </c03>
		  <c03 level="file">
			 <did><container type="box">5</container><container
				type="folder">2-5</container>
				<unittitle>Commonwealth Mining and Milling Co. 
				  <unitdate type="inclusive"
					normal="1905/1926">1905-1926</unitdate></unittitle>
			 </did>
		  </c03>
		  <c03 level="file">
			 <did><container type="box">5</container><container
				type="folder">6</container>
				<unittitle>Swatling and Smith. 
				  <unitdate type="inclusive"
					normal="1905/1908">1905-1908</unitdate></unittitle>
			 </did>
		  </c03>
		</c02>
	 </c01> 
	 <c01 level="subgrp"> 
		<did>
		  <unittitle>Subgroup II: Supplemental Companies and
			 Activities</unittitle> 
		</did> 
		<scopecontent>
		  <p>Contains board of directors minutes and meetings, correspondence,
			 legal, and financial documents relating to the businesses, several of which
			 were operated by the directors of the Commonwealth Mine.</p>
		</scopecontent>
		<c02 level="series">
		  <did>
			 <unittitle>Series I: American National Red Cross. Sulphur Springs
				Valley Branch, 
				<unitdate type="inclusive"
				 normal="1923/1927">1923-1927</unitdate></unittitle>
		  </did>
		  <c03 level="file">
			 <did><container type="box">6</container><container
				type="folder">1</container>
				<unittitle>American National Red Cross. Sulphur Springs Valley
				  Branch. 
				  <unitdate type="inclusive"
					normal="1923/1927">1923-1927</unitdate></unittitle>
			 </did>
		  </c03>
		</c02>
		<c02 level="series">
		  <did>
			 <unittitle>Series II: B.S.B. Egg Farm, 
				<unitdate type="inclusive"
				 normal="1924/1927">1924-1927</unitdate></unittitle>
		  </did>
		  <c03 level="file">
			 <did><container type="box">6</container><container
				type="folder">2</container>
				<unittitle>B.S.B. Egg Farm. 
				  <unitdate type="inclusive"
					normal="1924/1927">1924-1927</unitdate></unittitle>
			 </did>
		  </c03>
		</c02>
		<c02 level="series">
		  <did>
			 <unittitle>Series III: Cochise County Highway Commission, 
				<unitdate type="inclusive"
				 normal="1919">1919</unitdate></unittitle>
		  </did>
		  <c03 level="file">
			 <did><container type="box">6</container><container
				type="folder">3</container>
				<unittitle>Cochise Highway Commission. 
				  <unitdate type="inclusive"
					normal="1919">1919</unitdate></unittitle>
			 </did>
		  </c03>
		</c02>
		<c02 level="series">
		  <did>
			 <unittitle>Series IV: Coronado Cattle Company, 
				<unitdate type="inclusive"
				 normal="1909/1922">1909-1922</unitdate></unittitle>
		  </did>
		  <c03 level="file">
			 <did><container type="box">6</container><container
				type="folder">4</container>
				<unittitle>Coronado Cattle Company. 
				  <unitdate type="inclusive"
					normal="1909/1922">1909-1922</unitdate></unittitle>
			 </did>
		  </c03>
		</c02>
		<c02 level="series">
		  <did>
			 <unittitle>Series V: Glenn Land and Cattle Company, 
				<unitdate type="inclusive"
				 normal="1914/1930">1914-1930</unitdate></unittitle>
		  </did>
		  <c03 level="file">
			 <did><container type="box">6</container><container
				type="folder">5-7</container>
				<unittitle>Glenn Land and Cattle Company. 
				  <unitdate type="inclusive"
					normal="1914/1930">1914-1930</unitdate></unittitle>
			 </did>
		  </c03>
		</c02>
		<c02 level="series">
		  <did>
			 <unittitle>Series VI: Midwest Sugar Company, 
				<unitdate type="inclusive"
				 normal="1917/1924">1917-1924</unitdate></unittitle>
		  </did>
		  <c03 level="file">
			 <did><container type="box">6</container><container
				type="folder">8</container>
				<unittitle>Midwest Sugar Company. 
				  <unitdate type="inclusive"
					normal="1917/1924">1917-1924</unitdate></unittitle>
			 </did>
		  </c03>
		</c02>
		<c02 level="series">
		  <did>
			 <unittitle>Series VII: Town and Country Club (Pearce, Ariz.), 
				<unitdate type="inclusive"
				 normal="1914/1922">1914-1922</unitdate></unittitle>
		  </did>
		  <c03 level="file">
			 <did><container type="box">6</container><container
				type="folder">9</container>
				<unittitle>Town and Country Club (Pearce, Ariz.). 
				  <unitdate type="inclusive"
					normal="1914/1922">1914-1922</unitdate></unittitle>
			 </did>
		  </c03>
		</c02>
		<c02 level="series">
		  <did>
			 <unittitle>Series VIII: Worlds Fair Mine Development Company, 
				<unitdate type="inclusive"
				 normal="1914/1920">1914-1920</unitdate></unittitle>
		  </did>
		  <c03 level="file">
			 <did><container type="box">6</container><container
				type="folder">10</container>
				<unittitle>Worlds Fair Mine Development Company. 
				  <unitdate type="inclusive"
					normal="1914/1920">1914-1920</unitdate></unittitle>
			 </did>
		  </c03>
		</c02>
	 </c01>
  </dsc> 
</archdesc></ead>