<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ead PUBLIC "+//ISBN 1-931666-00-8//DTD ead.dtd (Encoded Archival Description (EAD) Version 2002)//EN" "http://www.asu.edu/asuns/dtd/ead.dtd"> 
<ead relatedencoding="MARC21">
<eadheader audience="internal" findaidstatus="edited-full-draft"
 langencoding="iso639-2b">
  <eadid encodinganalog="856$u">PUBLIC "-//University of Arizona Library
	 Special Collections//text(US::AzU::New Mexican mining documents
	 collection)//en" "UAMS237.xml"</eadid>
  <filedesc> 
	 <titlestmt> 
		<titleproper encodinganalog="245$a"> New Mexican mining documents
		  collection, 
		  <date>1881-1904</date></titleproper>
		<author encodinganalog="245$c">Inventory updated by Patricia
		  Doherty</author>
	 </titlestmt>
	 <publicationstmt>
	 	<publisher encodinganalog="260$b">University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections</publisher> 
		<address>
		  <addressline>PO Box 210055</addressline> 
		  <addressline>Tucson, AZ 85721-0055</addressline>
		  <addressline>Phone: 520-621-6423</addressline>
		  <addressline>Fax: 520-621-9733</addressline>
		  <addressline>URL: http://speccoll.library.arizona.edu/</addressline>
		</address>
		<date>&#x00A9; 2001</date> 
		<p>Arizona Board of Regents. All Rights Reserved.</p>
	 </publicationstmt> 
  </filedesc> 
  <profiledesc>
	 <creation encodinganalog="500">Inventory encoded by Jennie Stapp 
		<date>June 24, 2002</date></creation> 
	 <langusage>Inventory is in<language langcode="en"
		encodinganalog="546">English.</language></langusage> 
  </profiledesc> 
</eadheader> 
<frontmatter>
  <titlepage>
	 <titleproper encodinganalog="245$a">New Mexican mining documents
		collection, 
		<date>1881-1904</date></titleproper>
	 <num>Collection Number: MS 237</num>
  	<publisher encodinganalog="260$b">University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collectionss</publisher>
	 <list>
		<defitem>
		  <label>Processed by:</label>
		  <item>Patricia Doherty</item>
		</defitem>
		<defitem>
		  <label>Date completed:</label>
		  <item>
			 <date>September 1995</date></item>
		</defitem>
		<defitem>
		  <label>Encoded by:</label>
		  <item>Jennie Stapp</item>
		</defitem>
	 </list>
	 <p>&#x00A9; 2001. Arizona Board of Regents. All rights reserved.</p>
  </titlepage>
</frontmatter>
<archdesc level="collection">
  <did id="a1">
	 <head>Collection Summary</head>
	 <unittitle encodinganalog="245" label="Collection Name:">New Mexican mining
		documents collection, 
		<unitdate type="inclusive"
		 normal="1881/1904">1881-1904</unitdate></unittitle>
	 <unitid label="Collection Number:" encodinganalog="099"
	  repositorycode="AzU" countrycode="us">MS 237</unitid> 
	 <origination label="Creator:"> 
		<persname encodinganalog="100">Bartlett, Edward
		  L</persname></origination>
	 <abstract label="Abstract:">Correspondence, legal and financial documents, from 1881-1904,
		that include location notices, mining and quit-claim deeds, proofs of labor,
		contracts, powers of attorney, leases, receipts, bills, promissory notes,
		injunctions, subpoenas, and bills of complaint.</abstract>
	 <physdesc encodinganalog="300$a" label="Physical Description:"><extent
		encodinganalog="300">.5 linear feet</extent></physdesc>
	 <repository label="Repository:">
	 	<corpname encodinganalog="110">University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections</corpname>
		<address>
		  <addressline>University of Arizona</addressline>
		  <addressline>PO Box 210055</addressline> 
		  <addressline>Tucson, AZ 85721-0055</addressline>
		  <addressline>Phone: 520-621-6423</addressline>
		  <addressline>Fax: 520-621-9733</addressline>
		  <addressline>URL: http://speccoll.library.arizona.edu/</addressline>
		</address></repository>
  </did> 
  <accessrestrict encodinganalog="506">
	 <head>Restrictions</head>
	 <p>None.</p>
  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict encodinganalog="540">
	 <head>Copyright</head>
	 <p>It is the responsibility of the user to obtain permission to publish
		from the owner of the copyright (the institution, the creator of the record,
		the author or his/her transferees, heirs, legates, or literary executors). The
		user agrees to indemnify and hold harmless the Arizona Board of Regents for the
		University of Arizona, its officers, employees, and agents from and against all
		claims made by any person asserting that he or she is an owner of
		copyright.</p>
  </userestrict>
  <prefercite encodinganalog="524">
	 <head>Credit Line</head>
	 <p>New Mexican mining documents collection(MS 237). Special Collections, University of Arizona Libraries.</p>
  </prefercite>
  <bioghist id="a2" encodinganalog="545"> 
	 <head>Biographical Note</head>
	 <p>Edward Leland Bartlett was born in Maine in 1847. He attended Bowdin
		College, studied law at the University of Michigan and in Kansas where he was
		admitted to the Bar in 1871. He practiced law in Kansas City until 1880. He
		then moved to Santa Fe where he was active with the regular troops and militia.
		Bartlett was appointed Solicitor General of New Mexico in 1889. He was active
		in establishing the New Mexico Bar Association and was a member of the Knights
		Templars, Masons, and Lodge of Odd Fellows.</p>
	 <p> According to the seal on one of the documents, Edward L. Bartlett was
		U.S. Court Commissioner for the Territory of New Mexico, in Santa Fe. Other
		documents indicate that, as a lawyer, he held power of attorney for the various
		owners of these mines. He died in Santa Fe on October 19, 1904.</p> 
  </bioghist> 
  <scopecontent id="a3" encodinganalog="520"> 
	 <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
	 <p>Correspondence, legal and financial documents, from 1881-1904, that
		include location notices, mining and quit-claim deeds, proofs of labor,
		contracts, powers of attorney, leases, receipts, bills, promissory notes,
		injunctions, subpoenas, and bills of complaint. Two sketch maps are present.
		One shows the Lone Star and Gold King Mines; the other depicts those of the
		Good Hope Mill and Mining Co.: Clare D., Croesus, Grand Mogul, Little Casino,
		and Mary E. Steel.</p> 
  </scopecontent> 
  <controlaccess id="a12">
	 <head>Access Terms</head>
	 <list>
		<item>
		  <persname encodinganalog="100">Bartlett, Edward L.</persname></item>
		<item>
		  <corpname encodinganalog="110">New Mexico Mining Co. -- Records and
			 correspondence</corpname></item>
		<item>
		  <corpname encodinganalog="110">Pecos River Mining Co. -- Records and
			 correspondence</corpname></item>
		<item>
		  <corpname encodinganalog="110">Good Hope Mill and Mining Co. -- Records
			 and correspondence</corpname></item>
		<item>
		  <subject>Mining corporations -- New Mexico -- History -- 19th
			 century</subject></item>
		<item>
		  <geogname> Ruby King Mine (Cerrillos, N.M.) </geogname></item>
		<item>
		  <geogname>Galena Chief Mine (Cerillos, N.M.) </geogname></item>
		<item>
		  <geogname> Lone Star Mine (Cerillos, N.M.) </geogname></item>
		<item>
		  <geogname>San Pedro Coal Mines (Dolores, N.M.) </geogname></item>
		<item>
		  <geogname>Clare D. Mine (Tres Piedras, N.M.) </geogname></item>
		<item>
		  <geogname>Croesus Mine (Tres Piedras, N.M.)</geogname></item>
		<item>
		  <geogname>Grand Mogul Mine (Tres Piedras, N.M.) </geogname></item>
		<item>
		  <geogname>Little Casino Mine (Tres Piedras, N.M.) </geogname></item>
		<item>
		  <geogname>Mary E. Steel Mine (Tres Piedras, N.M.)</geogname></item>
		<item>
		  <geogname>Gold King Mine (Cerrillos, N.M.) </geogname></item>
		<item>
		  <geogname> Santa Fe County (N.M.) -- History -- Sources
			 </geogname></item>
		<item>
		  <geogname>Cerrillos (N.M.) -- History -- Sources</geogname></item>
		<item>
		  <geogname>Dolores (N.M.) -- History -- Sources</geogname></item>
		<item>
		  <genreform>Correspondence</genreform></item>
		<item>
		  <genreform>Deeds</genreform></item>
		<item>
		  <genreform>Leases</genreform></item>
	 </list>
  </controlaccess> 
  <dsc type="combined" id="a23"> 
	 <head>Container List</head>
	 <c01 level="file">
		<did><container type="box">1</container><container
		  type="folder">1</container>
		  <unittitle>Galena Chief Mine, Cerrillos, New Mexico. 
			 <unitdate type="inclusive"
			  normal="1881/1900">1881-1900</unitdate></unittitle> 
		</did> 
		<scopecontent>
		  <p>Correspondence between Edward L. Bartlett and various individuals,
			 including Cyrus Wells, William Minters, M. O'Neil, O. H. Warner, W. H. Morris,
			 R. M. Cooke, Frank W. Clancy, and L. Bradford Prince. Correspondence relates to
			 the sale and development, operations and financial matters of the mine. </p>
		  <p>Legal documents include location notices, mining and quit-claim
			 deeds, proofs of labor, contracts, power of attorney and leases, and a decision
			 by a sheriff in the case of David K. Osbourn vs. John Sherman, Jr. Financial
			 documents include receipts for work assessments. </p>
		</scopecontent>
	 </c01>
	 <c01 level="file">
		<did><container type="box">1</container><container
		  type="folder">2</container>
		  <unittitle>Good Hope Mill and Mine, Hopewell and Tres Piedras, New
			 Mexico. 
			 <unitdate type="inclusive"
			 normal="1884/1901">1884-1901</unitdate></unittitle> 
		</did> 
		<scopecontent>
		  <p>Mines include the Clara D., Croesus, Grand Mogul, Little Casino, and
			 the Mary E. Steel. Correspondence is between Edward L. Bartlett and various
			 individuals, including D. A. Chambers, Walter E. Hope, Mornay Williams, E. C.
			 Sterling, Lord Sterling, J. L. Sterling, W. B. Twitchell, and Francisco C.
			 Chavez. Correspondence relates to patents, conditions of the mines, possible
			 sales of mines and taxes. </p>
		  <p>Legal documents include a form letter announcing patents on mines
			 filed in the U. S. Land Office and financial documents include a receipt. Also
			 included is a sketch map and claims. </p>
		</scopecontent>
	 </c01>
	 <c01 level="file">
		<did><container type="box">1</container><container
		  type="folder">3</container>
		  <unittitle>Lone Star and Gold King Mines, Cerrillos, New Mexico. 
			 <unitdate type="inclusive"
			 normal="1885/1892">1885-1892</unitdate></unittitle> 
		</did> 
		<scopecontent>
		  <p>Correspondence is between Edward L. Bartlett and Samuel A. Losch, J.
			 P. O'Brien and Edwin B. Seward regarding the value and condition of the mine,
			 work assessment, power of attorney, and financial concerns. Legal documents
			 include a Notice of Location, leases, a meeting notice and proofs of labor.
			 Financial documents include promissory notes, receipts and contracts. </p>
		</scopecontent>
	 </c01>
	 <c01 level="file" id="ser1">
		<did><container type="box">1</container><container
		  type="folder">4</container>
		  <unittitle>Ruby King Mine, Pecos River Mining Co., Cerrillos, New
			 Mexico. 
			 <unitdate type="inclusive"
			  normal="1881/1885">1881-1885</unitdate></unittitle> 
		</did> 
		<scopecontent>
		  <p>Correspondence is between Edward L. Bartlett and various
			 individuals, including Eugene H. Cowles, S. R. Buchanan, Chambers McKibbin and
			 John A. Mills. Correspondence is regarding sale of stock and mining interests.
			 Legal documents include location notices, mining and quit-claim deeds, an order
			 for injunction, a subpoena and extracts of court proceedings and bills of
			 complaint. Financial documents include promissory notes, receipts, statements
			 of stock and ownership of the Ruby King Mine.</p>
		</scopecontent>
	 </c01> 
	 <c01 level="file">
		<did><container type="box">1</container><container
		  type="folder">5</container>
		  <unittitle>San Pedro Coal Mines, Dolores, New Mexico. 
			 <unitdate type="inclusive"
			  normal="1888/1897">1888-1897</unitdate></unittitle> 
		</did> 
		<scopecontent>
		  <p>Includes miscellaneous mining documents and a Shoshone mining claim.
			 Correspondence is between Edward L. Bartlett and J. W. Ricketts, W. J. Jackson
			 and Alfred Wolf. Correspondence is regarding legal cases, and potential law
			 suits. Legal documents relate to the case of Gildersleeve vs. New Mexico Mining
			 Co. </p>
		</scopecontent>
	 </c01>
	 <c01 level="file">
		<did><container type="box">2</container><container
		  type="folder">1</container>
		  <unittitle>Francisco Montes Vigil Land Grant. 
			 <unitdate type="inclusive"
			  normal="1883/1904">1883-1904</unitdate></unittitle>
		</did>
		<scopecontent>
		  <p>Correspondence between Edward L. Bartlett and various individuals,
			 including Urbano Chacon and S. I. Hallett, relating to the sale of portions of
			 the grant which is located on the western slope of the Las Truchas Mountains,
			 Rio Arriba County, New Mexico. </p>
		  <p>Legal documents include assignment of title, land claims court
			 documents, release of mortgage, sale contracts, a partial genealogy of
			 Francisco Montes Vigil, transcript of field notes describing the grant, notes
			 regarding land claimants, and other conveyances, deeds, agreements, and
			 invoices. Financial records include receipts and a check book for 1904.</p>
		</scopecontent>
	 </c01>
	 <c01 level="file">
		<did><container type="box">2</container><container
		  type="folder">2</container>
		  <unittitle>Petaca Land Grant. 
			 <unitdate type="inclusive"
			  normal="1883/1896">1883-1896</unitdate></unittitle>
		</did>
		<scopecontent>
		  <p>Correspondence between Edward L. Bartlett and George Howard
			 concerning the claim in Taos and Rio Arriba Counties, New Mexico. Also included
			 is a partial genealogy for Jose Julian Martinez and Antonio Martinez. </p>
		  <p>Legal documents include an abstract of title, private land claims
			 court documents, affidavits as to interests of heirs by Tomas Rivera and Jose
			 Maria Vigil, state of case in claim of Farwell v. United states, translation of
			 petition to the court of Jose Julian Martinez, handwritten transcripts of
			 testimony of Jose Julian Martinez, notice of land claim conflict, case notes,
			 and court decree. </p>
		</scopecontent>
	 </c01>
	 <c01 level="file">
		<did><container type="box">2</container><container
		  type="folder">3</container>
		  <unittitle>Railroad Right of Way, Santa Fe, New Mexico. 
			 <unitdate type="inclusive"
			  normal="1880/1898">1880-1898</unitdate></unittitle>
		</did>
		<scopecontent>
		  <p>Correspondence between Edward L. Bartlett and representatives of
			 Denver and Rio Grande Railroad Company, and others. Legal documents including
			 warranty deeds between E. C. Manning and T. B. Myers; memorandum of conveyance,
			 power of attorney, text of land claims court final decree in the claim of Juan
			 Chaves, handwritten right of way agreement between the Indians of San Juan
			 Pueblo in Rio Arriba County, a Santa Fe citizens petition protesting the right
			 of way, and notes on the text of the articles of incorporation for the Denver
			 and Rio Grande Railroad Co. Also included are maps depicting the right of way
			 location.</p>
		</scopecontent>
	 </c01>
  </dsc>
</archdesc></ead>