<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!DOCTYPE ead PUBLIC "+//ISBN 1-931666-00-8//DTD ead.dtd (Encoded Archival Description(EAD)Version 2002)//EN" "http://www.asu.edu/asuns/dtd/ead.dtd">
<ead relatedencoding="MARC21"> 
<eadheader langencoding="iso639-2b" findaidstatus="edited-full-draft"
 audience="internal" id="a0"> 
	<eadid encodinganalog="852"> PUBLIC "-//University of Arizona Library Special
		Collections//text(US::AzU::Southwest Folklore Center Pre-1980 Sound Disc Collection)//en""SWF007.xml"</eadid> 
  <filedesc> 
	 <titlestmt> 
	 	<titleproper> Southwest Folklore Center Pre-1980 Sound Disc Collection,
	 		<date normal="1931/1964" era="ce" calendar="gregorian" certainty="approximate">1931-1964</date>
	 		</titleproper> 
	 	<author>Processed by Staff.</author> 
	 </titlestmt> 
	 <publicationstmt> 
	 	<publisher>University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections</publisher> 
		<address> 
		  <addressline>PO Box 210055</addressline> 
		  <addressline>Tucson, AZ 85721-0055</addressline> 
		  <addressline>Phone: 520-621-6423</addressline> 
		  <addressline>Fax: 520-621-9733</addressline> 
		  <addressline>URL:http://speccoll.library.arizona.edu/</addressline>
		</address> 
		<date normal= "2012" era= "ce" calendar = "gregorian">; 2012</date> 
		<p>Arizona Board of Regents. All Rights Reserved.</p> 
	 </publicationstmt> 
  </filedesc> 
  <profiledesc> 
  	<creation>Inventory encoded in Oxygen XML editor by Anne Martinez. 
  		<date era="ce" encodinganalog="date" normal="20120227">February 27, 2013</date></creation> 
	 <langusage>Finding aid is in<language> English.</language></langusage> 
  </profiledesc> 
</eadheader> 
<frontmatter> 
  <titlepage> 
  	<titleproper>Southwest Folklore Center Pre-1980 Sound Disc Collection,<date era= "ce" calendar= "gregorian">1931-1964</date></titleproper> 
	 <num>Collection Number: SWF 007</num> 
  	<publisher>University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections</publisher> 
	 <list> 
		<defitem> 
		  <label>Processed by:</label> 
		  <item>Staff</item> 
		</defitem> 
		<defitem> 
		  <label>Date completed:</label> 
		  <item> 
			 <date>August 2013</date></item> 
		</defitem> 
		<defitem> 
		  <label>Encoded by:</label> 
		  <item>Anne Martinez</item> 
		</defitem> 
	 </list> 
	 <p>&#x00A9; 20013. Arizona Board of Regents. All rights reserved.</p> 
  </titlepage> 
</frontmatter> 
<archdesc level="collection" type="inventory" relatedencoding="marc21"> 
  <did id="a1"> 
	 <head>Collection Summary</head> 
  	<unittitle encodinganalog="245" label="Collection Name:"> Southwest Folklore Center Pre-1980 Sound Disc Collection,
		<unitdate type="inclusive" label="Dates:" normal="1931/1964">1931-1964</unitdate></unittitle>	 
	 <unitid label="Collection Number:" encodinganalog="099"
	 repositorycode="AzU" countrycode="us">SWF007</unitid> 
	 <origination label="Creator:"> 
	 	<persname source="lcnaf" encodinganalog="100">Collected by the University of Arizona Folklore Committee and the University of Arizona Southwest Folklore Center.</persname> </origination> 
  	<abstract label="Abstract:">Sound discs of commercial and non-commercial recordings of oral history interviews and examples of local, national, and international folk music, collected by the Center before 1980. The collection includes recordings made in 33-1/3, 45 and 78 rpm formats.</abstract> 
	 <physdesc encodinganalog="300$a" label="Physical Description:"><extent><?xm-replace_text {IN LINEAR FEET}?></extent></physdesc>	 
	 <repository label="Repository:"> 
	 	<corpname>University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections</corpname> 
		<address> 
		  <addressline>University of Arizona</addressline> 
		  <addressline>PO Box 210055</addressline> 
		  <addressline>Tucson, AZ 85721-0055</addressline> 
		  <addressline>Phone: 520-621-6423</addressline> 
		  <addressline>Fax: 520-621-9733</addressline> 
		  <addressline>URL: http://speccoll.library.arizona.edu/</addressline>		  
		</address></repository>
  	<langmaterial>Materials in <language encodinganalog="546" langcode="eng"
  		scriptcode="Latin">English</language></langmaterial>
  </did> 
  <accessrestrict> 
	 <head>Restrictions</head> 
  	<p>Researchers must use cassette tape copies of all sound discs or tape reels when they are available. An item level listing of all sound discs in the collection is available in the University of Arizona Library Special Collections. Tape reel duplicates of the sound discs are numbered to correspond to the call numbers of the sound discs themselves.</p> 
  </accessrestrict> 
  <userestrict> 
	 <head>Copyright</head> 
	 <p>It is the responsibility of the user to obtain permission to publish
		from the owner of the copyright (the institution, the creator of the record,
		the author or his/her transferees, heirs, legates, or literary executors). The
		user agrees to indemnify and hold harmless the Arizona Board of Regents for the
		University of Arizona, its officers, employees, and agents from and against all
		claims made by any person asserting that he or she is an owner of
		copyright.</p> 
  </userestrict> 
  <prefercite> 
	 <head>Credit Line</head> 
  	<p>Southwest Folklore Center Pre-1980 Sound Disc Collection, 1931-1964 (SWF007). Special Collections, University of Arizona Libraries.</p> 
  </prefercite> 
  <bioghist id="a2" encodinganalog="545"> 
	 <head>Historical Note</head> 
  	<p>Members of the University of Arizona Folklore Committee began collecting sound recordings in the 1940s which documented folklore traditions in the Southwestern United States and Mexico. Committee members most active in recording were Vicente S. Acosta (1918-1983), Frances Gillmor (1903-1993), and Byrd Howell Granger (1912-1991).</p>
  	<p>Vicente S. Acosta was a longtime member of the University's Folklore	Committee and contributor to the committee’s archive of Southwest folklore materials. His 1951 master's thesis, Some Surviving Elements of Spanish Folklore in Arizona, is considered a definitive work on the subject. A Spanish teacher at Rincon High School in Tucson, Arizona, Acosta continued to collect folklore materials throughout his career.</p>
  	<p>Frances Gillmor, an English professor at the University of Arizona, spent much of her research time collecting traditional dance dramas of Mexico. Dr. Gillmor established the Folklore Center in 1942, and served as Chairman of the Southwest Folklore Committee from 1942-1972.</p>
  	<p>Byrd Howell Granger, a professor at the University of Arizona and Chair of the Folklore Committee, 1972-1978, is best known for her revision of Will C. Barnes' Arizona Place Names, published in 1960, and Arizona's Names: X Marks the Place published in 1983. Dr. Granger was also involved in systematically collecting documentation of Arizona folk customs and beliefs.</p>
  	<p>During the 1940s and 1950s, Acosta, Granger and Gillmor, assisted by Doris Seibold, a teacher from Patagonia, Arizona, interviewed local people and recorded various types of music and oral histories using the KUAT studios at the University of Arizona. These recordings were made on 78 rpm sound discs which were used in the teaching of folklore classes at the University. Examples of international and American folk music were collected through purchase and donation. Many of the commercial recordings in this series were produced by the Library of Congress Division of Music Recording Laboratory and Folkways Records and Service Corporation of New York City. Prison songs, labor union songs, sea songs, and Mormon pioneer songs are examples of American folk music included in this series. Noted performers include Woody Guthrie, Pete Seeger, and Leadbelly. The pre-1980 sound discs were later duplicated onto tape reels. The original sound discs and the tape reels are located in the University of Arizona Library Special Collections.</p> 
  </bioghist> 
  <arrangement id="a4" encodinganalog="351$a"> 
	 <head>Arrangement</head> 
  	<p>This collection is arranged according to accession into the collection.</p>	 
	</arrangement> 
  <scopecontent id="a3" encodinganalog="520"> 
	 <head>Scope and Content Note</head> 
  	<p>All items in this collection were acquired by the University of Arizona Folklore Committee and its successor body, the University of Arizona Southwest Folklore Center before 1980. Sound discs in this collection contain commercial and non-commercial recordings of oral history interviews and examples of local, national, and international folk music. The majority of these sound discs contain interviews and music collected in Southern Arizona by Vicente S. Acosta, Byrd Howell Granger, Frances</p>
  	<p>Gillmor, and Doris Seibold. These recordings include regional music including Mormon hymns, cowboy songs, Mexican music and corridos, Native American music, fiddle and banjo tunes. The recorded interviews concern family life and traditions, home remedies, Native American languages and Tucson slang, as well as oral histories of the participants. Sound discs acquired by the Southwest Folklore Center after 1980 are available in collection SWF 008.</p>
  	<p>72 commercial recordings were obtained through the Library of Congress Division of Music Laboratory, recorded by John and Alan Lomax. Prison songs, labor union songs, sea songs, and American folk songs from the 1930s and 1940s are included in these recordings.</p>
  	<p>63 sound discs containing international and national folk songs and music were collected commercially from the Folkway Record and Service Corporation of New York City. Published primarily in the 1950s, some recordings contain music performed by Woody Guthrie, Pete Seeger, Cisco Houston, and Leadbelly.</p>
  	<p>A listing of individual items in this collection is available at the end of this document.</p> 
  </scopecontent> 
  <controlaccess id="a12"> 
	 <head>Access Terms</head> 
  	<list> 
  		<item> 
  			<subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Folk music</subject></item> 
  	</list> 
	 <list> 
		<item> 
			<subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Corridos</subject> </item> 
	 </list> 
  	<list> 
  		<item> 
  			<subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Mexican Americans -- Folklore.</subject> </item> 
  	</list> 
  	<list> 
  		<item> 
  			<subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Mexican Americans -- Music</subject> </item> 
  	</list> 
  	<list> 
  		<item> 
  			<subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Indians of North America -- Folklore</subject> </item> 
  	</list> 
  	<list> 
  		<item> 
  			<subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Indians of North America -- Music</subject> </item> 
  	</list> 
	 <list> 
		<item> 
			<genreform encodinganalog="655" source="tgm">Folklore -- Arizona</genreform> </item> 
	 </list> 
  	<list> 
  		<item> 
  			<genreform encodinganalog="655" source="tgm">Folklore -- Southwest, New</genreform> </item> 
  	</list> 
  	<list> 
  		<item> 
  			<genreform encodinganalog="655" source="tgm">Folklore -- Mexico</genreform> </item> 
  	</list> 
  </controlaccess> 
  <dsc type="combined" id="a23"> 
	 <head>Container List</head> 
	 <c01> 
	 	<did> 
	 		<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Armenta, Guadalupe</unittitle>
	 		<unitdate>May 14, 1947</unitdate>
	 		<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm, 12 in.</physdesc>
	 		<abstract>Tucson, AZ. Recorded by Vincent (Vicente) Acosta... El Corrido de le Merino (recited by Guadalupe Armenta)... Interview with Guadalupe Armenta...</abstract>
	 		<unitid label="Local Call Number:">SWF PRE1980.1/D.1</unitid>
	 	</did>
	 	<custodhist><p>Original Collector: Vicente S. Acosta</p></custodhist>
	 </c01> 
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Rios, Frank</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>March 19, 1947</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm, 12in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Tucson, AZ. Recorded by Vincent (Vicente) Acosta... Music by Frank Rios: Azatón (El Azoton) -- Dicen por ai (Dicen por alli) -- Serenata --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.2</unitid>
  		</did> 
  		<custodhist><p>Original Collector: Vicente S. Acosta</p></custodhist>
  	</c01> 
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections,	Dominguez, Connie</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>March 31, 1947</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>31, 1947; 1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm, 12in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Tucson, AZ. Recorded by Vincent (Vicente) Acosta... Music by Connie Dominquez: Las Senas del Marido -- El Celoso -- La Delgadina -- El Desertor --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.3</unitid>
  		</did> 
  		<custodhist><p>Original Collector: Vicente S. Acosta</p></custodhist>
  	</c01> 
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Rayando el Solo</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>March 31, 1947</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm, 12in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Tucson, Az. Recorded by Vincent (Vicente) Acosta... Rayando el solo --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.4</unitid>
  		</did>
  		<custodhist><p>Original Collector: Vicente S. Acosta</p></custodhist>
  	</c01> 
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Rios, Frank</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>March 19, 1947</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm, 12in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Tucson, AZ. Recorded by Vincent (Vicente) Acosta... Frank Rios: Adelita -- Valentino -- Soldado de Levita --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.5</unitid>
  		</did> 
  		<custodhist><p>Original Collector: Vicente S. Acosta</p></custodhist>
  	</c01> 
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Rios, Frank</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>March 19, 1947</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm, 12in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Tucson, AZ. Recorded by Vincent (Vicente) Acosta... Intro(duction) -- Nosotros (Frank Rios) -- La Mileguena (Frank Rios) --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.6</unitid>
  		</did>
  		<custodhist><p>Original Collector: Vicente S. Acosta</p></custodhist>
  	</c01> 
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections,	Ochoa, Chito and Tony Corral</unittitle>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm, 12in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Tucson, AZ. Recorded by Vicente S. Acosta... Corrido de Elena, la Traicionera (Chito Ochoa) -- Corrido de Rosita Elvires (Tony Corral) --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.7 (in.)</unitid>
  		</did>
  		<custodhist><p>Original Collector: Vicente S. Acosta</p></custodhist>
  	</c01> 
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Corral, Tony</unittitle>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm, 12in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Tucson, AZ. Recorded by Vicente S. Acosta... Corrido de Juan Charrasqueado (Tony Corral) -- Jamas (Tony Corral) --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.8</unitid>
  		</did> 
  		<custodhist><p>Original Collector: Vicente S. Acosta</p></custodhist>
  	</c01> 
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Corral, Tony</unittitle>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm, 12in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Tucson, AZ. Recorded by Vicente S. Acosta... Corrido de Valiente Quintero (Tony Corral) -- Corrido de Valiente Quintero (Tony Corral) --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.9</unitid>
  		</did> 
  		<custodhist><p>Original Collector: Vicente S. Acosta</p></custodhist>
  	</c01> 
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Rios, Paco and Concepcion Guerrero</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>May, 1948</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Tucson, AZ. Recorded by Vicente S. Acosta... Humo en los ojos (Paco Rios) -- Tiene tus ojos (Paco Rios) -- La Barca de oro (Concepcion Guerrero) --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.10</unitid>
  		</did>
  		<custodhist><p>Original Collector: Vicente S. Acosta</p></custodhist>
  	</c01> 
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Guerrero, Lalo, Eugene Guerrero and Concepcion Guerrero</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>May, 1948</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Tucson, Az. Recorded by Vicente S. Acosta... La Adelita (Lalo Guerrero) -- Corrido de los dos hermanos (Eugene Guerrero) -- El Corrido del merino (Concepcion	Guerrero) --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.11</unitid>
  		</did>
  		<custodhist><p>Original Collector: Vicente S. Acosta</p></custodhist>
  	</c01> 
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Copeland, George and Larry Cage</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>February 15, 1948</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Tucson, AZ. Recorded at the Old Time Fiddlers' Contest, Tucson, Arizona, February 15, 1948, by Charles Wiley... Breakdown: Mississippi Sawyer (George Copeland) -- Breakdown: Cross-eyed Joe (George Copeland) -- Breakdown: Turkey in the straw (Larry Cage) -- Breakdown: She'll be coming round the mountain -- Waltz: Missouri waltz (Larry Cage) --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.14</unitid>
  		</did>
  	</c01> 
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Hamby, Wild Horse Shorty and Roy Mack</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>February 15, 1948</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Tucson, AZ. Recorded at the Old Time Fiddlers' Contest, Tucson, AZ., February 15, 1948, by Charles Wiley... Breakdown: Sweet Avalina (Wild Horse Shorty Hamby and Mrs. Hamby, guitar) -- Sweet Avalina (Wild Horse Shorty Hamby, Mrs. Hamby) -- Breakdown: Hey, hey, hey or Ragtime Annie (Wild Horse Shorty Hamby) -- Breakdown: Eighth of January (Roy Mack) --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.15</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01> 
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Mack, Roy</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>February 15, 1948</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Tucson, AZ. Recorded by Charles Wiley at the Old-Time Fiddlers' Contest... Crazy waltz -- Breakdown: Waggoner -- Soldiers' joy -- Wednesday night waltz -</abstract>
  			
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.16</unitid>
  		</did>
  		<custodhist><p>Original Collector: Charles Wiley</p></custodhist>
  	</c01> 
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Scott, Pugs and Bill Bradley</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>February 15, 1948</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Tucson, AZ. Recorded by Charles Wiley at Old Time Fiddlers' Contest... Ragtime Annie (Pugs Scott) -- Bill Bradley: Soldiers' joy -- Kelly waltz -- Lop-eared mule --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.17</unitid>
  		</did>
  		<custodhist><p>Original Collector: Charles Wiley</p></custodhist>
  	</c01> 
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Hamby, Wild Horse Shorty and Roy Mack</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>February 15, 1948</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc analog, 78 rpm, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Tucson AZ. Recorded by Charles Wiley at the Old Time Fiddlers' Contest... Arkansas Traveller (sic) (Wild Horse Shorty Hamby) -- Arkansas Traveller (sic) (Roy Mack) --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.18</unitid>
  		</did> 
  		<custodhist><p>Original Collector: Charles Wiley</p></custodhist>
  	</c01> 
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Hamby, Wild Horse Shorty, Larry Gates and Pugs Scott</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>February 15, 1948</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Whoa, mule, whoa! (Wild Horse Shorty Hamby, accompanied by his wife on guitar) -- Redwing, (Larry Gates) -- Golden slippers (Pugs Scott) --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.19</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01> 
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Ray, Mrs. John A.</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>May 1948</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 78rpm, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Mesa, AZ. Recorded by Frances Gillmor for the University of Arizona Folklore Archive... Sung by Mrs. John A. Ray: I'll be a little Mormon -- Oh Zion dear how joyful -- Come my dearest, come my fairest --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.20</unitid>
  		</did>
  		<custodhist><p>Original Collector: Frances Gillmor</p></custodhist>
  	</c01> 
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Ray, Mrs. John A.</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>May, 1948</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 78rpm, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Mesa, AZ. Recorded by Frances Gillmor... Sung by Mrs. John A. Ray: Twas on a cold and winter's morn -- The Drunkard's ragged wee'un --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.21</unitid>
  		</did>
  		<custodhist><p>Original Collector: Frances Gillmor</p></custodhist>
  	</c01> 
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Ray, Mrs. John A.</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>May, 1948</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 78rpm, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Mesa, AZ. Recorded by Frances Gillmor for the Univeristy of Arizona Folklore Archive... Sung by Mrs. John A. Ray: Oh Father, dear Father, come home to me now -- Come all ye Texan Rangers and listen unto me --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.22</unitid>
  		</did>
  		<custodhist><p>Original Collector: Frances Gillmor</p></custodhist>
  	</c01> 
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Ray, Mrs. John A., Mrs. Verda Eyring, and Mrs. Lurline Russell</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>May, 1948</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Recorded by Frances Gillmor for the Univeristy of Arizona Folklore Archive... Mrs. John A. Ray: My dear little son, go to sleep -- All blue eyes close in slumber -- We are here in Council Bluffs -- The Birdies' ball -- The Fox (Mrs. Verda Eyring) -- I'm going to write to Papa (Mrs. Lurline Russell) -- I'll never use tobacco (Mrs. John A. Ray) --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.25</unitid>
  		</did>
  		<custodhist><p>Original Collector: Frances Gillmor</p></custodhist>
  	</c01> 
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Ray, Mrs. John A. and Mrs. Kathleen Palmer</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>May, 1948</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Recorded for University of Arizona Folklore Archive by Francis Gillmor... The Crow (Mrs. John A. Ray) -- The Toad said to the bumble bee (Mrs. Kathleen Palmer) --</abstract>
  			
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.26</unitid>
  		</did>
  		<custodhist><p>Original Collector: Frances Gillmor</p></custodhist>
  	</c01> 
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Busby, Abraham J. and Ethel Oldfather</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>June 21, 1949</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Patagonia, AZ. A Freighting from Wilcox to Globe [Ariz.](Abraham John Busby) -- In sunny Tennessee (Ethel Oldfather) -- Dixie (Abraham Oldfather) -- Froggie	School (Ethel Oldfather) --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.27</unitid>
  		</did>
  		<custodhist><p>Original Collector: University of Arizona Project</p></custodhist>
  	</c01> 
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Busby, Abraham J., Don Juan Urias, and Ethel M. Oldfather</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>June 21, 1949</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Tucson, AZ. Recorded by Peter Tufts and Doris Seibold... None do preach the gospel like the Mormons (Abraham J. Busby) -- Cancion (Don Juan Urias) -- All hearts be merry (Abraham J. Busby) -- Coon, coon, coon (Ethel M. Oldfather) --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.28</unitid>
  		</did> 
  		<custodhist><p>Original Collector: University of Arizona Project</p></custodhist>
  	</c01> 
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Capps, Will, Jack Turner, and Ethel M. Oldfather</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>June 21, 1949</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Tucson, AZ. Recorded by Doris Seibold... Ethel M. Oldfather: Version of swapping song -- Civil War song (Year of Jubilo)... Will Capps and Jack Turner: Introduction -- Violin tune -- Violin tune -- Violin tune --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.29</unitid>
  		</did>
  		<custodhist><p>Original Collector: University of Arizona Project</p></custodhist>
  	</c01> 
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Capps, Will, Jack Turner, and Grace Murrieta</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>June 21, 1949</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Tucson, AZ. Recorded by Doris Seibold... Performers include: Will Capps; Jack Turner; Grace Murrieta... La Varsoviono -- My wild Irish Rose -- Rye waltz -- Whistling -- Corrido about two bandits, Cuevas and M. Yescas --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.30</unitid>
  		</did> 
  		<custodhist><p>Original Collector: University of Arizona Project</p></custodhist>
  	</c01> 
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Murrieta, Grace</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>June 21, 1949</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Tucson, AZ. Recorded by Doris Seibold... Solos by Grace Murrieta... Corrido about Cuevas &amp; Marcelino Yescas, part II -- Corrido de Delgadina -- Corrido de Ubaldina, part I --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.31</unitid>
  		</did>
  		<custodhist><p>Original Collector: University of Arizona Project</p></custodhist>
  	</c01> 
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Murrieta, Grace</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>June 21, 1949</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Tucson, AZ. Recorded by Doris Seibold... Solos by Grace Murrieta... Corrido de Ubaladina, part II -- Que sacrificios -- Por una mujer cusada -- Cuando salgas campor --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.32</unitid>
  		</did>
  		<custodhist><p>Original Collector: University of Arizona Project</p></custodhist>
  	</c01> 
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Urias, Don Juan and Ethel Oldfather</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>June 21, 1949</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Tucson, AZ. Recorded by Doris Seibold... Mercario Romero, parts I and II (Don Juan Urias) -- Pretty pussy willows (Ethel Oldfather) --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.33</unitid>
  		</did>
  		<custodhist><p>Original Collector: University of Arizona Project</p></custodhist>
  	</c01> 
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Urias, Don Juan</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>June 21, 1949</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Tucson, AZ. Recorded by Doris Seibold... Corrido de Cananea, parts I and II --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.34</unitid>
  		</did>
  		<custodhist><p>Original Collector: University of Arizona Project</p></custodhist>
  	</c01> 
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Arias (Urias), Don Juan</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>June 21, 1949</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Tucson, AZ. Recorded by Doris Seibold... El Aguila -- La Victima --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.35</unitid>
  		</did>
  		<custodhist><p>Original Collector: University of Arizona Project</p></custodhist>
  	</c01> 
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Urias, Don Juan</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>June 21, 1949</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Tucson, AZ. Recorded by Doris Seibold... Corridos de Fuentes, parts I and II --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.36</unitid>
  		</did>
  		<custodhist><p>Original Collector: University of Arizona Project</p></custodhist>
  	</c01> 
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Hummel, Alvesa and Mercedes Amados</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>December 12, 1948</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm, 10 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Patagonia, AZ. Duets by Alvesa Hummel and Mercedes Amados: Valentina -- Capullito de Adeline... Solos by Alvesa Hummel: Primavera -- Una Indita --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.37 (10in.)</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01> 
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Hummel, Alvesa and Mercedes Amados</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>December 12, 1948</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm,	10 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Patagonia, AZ. Duets by Alvesa Hummel and Mercedes Amados: In Old Nogales -- Cuatro milpas -- Noche de ronda --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.38 (10in.)</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01> 
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Alvesa Hummel's Orchestra</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>December 22, 1948</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm,	10 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Patagonia, AZ. Varsoviana -- Heel-toe polka -- Schottishe -- Mexican rumba - Juan Charresqueado --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.39 (10in.)</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01> 
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Alvesa Hummel's Orchestra</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>December 22, 1948</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm,	10 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Patagonia, AZ. Alvesa Hummel's Orchestra performing for the Little Outfit's Christmas party...</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.40 (10in.)</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01> 
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Laguna Brothers</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>December 30, 1948</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm,	10 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Patagonia, AZ. Duets by the Laguna Brothers... Naci para Quererte -- Nada gano con Quererte</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.41 (10in.)</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01> 
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Laguna Brothers</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>December 30, 1948</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm,	10 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Patagonia, AZ. Las Mananitas Zapatias -- Desegando --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.42 (10in.)</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01> 
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Laguna Brothers</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>December 30, 1948</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm,	10 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Patagonia, AZ. La Gairota -- La Bola -- Soy Mexicano --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.43 (10in.)</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01> 
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Urias, Juan</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>November 3, 1948</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm,	10 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Patagonia, AZ. Recorded by Al Whitney and Doris Seibold, ... Untitled song sung by Juan Urias..</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.44 (10in.)</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01> 
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections Murrieta, Grace</unittitle>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm, 10 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Tucson, AZ. Corrido de los Yescas sung by Grace Murrieta, Patagonia, Arizona --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.45 (10in.)</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01> 
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Gardner, Edwin (Lucky)</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>December 12, 1948</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm, 10 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Patagonia, AZ. Recorded by Al Whiting and Doris Seibold... Performed by Edwin "Lucky" Gardner: Bad brahma bull -- In Old Nogales --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.46 (10in.)</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01> 
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Beals, Pauline</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>December 11, 1948</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm, 10 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Patagonia, AZ. Recorded by Al Whiting and Doris Seibold... Performed by Pauline Beals: The Dying ranger -- The Yellow Rose of Texas -- The Strawberry roan --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.47 (10in.)</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01> 
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Beals, Pauline</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>December 30, 1948</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm, 10 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Patagonia, AZ. Note on label indicates recording may be poor... Performed by Pauline Beals: Napanee -- Yellow Rose of Texas -- Cowboy's home sweet home --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.48</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01> 
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Beals, Pauline</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>December 30, 1948</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Patagonia, AZ. Recorded by Al Whiting and Doris Seibold... Performed by Pauline Beals: Message from home sweet home --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.49 (10in.)</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01> 
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Beals, Pauline</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>December 11, 1948</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Patagonia, AZ. Performed by Pauline Beals: Napanee -- Cowboy's lament -- [Part of] Yellow Rose of Texas --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.50</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01> 
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Beals, Pauline</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>December 30, 1948</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm,	10 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Patagonia, AZ. Performed by Pauline Beals: Billy Venero -- Kenny Wagner's surrender --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D51 (10in.)</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01> 
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Kier, William (Scotty)</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>December 11, 1948</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm,	10 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Patagonia, AZ. Sung by William "Scotty" Kier: An Irishman's dream of home -- The Girl	I left behind -- Son of Ireland --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.52 (10in.)</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01> 
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Garcia, Tranquelino and Julio Ortega</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>April 18, 1949</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Tucson, AZ. Recorded by Al Whiting and Doris Seibold... Played by Tranquelino Garcia and Julio Ortega (mandolin and guitar): Ofelia -- Luces blancas --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.53</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01> 
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Urias, Juan and Tranquelino Garcia</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>April 18, 1949</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Tucson, AZ. Recorded by Al Whiting and Doris Seibold... Sung by Don Juan Urias: Los Pajarillos escondidos -- Corrido de Pancho Villa... Sung by Tranquelino Garcia: Coplas and laugh --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.54</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01> 
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Urias, Juan</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>Urias, Juan</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Tucson, AZ. Recorded by Al Whiting and Doris Seibold... Duet by Don Juan Urias and unknown: La Gusanera... Solo by Don Juan Urias: La Barca -- Instrumental: Prestame tu caballito --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.55</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01> 
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Urias, Juan</unittitle>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Patagonia, AZ. Sung by Don Juan Urias: Cancion --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.56</unitid>
  		</did>
  		<custodhist><p>Original Collector: Doris Seibold</p></custodhist>
  	</c01> 
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Powell, Dr. Desmond</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>June 21, 1949</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Tucson, AZ. Two dates appear on label: May 1949 and June 21, 1949... Performed by Dr. Desmond Powell: Down in yon forest -- Fiosh McHugh O'Bryne -- Old Smokey --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.57</unitid>
  		</did>
  		<custodhist><p>Original Collector: University of Arizona Project</p></custodhist>
  	</c01> 
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Powell, Dr. Desmond</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>May 1949</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Tucson, AZ. Performed by Dr. Desmond Powell: The Croodin Doo -- The Streets of Laredo -- The Golden willow tree -- The Eddystone light --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.58</unitid>
  		</did>
  		<custodhist><p>Original Collector: University of Arizona Project</p></custodhist>
  	</c01> 
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Thomas, Bob and Barton Wright</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>June 21, 1949</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Tucson, AZ. Recorded by A.W. Bork... Performed by Bob Thomas: John Kanoatsie -- Streets of Glencairn... Duets performed by Bob Thomas and Bart Wright: Good old mountain dew -- Will the circle be unbroken --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.59</unitid>
  		</did> 
  		<custodhist><p>Original Collector: University of Arizona Project</p></custodhist>
  	</c01> 
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Thomas, Bob and Barton Wright</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>June 21, 1949</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Tucson, AZ.</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.60</unitid>
  		</did>
  		<custodhist><p>Original Collector: University of Arizona Project</p></custodhist>
  	</c01> 
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Thomas, Bob and Barton Wright</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>April 21, 1949</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Tucson, AZ. Recorded by A.W. Bork... Boll weevil song -- Ground hog -- Sourwood peaks -- Miner's lament --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.61</unitid>
  		</did> 
  		<custodhist><p>Original Collector: University of Arizona Project</p></custodhist>
  	</c01>  
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Thomas, Bob and [Barton Wright]</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>April 21, 1949</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Tucson, AZ. Recorded by A.W. Bork... You gotta walk that lonesome valley -- Columbus Stockade blues -- What will you do -- John Henry --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.62</unitid>
  		</did>
  		<custodhist><p>Original Collector: University of Arizona Project</p></custodhist>
  	</c01> 
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Baird, Mrs. Amy Hancock</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>June, 1949</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Safford, AZ. The Hunter wings his bugle horn -- Green Bill -- Oh, I was born in Boston --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.63</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>   
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Baird, Mrs. Amy Hancock</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>June, 1949</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Safford, AZ. Willie Gray -- My sweet Anona from Arizona -- My grandma lived on yonder green -- Young man who wouldn't have his corn --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.64</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>   	
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections and Interview, Baird, Mrs. Amy Hancock</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>June, 1949</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Safford, AZ. Valley of Custer -- See a weary band of pilgrims (a pioneer song) -- Interview regarding song origins --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.65</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Baird, Mrs. Amy Hancock</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>June, 1949</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Safford, AZ. O'er rugged hills -- Oh Robin, they tell me you are going away --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.66</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Baird, Mrs. Amy Hancock</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>June, 1949</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Safford, AZ. Where are you going my pretty maid -- I'll hang my harp on a willow tree -- God pity Bessie, the drunkard's child, part II -- </abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.67</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Baird, Mrs. Amy Hancock</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>June, 1949</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Safford, AZ. As I was walking one morning in May, part I -- God pity Bessie, the drunkard's child, part I --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.68</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Baird, Mrs. Amy Hancock</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>June, 1949</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Safford, AZ. Tis of a youg sailor boy -- I should dearly love to marry --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.69</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Baird, Mrs. Amy Hancock</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>June, 1949</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Safford, AZ. As I was walking one morning in May, part II --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.70</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections and Interview, Buno, Paul</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>May 4, 1950</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm, 10 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Grand Canyon, AZ. Interview by Al Whiting regarding songs by Paul Buno... Havasupai Indian Music -- Opening verse, Peach dance song -- Death song (Mohave mourning song) --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.71 (10in.)</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections and Interview, Bailey, Paul and Gladys Barker</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>March 26, 1950</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Tucson, AZ. Bonaparte's retreat, and another untitled violin tune performed by Paul Bailey... Interview by Al Whiting concerns Bailey's life and music...</abstract>
  			<unitid>Pre-1980-1/D.73</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Bailey, Paul and Gladys Barker</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>March 11, 1950</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Tucson, AZ. Billy Vanero -- Bloomer Johnson --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.74</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Baily, Paul</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>April 9, 1950</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Performed by Paul Bailey: Lord Ullin's daughter -- Disscussion of "Lord Ullin's daughter" with Al Whiting -- Poor Caroline (tune only) --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.76</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Bailey, Paul and Gladys Barker</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>March 25, 1950</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Performed by Paul Bailey and Gladys Barker...Lowland's low -- Green grow the lilacs --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.77</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Baily, Paul</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>March 25, 1950</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Performed by Paul Bailey: Utah Carl --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.78</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Wadleigh, Atherton B.</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>May, 1950</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Tucson, AZ. Performed by Atherton B. Wadleigh...Fragments of: Old Thompson had an old gray mule -- I went to call on Miss McGee -- Dime porque me enganste -- Bury me not on the lone prarie --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.79</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Pooyauma, Rex and Allen Pooyauma, Ralph Doyauma, Herbert Honani</unittitle>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Recording by Mac Schweitzer...Performed by Rex Pooyauma; Allen Pooyauma; Ralph Doyauma; Herbert Honani...Hopi songs [Sunrise song -- Want some Piki -- Approaching song -- Hopi versions of Comanche songs -- Mixed dancers' song -- ]</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.81</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Pooyauma, Rex and Allen Pooyauma, Ralph Doyauma, Herbert Honani</unittitle>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Recording by Mac Schweitzer...Performed by Rex Pooyauma; Allen Pooyauma; Ralph Doyauma; Herbert Honani...Hopi songs [Hopi buffalo dance song -- Hopi butterfly dance song -- Hopi version of a Navajo buffalo dance song -- Mixed dance Katchinas song -- Hopi version of a Navajo dance song -- ]</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.82</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Pooyauma, Rex and Allen Pooyauma, Ralph Doyauma, Herbert Honani</unittitle>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Recorded by Mac Schweitzer...Performed by Rex Pooyauma; Allen Pooyauma; Ralph Doyauma; Herbert Honani...Hopi songs [Hopi long hair dance song -- Closing song -- ]</abstract>
  			<unitid>Local Call Number: SWF PRE1980.1/D.83</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Morris, Charles G., Mr. and Mrs. Charles G. Morris</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>1953</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Tumacacori, AZ. Recorded by Doris Seibold...Performed by Mr. Morris: A Church without a bishop, a state without a king -- Poor Tom, a sea song -- The Old hen flew over in the garden...Performed by Mrs. Morris: If I were queen of France --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.84</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Morris, Charles G., Mr. and Mrs. Charles G. Morris</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>1953</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Tucson, AZ. Recorded by Doris Seibold...Performers are Mr. and Mrs. Charles G. Morris...Sir Robert Kilaloo (Mrs. Morris) -- Some folks love to say (Mrs. Morris) --A Family that once resided in the very same thoroughfare that I did (Mr. Morris) -- A Little peach in an orchard grew -- Listen to my tale of woe (Mr. Morris) --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.85</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Morris, Charles G., Mr. and Mrs. Charles G. Morris</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>1953</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Tucson, AZ. Recorded by Doris Seibold...Performed by Mr. and Mrs. Charles G. Morris: I'm Romeo -- Oh where have you been Billy Boy...Performed by Mr. Morris: Let's go home -- No more walking in the moonlight -- tale of woe (Mr. Morris) --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.86</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Hummel, Alvesa and Juan Urias</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>December 31, 1953</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Patagonia, AZ. Recorded by Dean Robb, University of New Mexico, at Doris Seibold's chuck wagon dinner, T-Tail Ranch, Patagonia, Arizona, for the American Folklore Society...Performances by unknown girls, Alvesa Hummel, and Juan Urias of three songs...</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.87</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Urias, Juan and Alvesa Hummel</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>December 31, 1953</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Patagonia, AZ. Recorded by Dean Robb, University of New Mexico, at Doris Seibold's chuck wagon dinner, T-Tail Ranch, Patagonia, Arizona, for the American Folklore Society...Performed by Juan Urias: Song, Part II -- Laughing song, Part II -- Crying song, Part I...Performed by Alvesa Hummel: La Indita --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.88</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Busby, A.J., Alvesa Hummel and Juan Urias</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>December 31, 1953</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>December 31, 1953; 1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Patagonia, AZ. Recorded by Dean Robb, University of New Mexico, at Doris Seibold's chuck wagon dinner, T-Tail Ranch, Patagonia, Arizona, for the American Folklore Society...Freighting from Wilcox to Globe (A.J. Busby) -- I'm poor, I'm old and only in the way (A.J. Busby) -- Las Mananitas (Alvesa Hummel) -- Laughing song, Part I (Juan Urias) --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.89</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Busby, A.J.</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>December 31, 1953</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Patagonia, AZ. Recorded by Dean Robb, University of New Mexico, at Doris Seibold's chuck wagon dinner, T-Tail Ranch, Patagonia, Arizona, for the American Folklore Society...Performed by A.J. Busby: Freighting from Wilcox to Globe -- The Sheriff's sale -- Dixie -- Nice young Mormons --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.90</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Thomas, Eleece</unittitle>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Tucson, AZ. Recorded by Mrs. Wm. Gaston -- [Negro blues] and work songs --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.91</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>May 12, 1949</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>The Library of Congress Division of Music Recording Laboratory. Robin bird song (Phoenix) -- There's a spot that I know (Coolidge) -- No home for the poor (Tempe) --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.92</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>May 12, 1949</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>The Library of Congress Division of Music Recording Laborabory. Way down in old St. Francis Bottom (Tucson) --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.93</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections</unittitle>
  			<physdesc>Pueblo Grande Museum; 1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Phoenix, AZ., Pueblo Grande Museum. Recorded with introduction and concluding remarks by Odd S. Halseth...Cochiti songs include: Chaquenna -- Travel song -- Cradle song - - Daybreak song --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.94</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections</unittitle>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Phoenix, AZ., Pueblo Grande Museum. Recorded with introduction and concluding remarks by Odd S. Halseth...Green corn dance (Cochiti) -- War chants (the last war chant with English insert "Lord bring them home", Cochiti) --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.95</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections</unittitle>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Phoenix, AZ., Pueblo Grande Museum. Recorded by Odd S. Halseth...Navajo yebichi: Eagle-in-the-air Narrow eagle -- Seneca false face song -- Navajo yebichi songs: Eagle-in-the-air (complete) -- Narrow eagle (incomplete) --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.96</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections</unittitle>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Phoenix, AZ., Pueblo Grande Museum. Recorded with comments by Odd S. Halseth...Caddo stomp dance -- Zuni corn dance -- Jemez hunting or arrow dance -- Kiowa round dance -- Kiowa war dance -- Taos round dance --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.98 90</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections</unittitle>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Phoenix, AZ., Pueblo Grande Museum. Recorded with comments by Odd S. Halseth...Pima kingfisher song -- Pima Ka-a-ghem -- Cocopa ilcha "Bird song" -- Cocopa karuk -- Apache gahan (White Mountain) -- Apache gahan (Mescalero) -- Comanche peyote song --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.99</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Busby, A.J.</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>1954</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Tucson, AZ. Recorded by Carroll Rinehart...Keeley cure -- Freighting from Wilcox to Globe -- I'm just forty-five and my dear little wife -- Hose cart song -- A Passing policeman found a little child -- Near a cottage in the twilight -- Stood a soldier and a maid -- My grandfather's farm --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.100</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Busby, A.J.</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>1954</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Tucson, AZ. Recorded by Carroll Rinehart...Sheriff's sale -- Engagement ring -- On the baggage coach ahead -- Miss Fogarty's Christmas cake -- Nice young Mormons -- Old and only in the way -- Are you staying, staying, in the tender shepherd's fold?</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.101</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections and Narratives, Mormon pioneer pageant</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>July 24, 1954</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>St. David, AZ. Recorded by Desmond Powell and Carl Ketoham at the Mormon Pioneer Pageant...Introductory narrative (Mrs. Tilloston) -- Pioneer song -- interview -- Grandmother's diary -- Account of Brigham Young -- Account of departure from Nauvoo -- Burial of a child on the plains...Continued on Pre-1980-1/D.103...</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.102</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections and Narratives, Mormon pioneer pageant</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>July 24, 1954</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>St. David, AZ. Recording is a continuation of Pre-1980-1/D.102...Recorded by Desmond Powell and Carl Ketoham at the Mormon Pioneer Pageant...Narrative: Festivities en route -- Dance: Tiptoe through the tulips -- Narrative: Indians tableau -- Narrative: German Mormons -- Speech on LDS in modern Germany -- Narrative: Hardships en route -- Speech by Bringham Young, tableau -- Narrative: Persecutions, army -- Tableau: Bringham Young with army officers -- Narrative: Drafting of husband -- Handcarts -- Handcart song -- Come, come, ye saints --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.103</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Colladay, Diana, Ralph Corrales and Frank Rodriguez</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>May 13, 1954</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Tucson, AZ. Recorded by V[icente] Acosta...Cancion de cuna (Diana Colladay) -- Proverbs (Diana Colladay) -- Cancion de primavera (Diana Colladay, accompanied by Ralph Corrales and Frank Rodriguez) -- Corrido de los dos hermanos (Frank Rodriguez and Ralph Corrales) -- Corrido de Santa Amalia (Ralph Corrales and Frank Rodriguez) -- Corrido de Jose Lisorio (Ralph Corrales and Frank Rodriguez)... Colladay, Corrales, and Rodriguez were students at Tucson Senior High School...</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.104</unitid>
  		</did>
  		<custodhist><p>Original Collector: Vicente S. Acosta</p></custodhist>
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections and Interview, Colladay, Diana, V[icente] Acosta, Herb Burrows, and Guadalupe Armenta</unittitle>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Tucson, AZ. Recorded by V[icente] Acosta...Tres hojitas (Diana Colladay) -- La Realera, camp follower (V[icente] Acosta) -- Preguntale a las estrellas (V[icente] Acosta and Herb Burrows) -- Corridos recited by Guadalupe Armenta: El Cautivo, a famous race horse -- El Desertor -- Luisita -- El Real de Guadalupe -- Abraham Lincoln...Incomplete interview between Vicente S. Acosta and Armenta on the "gaucho slang" (continued on Pre-1980-1/D.106-107)...</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.105</unitid>
  		</did>
  		<custodhist><p>Original Collector: Vicente S. Acosta</p></custodhist>
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Interview, Armenta, Sr. Guadalupe</unittitle>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Sound disc contains continuation of interview with Mr. Guadalupe Armenta by Vicente S. Acosta on gaucho slang...</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.106</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Brannen, Charlie, Ed Gardner and Guadalupe Armenta</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>Summer, 1953</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Tucson and Patagonia, AZ. Sound disc contains three distinct recordings: My name is Charlie Brannen, sung by Travis Edmonson and recorded by Carl Ketcham, Tucson, Arizona, 1953...In old Nogales, sung by Ed Gardner and recorded by Doris Seibold in Patagonia, Arizona...Continuation of an interview by Vicente S. Acosta with Mr. Guadalupe Armenta on gaucho slang, recorded in Tucson, Arizona...</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.107</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Interview, Stevens, Jess</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>April, 1955</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Sound disc contains part one of an interview with Jess Stevens (Apache) by Larry Kellner, and includes an Apache dance-chant...</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.108</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Interview, Stevens, Jess</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>April, 1955</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Sound disc contains part of an interview with Jess Stevens (Apache), recorded Larry Kellner, and includes an Apache dance-chant...</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.109</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections and Interviews, Fellows, Mr. Clinton D.</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>Winter, 1955</unitdate>
  			<unitdate>April, 1955</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Tucson, AZ. Sound disc contains the end of an interview with Jess Stevens (Apache), recorded by Larry Kellner...Mr. Fellows performs the sing-song method of learning [the] alphabet and [multiplication] tables in his youth in Vandalia, Michigan...Also contains some nonsense syllable rhymes...</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.110</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections and Interview, England, Judy</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>November 19, 1949</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Carmen, AZ. Recorded by Al Whiting...There was a Phillipine hombre -- Song in many languages - Que sorry es la vida -- "Italian" song -- Alas, mi vida - yo soy tu querer -- The Old grey mare -- Nocodemus [Nicodemus] the slave -- The Prodigal son -- Nurse's song -- Serán las dos -- There once was an hombre -- Game song from Sonora and a discussion of going to school there --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.111</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Clark Myron</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>May 1, 1949</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Carmen, AZ. Recorded by Al Whiting...Devils' Roping (Myron Clark) -- Ninety eight bottles of beer on the wall (sung in chorus by Boy Scout Troops [66 &amp; 96]) --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.112</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Lee Katie</unittitle>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Tucson, AZ. "Sung by Katie Lee and her guitar"...Trail herding song (music by Katie Lee) -- Spanish is the loving tongue -- Johnny Ringo (music by Katie Lee, and chorus added by her) -- Wee little Paiute (written in last five years by Cassie Monson and A.R. Syman of Monticello, Utah) --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.113</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Lee Katie</unittitle>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Tucson, AZ. "Sung by Katie Lee and her guitar"...Blue Mountain (written by Cassie Monson -- Lolita (music by Katie Lee) -- The Frisco Peaks (Tyin' knots in the devil's tail) -- Lasca (music by Katie Lee) --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.114</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, La Farge, Pete</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>February, 1956</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Tucson, AZ. The Pony called Nell -- Walkin' John -- 'Twas in the spring time of the year -- The Key to the highway blues -- Yavapai Pete --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.115</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, La Farge, Pete</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>February, 1956</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Tucson, AZ. Blues: Now Betty told Dupris, "Get me a dime" -- The Ballad of Roger Young -- The Old Chisholm Trail --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.116</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Garlinghouse, Bill</unittitle>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Globe, AZ. Recorded by Ben E. Timian...Can I sleep in your brain tonight, Mister? -- Butcher's bay -- East bound train -- Kitty Wells -- Lover of lone Green Valley --</abstract>
  			<unitid>Pre-1980-1/D.117</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Garlinghouse, Bill</unittitle>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Globe, AZ. Recorded by Ben E. Timian...I got no use for the women -- Letter from home sweet home -- My mother the queen of my heart -- Jack and Joe -- Little Mohee -- When the work's all done this fall -- Maple on the hill -- Put your little foot -- Tennessee waltz -- Golden slippers --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.118</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Garlinghouse, Bill</unittitle>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Globe, AZ. My Juanita -- Little Joe -- The Wrangler -- Little Joe -- The Wrangler's sister Nell -- Floyd Collins -- Beer barrel polka --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.119</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Garlinghouse, Bill</unittitle>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Globe, AZ. Recorded by Ben E. Timian...Hobo Bill -- Wreck of ol' Number Nine -- Punchin' the dough -- Charlie Rutledge -- My pretty quadroon -- Moonlight and skies --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.120</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Miller, Bob</unittitle>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Globe, AZ. Recorded by Ben E. Timian...Songs [sung] by Bob Miller at the Elkhorn Ranch near Sasabee, Arizona: Hoe-down -- Hobo Bill -- Windy Bill -- Days of '49 -- The God damn wheel -- The Bad Brahma bull --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.121</unitid>
  		</did> 
  		<custodhist><p> Original Collector: Ben E. Timian</p></custodhist>
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Shreeves, Charles</unittitle>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Globe, AZ. Recorded by Ben E. Timian...Sung by Charles Shreeves: Bad Brahma bull -- The Zebra dun -- The Strawberry roan -- A Cowboy's dance song --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.122</unitid>
  		</did>
  		<custodhist><p> Original Collector: Ben E. Timian</p></custodhist>
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Strickland, Dee, Ben E. Timian and Jim Griffith</unittitle>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Tucson, AZ. and Flagstaff, AZ. Recorded by Ben E. Timian in Flagstaff...Songs [sung] by Dee Strickland: Careless love -- Wayfaring stranger -- Long time ago -- Sometimes I feel like a motherless child -- Barbara [Allen?] Ellen -- Ben E. Timian and Jim Griffith: Your mother still prays for you, Jack -- Cowboy Jack -- I'll be hanged if they're going to hang me -- Fort Dix boogie --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.123</unitid>
  		</did>
  		<custodhist><p> Original Collector: Ben E. Timian and Jim Griffith</p></custodhist>
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Strickland, Dee</unittitle>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, [33 1/3 rpm], 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Flagstaff, AZ. Recorded by Ben E. Timian...Songs [sung] by Dee Strickland: Mistletoe bough -- Takes a worried man to sing a worried song -- Goodby little darling -- I'll be all smiles tonight -- Green grow the lilacs -- Dreary, black hills -- Marching to Pretoria -- Delia -- Way back in the hills -- Roundup lullaby --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.124</unitid>
  		</did> 
  		<custodhist><p> Original Collector: Ben E. Timian</p></custodhist>
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Strickland, Dee</unittitle>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Flagstaff, AZ. Recorded by Ben E. Timian...Songs [sung] by Dee Strickland: Down in the valley -- My pretty quadroon -- Two brothers -- Streets of Laredo -- Zebra dunn -- To the fox -- If I were a blackbird --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.125</unitid>
  		</did> 
  		<custodhist><p> Original Collector: Ben E. Timian</p></custodhist>
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Interview, Elias, Araella F., Sra. Refrigio Aguirre Elias, Juan Elias Marcos, and Alfred Elias</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>May, 1956</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Tucson, AZ. Recorded by Aravelea F. Elias... Continuation of interview of a party at her house about old-time Mexican remedies, tales, festival customs, foods, etc... Interview in Spanish and English... Transcript available in SWF 002, box 5, under Elias.</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.126</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Interview, Elias, Aravella F.</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>May, 1956</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, [33 1/3 rpm], 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Tucson, AZ. Recorded by Aravella F. Elias... Continuation of Aravella F. Elias interview about old-time Mexican remedies, tales, festival customs, and foods in Tucson... Interview in Spanish with some English... Interview in four parts... Transcript available in SWF 002, box 5, under Elias.</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.127</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Interview, Diamos de Grazia, Alexandra</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>April 15, 1956</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Tucson, AZ. Recorded by Magdalena Diamos... Continuation of interview with Alexandra Diamos de Grazia about Mexican tales and legends... In English... Songs include: El Tejano -- El Merino… Transcript available in SWF 002, box 5, under Diamos.</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.128</unitid>
  		</did>
  		<custodhist><p> Original Collector: Magdalena Diamos</p></custodhist>
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Interview, Diamos de Grazia, Alexandra</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>April 15, 1956</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Tucson, AZ. Recorded by Magdalena Diamos... Continuation of Alexandra Diamos de Grazia interview about Mexican folktales and legends in Tucson... Interview in English... Songs include: El Tejano -- El Merino -- San Xavier… Transcript available in SWF 002, box 5, under Diamos.</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.129</unitid>
  		</did>
  		<custodhist><p> Original Collector: Magdalena Diamos</p></custodhist>
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Interview, Richards, A.L., Mrs. A.L. Richards, and Marciana Rejon</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>May, 1956 </unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Tucson, AZ. Recorded by Magdalena Diamos... Continuation of Mr. and Mrs. A.L. Richards interview about tales and legends from Sonora (Mexico) and Tucson... Marciana Rejon talks about tales and legends from Colima, Guaymas and Tucson... Interview complete in three parts... In Spanish... Transcript available in SWF 002, box 5, under Diamos.</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.130</unitid>
  		</did> 
  		<custodhist><p> Original Collector: Magdalena Diamos</p></custodhist>
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Interview, Rejon, Marciana and Norma Santa Ana</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>may, 1956</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Tucson, AZ. Recorded by Magdalena Diamos... Miss Marciana Rejon talks about tales and legends from Colina, Guaymas and Tucson, in Spanish... Interview complete in three parts... Miss Norma Santa Ana tells a story from Springer, New Mexico, in English...</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.131</unitid>
  		</did> 
  		<custodhist><p> Original Collector: Magdalena Diamos</p></custodhist>
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Interview, Rios, Margot and Julia Ortega</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>May, 1956</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, [33 1/3 rpm], 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Tucson, AZ. Recorded by Magdalena Diamos... Interview complete in tow parts... Margot Rios tells stories from Nogales and Sonora, in English... El en cuentro del Sr. Pimienta con El Diablo -- La Muchacha emtorujada -- Las Tres manos... Julia Ortega tells the Sonoran story, El Diablo de la montaña... Transcript available in SWF 002, box 5, under Diamos.</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.132</unitid>
  		</did>
  		<custodhist><p> Original Collector: Magdalena Diamos</p></custodhist>
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Interviews, Espinosa de Garcia, Mrs. Matilde</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>May, 1956</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, [33 1/3 rpm], 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Tucson, AZ. Recorded by Magdalena Diamos... Continuation of interview with Mrs. Matilde Espinosa de Garcia about Yaqui and Sonoran tales and legends... In Spanish... Interview complete in seven parts... Transcript available in SWF 002, box 5, under Diamos.</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.133</unitid>
  		</did>
  		<custodhist><p> Original Collector: Magdalena Diamos</p></custodhist>
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Interview, Espinosa de Garcia, Mrs. Matilde</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>May, 1956</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, [33 1/3 rpm], 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Tucson, AZ. Recorded by Magdalena Diamos... Continuation of interview with Mrs. Matilde Espinosa de Garcia about Yaqui and Sonoran tales and legends... In Spanish... Interview complete in seven parts... Transcript available in SWF 002, box 5, under Diamos.</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.134</unitid>
  		</did> 
  		<custodhist><p> Original Collector: Magdalena Diamos</p></custodhist>
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Narratives, Rosenthal, Mrs. Eva and Sr. Matilde Espinosa de Garcia</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>May, 1956</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Tucson, AZ. Recorded by Magdalena Diamos... The Black dog as devil -- El Tesoro de Indio (Mrs. Eva Rosenthal, Sonora) -- El Tesora de General (Mrs. Eva Rosenthal, Sonora) -- Girl from Douglas and poltergeist -- Crucifix in Magdalena -- Conclusion of interview with Sr. Matilde Espinosa de Garcia --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.136</unitid>
  		</did> 
  		<custodhist><p> Original Collector: Magdalena Diamos</p></custodhist>
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Valenzuela, Guadalupe Jose, Dave and Tony Yubeta, Donald Price, and Tila Escalada</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>May 14, 1960</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Nogalse, [AZ]. Recorded by KNOG, Nogales, for the University of Arizona Folklore Archive... Are you teasing me? (Tony and Dave Yubeta) -- A Pretty woman is a deadly weapon (Tony Yubeta) -- Old Nogales (Donald Price, age 17, learned form an old recording by Edw. Gardner) -- Guilty (Tila Escalada, age 17) -- Panchita (Guadalupe Jose Valenzuela) -- Rocillo (race horse song by Guadalupe Jose Valenzuela) -- El Corrido de dos hermanos (Ballad of two brothers by Dave and Tony Yubeta) --</abstract>
  			<origination label="collector">Doris Seibold</origination>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.137</unitid>
  		</did> 
  		<custodhist><p> Original Collector: Doris Seibold</p></custodhist>
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Price, Lillard and A.R. Whitfield</unittitle>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Tucson, AZ. Lillard Price is from Tubac, Arizona... A.R. Whitfield is from Nogales, Arizona... Guitar medley (Lillard Price) -- La Rumba (A.R. Whitfield... "who learned it in San Luis Potasi 65 years ago") -- A Little star shining for you (A.R. Whitfield) -- Ragtime clock (A.R. Whitfield... "learned from a musicial supplement to St. Louis Globe-Democrat about 65 years ago") -- Two sweethearts (Lillard Price) -- Little rosewood casket (Lillard Price) -- Strawberry roan (Lillard Price)</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.138</unitid>
  		</did> 
  		<custodhist><p> Original Collector: Doris Seibold</p></custodhist>
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Carrillo School Children</unittitle>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 10 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Tucson, AZ. Sung by Carrillo School children, solo voices: Angie Garcia and Vicki Canez... Toquen los pitos -- Carra Carmela -- Lullaby -- Nos despedimos contentos -- Noche de Pas -- Quien de las Posada -- Hermildes Regregrinos -- Operegrina graciada -- Abrid vuestras puertas -- Entre Regina --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.139 (10in.)</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Mariachi Jalisciense</unittitle>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 45 rpm, 7 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Palma Records. Bienvenida (Manuel Palma Parro) -- Josefina y Manuel -- La Tragedia de President Kennedy (Enrique Pino) -- Josefina Cuestas --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.140 (7in.)</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Hilton, L.M.and Paul Anderson</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>1946</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Ogden and Woods Cross, UT. Fife Mormon Recording. Hand cart song (L.M. Hilton, Ogden) -- Don't you marry the Mormon boys (Paul Anderson, Woods Cross) -- The Gospel news (L.M. Hilton, Ogden) --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.141</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Huntsman, Jetta, Mary H. Leavitt, L.M. Hilton and Myron Crandall</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>1946</unitdate>
  			<unitdate>1947</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog,</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Ogden and St. George, UT., Fife Mormon Recording. In the midst of these awful Mormons (Jetta Huntsman, St. George) -- None can preach the gospel like the Mormons (Mary H. Leavitt, St. George) -- Echo Canyon (L.M. Hilton, Ogden) -- Painting clouds of sunshine (composed and sung by Myron Crandall, Ogden) --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.142</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections,Kinmann, Matt</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>February 15, 1948</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Old Fiddler's Contest, Tucson, AZ. Recorded by Charles Wiley... Breakdowns: Turkey in the straw -- Durand's hornpipe -- Saturday night waltz --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.143</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Ray, Mrs. John A.</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>May, 1948</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Tucson, AZ. Mrs. John A. Ray from Mesa, Arizona... Little black like me ("Are there any angels black like me?") -- The Grasshopper song -- There was a queer little man --</abstract>
  			<origination label="collector">Frances Gillmor</origination>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.144</unitid>
  		</did> 
  		<custodhist><p> Original Collector: Frances Gillmor</p></custodhist>
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections,Ray, Mrs. John A. and Mrs. Lurlene Ray Russell</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>May, 1948</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Tucson, AZ. Performances from Mesa, Arizona... Jack Frost (Mrs. John A. Ray) -- The Little cherry tree (Mrs. John A. Ray) -- Rover (Mrs. Lurlene Ray Russell) -- Robin redbreast (Mrs. Lurlene Ray Russell) -- Songs of the five senses (Mrs. John A. Ray) --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.145</unitid>
  		</did>
  		<custodhist><p> Original Collector: Frances Gillmor</p></custodhist>
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Songs of Lebanon, Syria and Jordan, Bulos, Afif</unittitle>
  			<unitdate label="copyright">1961</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>New York, N.Y. Folkways Records, Ar-rozana (The Rozana) -- Hayyin Darb-is-seif (The Fall of the sword is easier) -- Yamil'abaya (Maiden beautiful) -- Lamman bada yatathana (When my love languished) -- Al-loma (Instrumental) -- Tafti Hindi (Indian Taffeta) -- Mash'al -- Ala Dal'ona (The Spoilt one) -- 'Al Yadi (The Valley) -- Ali-'snayyin -- Ya Ghzayyel (O Gazelle) -- Bint-esh-shalibiyya (The Pretty one) --</abstract>
 			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.146</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>American music - folk: Records from the collection of Harry Smith, Ballads, no. 1-2</unittitle>
  			<unitdate label="copyright">1952</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>New York, N.Y., Folkways Records. Henry Lee (Dick Justice) -- Fatal flower garden (Nelstone's Hawaiians) -- The House carpenter (Clarance Ashley) -- Drunkard's special (Coley Jones) -- Old lady and the devil (Bill and Belle) -- The Butcher boy (Buell Kazee) -- The Wagoners end (Buell Kazell) -- King Kong kitchie kitchie ki-me-o ("Chubby" Parker) -- Old shoes and leggins (Uncle Eck Dunford) -- Willie Moore (Burnett and Rutherford) -- A Lazy farmer boy (Buster Carter and Preston Young) -- Peg and awl (Carolina Tar Heels) -- Ommie Wise (G.B. Grayson) -- My name is John Johanna (Kelly Harrell) --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.148</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>American music - folk: Records from the collection of Harry Smith, Ballads, no. 3-4</unittitle>
  			<unitdate label="copyright">1952</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>New York, N.Y., Folkways Records. Bandit colt younger (Edward L. Crain) -- Charles Giteau (Kelly Harrell) -- John Hardy was a desperate little man (The Carter family) -- Gonna die with my hammer in my hand (Williamson Brothers and Cuny) -- Stackalee (Frank Hutchison) -- White Horse blues ( Charlie Poole with the North Carolina Ramblers) -- Frankie (Mississippi John Hurt) -- When that great ship went down (William and Varsey Smith) -- Engine One-Forty-Three (The Carter family) -- Kassie Jones, two parts (Furry Lewis) -- Mississippi Boweavil blues (The Mashed Marvel) -- Got the farm land blues (The Carolina Tar Heels) --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.149</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>American music - folk: Records from the collection of Harry Smith, Dances, no. 1</unittitle>
  			<unitdate label="copyright">1952</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>New York, N.Y., Folkways Records. Sail away lady (Uncle Bunt Stephens) -- The Wild wagoner (J.W. Day) -- Wake up Jacob (Prince Albert Hunt's Texas Ramblers) -- La Danseuse - Fox trot (De'ma Lachney and Blind Uncle Gaspard) -- Georgia stomp (Andrew and Jim Baxter) -- Brilliancy medley (Eck Robertson and family) -- Indian war whoop (Floyd Ming and his Pep-steppers) -- Old country stomp (Henry Thomas) -- Old dog Blue (Jim Jackson) -- Saut Crapaud - Fox trot (Columbus Freeze) -- Arcadian one step (Joseph Falcon) -- Home sweet home (Breaux Freres) -- Newport blues (Cincinnati Jug Band) -- Moonshiner's dance, part 1 (Frank Cloutier and Victoria Cale Orchestra) --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.150</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>American music - folk: Records from the collection of Harry Smith, Religious, no. 1-2</unittitle>
  			<unitdate label="copyright">1952</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>New York, N.Y., Folkways Records. Must be born again (Rev. J.M. Gates) -- Oh death where is they sting (Rev. R.M. Gates) -- Rocky road (Alabama Sacred Harp Singers) -- Present joys (Alabama Sacred Harp Singers) -- This song of love (Middle Georgia Singing Convention) -- Judgement (Rev. Sister Mary Nelson) -- He got better things for you (Memphis Sanctified Singers) -- Since I laid my burden down (Elders McIntorsch &amp; Edwards) -- John the Baptist (Rev. Moses Mason) -- Dry bones (Bascom Lamar Lunsford) -- John the Revelator (Blind Willie Johnson) -- Little Moses (The Carter family) -- Shine on me (Ernst Phipps and his Holiness Singers) -- Fifty miles of elbow room (Rev. F.W. McGee) -- I'm in the battle field for my Lord (Rev. D.C. Rice and his Sanctified Congregation) --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.151</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>American music - folk: Records from the collection of Harry Smith, Songs, no. 1-2</unittitle>
  			<unitdate label="copyright">1952</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>New York, N.Y., Folkways Records. The coo coo bird (Clarence Ashley) -- East Virginia (Buell Kazee) -- Minglewood blues (Cannons Jug Stompers) -- I woke up one morning (Didier Herbert) -- James Alley blues (Richard "Rabbit" Brown) -- Sugar baby ("Dock" Boggs) -- I wish I was a mole in the ground (Bascom Lamar Lunsford) -- The Mountaineer's courtship (Mr. and Mrs. Ernest V. Stoneman) -- The Spainish merchant's daughter (Stoneman family) -- Bob Lee Junior blues (Memphis Jug Band) -- Single girl, married girl (Carter family) -- Le Vieux soulard et sa femme (Clemo Breaux &amp; Joseph Falcon) -- Expressman blues (John Estes) --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.152</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Behind these walls, Ferguson, Hank</unittitle>
  			<unitdate label="copyright">1962</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Huntington, VT., Folk Legacy Records, Inc. I'm not living (Ferguson) -- The Walls -- Get a little dirt on your hands -- One life's as long as any man can live (Ferguson) -- Shackles and chains -- Thunder Road -- Trouble just got in my way (Ferguson) -- Busted -- You ain't heard nothing yet -- Waiting for the train -- The Wreck of Old # 9 -- Jolly time farmer -- Rich girl, poor girl -- The Wreck of Old 97 -- Wabash Cannonball -- Nine pound hammer -- Long black veil -- Interstate 40 --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.154</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Anglo-American folk songs, Nye, Hermes</unittitle>
  			<unitdate label="copyright">1952</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>New York City, N.Y., Folkways Records and Service Corp. Sung by Hermes Nye with guitar... Tomorrow is St. Valentine's Day -- A North country maid -- King Arthur had three sons -- Earl Richard -- Greenland fishery -- Earl of Murray -- John Peer -- The Mermaid (Landlubber) -- The Red herring -- The Bailiff's daughter --</abstract>
  			<origination label="collector"></origination>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.155</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>The Folksongs of Britain: Volume One, Songs of Courtship</unittitle>
  			<unitdate label="copyright">1961</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Lochrae Music Corporation. Peter Kennedy and Alan Lomax, editors... Green grow the laurels -- The False bride -- Our wedding day -- When a man's in love -- Ailein Duinn -- Bonnie Kate -- Old grey beard newly shaven -- Sweet primeroses -- The Coolin -- Shule aroon -- The Mountain streams -- The Brown thorn -- As I roved out -- The Magpie's nest -- Dame Durden -- Casadh an Tsugain -- Twisting the hay-rope -- My darling ploughman boy -- The False young man -- I'm a young bonnie lassie -- No, John, no -- Abhainn na sead -- Bogie's bonnie belle --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.156</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>The Folksongs of Britain: Volume Two, Songs of seduction</unittitle>
  			<unitdate label="copyright">1961</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>New York City, N.Y., Caedmon Records, Inc. Peter Kennedy and Alan Lomax, editors... As I walked through Dublin City -- The Light Drag'on -- The Orkney style of courtship -- The Cuckoo's nest -- The Soldier and the lady -- Molly, put the kettle on -- Never wed an old man -- The maid of Australia -- The Merchant's son and the beggar's daughter -- The Bold English Navy -- Cruising round Yarmouth -- The Nutting girl --The Bonnie wee lassie girl who never said no -- Bundle and go -- Blow the candle out -- The Foggy dew -- Toorna-ma-goon -- Rolling in the ryegrass -- The Jolly tinker -- The Long peggin'awl -- The Thrashing machine -- Up to the rigs of London town -- The Wind blew the bonnie lassie's plaidie awa -- The Cunning cobbler --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.157</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>The Folk songs of Britain: Volume 3, Jack of all trades</unittitle>
  			<unitdate label="copyright">1961</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Lochrae Music Corporation. Peter Kennedy and Alan Lomax, editors ... The Jovial tradesmen -- The Roving journeymen -- The Candlelight fisherman -- The Canny shepherd laddie -- The Dairy maid -- Green brooms -- Gruel -- The Jug of punch -- The Gresford disaster -- The Jolly miller -- The Irish washerwoman -- Farewell to whiskey -- The Roving ploughboy -- The Buchan miller -- Fagan the cobbler -- The Ould piper -- Sweep, chimney sweep -- The Mason's apron -- Rhynie -- The Tailor by trade -- The Wee weaver -- Jim the Carter lad -- Drumdelgie -- The Merry haymakers -- I'll mend your pots and kettles --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.158</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>The Folksongs of Britain: Volume 4, The Child ballads</unittitle>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>New York City, N.Y. Caedmon Records Inc. Captain Wedderman's courtship -- The Twa brothers -- Lord Bateman -- Lord Thomas and Fair Allen -- Lord Lovell -- Lord Gregory -- Barbara Allen -- George Collins -- Cruel Lincoln -- The Prickelly bush -- The Elfin knight (An Acre of land) -- The Elfin knight (Strawberry Lane) -- The False knight on the road -- Lady Isabel and the elf knight -- The Twa sisters -- Lord Randall -- Edward -- King Orfeo -- The Cruel mother -- The Broomfield wager --</abstract>
  			<origination label="collector">Peter Kennedy and Alan Lomax</origination>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.159</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>The Folksongs of Britain: Volume 5, The Child ballads</unittitle>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>New York City, N.Y., Caedmon Records Inc. The Royal forester -- The Baffled knight -- Johnie Cock -- Robin Hood and Little John -- The Jew's garden -- The Battle of Harlaw -- The Four Maries -- The Gypsy laddie -- Georgie -- The Dowie Dens of Yarrow -- Glenlogie -- The Grey cock -- Henry Martin -- Lang Johnny More -- Willie's fate -- Our goodman -- The Farmer's curst wife -- The Jolly beggar -- The Auld beggarman -- The Keach in the creel -- The Golden vanity - The Trooper lad </abstract>
  			<origination label="collector">Peter Kennedy and Alan Lomax</origination>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.160</unitid>
  		</did>
  		<custodhist><p> Original Collector: Peter Kennedy and Alan Lomax</p></custodhist>
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Broadside ballads - London: 1600-1700, MacColl, Ewan</unittitle>
  			<unitdate label="copyright">1962</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>New York City, N.Y., Folkways Records &amp; Service Corp. Sung by Ewan MacColl... Accompaniments by: Peggy Seeger, guitar, banjo and autoharp; Alf Edwards, English concertina, ocarina and tabor; Alfie Kahn, piccolo, flute and tin whistle... Room for company (piccolo and tabor) -- Pity's lamentation (guitar and flute) -- There's nothing to be had without money (concertina, flute and guitar) -- The Midwife's ghost (autoharp) -- A Merry progress to London (unaccompanied) --London's lottery (guitar and flute) -- London mourning in ashes (concertina) -- King Lear and his three daughters (flute, concertina and guitar) --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.161</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Blues with Brownie McGhee and guitar. McGhee, Brownie</unittitle>
  			<unitdate label="copyright">1955</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 10 in. </physdesc>
  			<abstract>New York City, N.Y., Folkways Records and Service Corp. Recorded by Moses Asch... Careless love -- Good morning blues -- Sporting life -- Me and Sonny -- Pawnshop blues -- Move Kansas City -- Betty and Dupree --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.162 (10in.)</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Lord Invader and the Trinidad Caribbean Orchestra, Calypso, with Lord Invader and the Trinidad Caribbean Orchestra</unittitle>
  			<unitdate label="copyright">1955</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 10 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>New York City, N.Y., Folkways Records and Service Corp. Barrack-room scandal -- Reincarnation -- Brooklyn, Brooklyn! -- Barbados -- Brown skin girl -- 29, Port of Spain -- Labor Day -- Jonah --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.163 (10in.)</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Christmas with Mahalia Jackson, Jackson, Mahalia</unittitle>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>New York City, N.Y., Edgewood Corp. Silent night - Holy night (3:00) -- Walking to Jerusalem (3:04) -- Go tell it on the mountain (3:06) -- I can put my trust in Jesus (3:13) -- God spoke to me (2:50) -- His eye in on the sparrow (3:25) -- The Lord's prayer (3:00) -- Come to Jesus (3:18) -- He's my light (2:55) -- City called Heaven (3:20) -- Bless this house (3:13) --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.164</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>La Fleche d'or d'Haiti</unittitle>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Haiti. Vocals by A. Dorismond and G. French... Rythmn: Cadence Rampa... Ti tata -- Belle martiniquaise -- Nanotte cherie --  Carnaval -- Retour de la cadence -- Crainte d'amour -- Ti cameau -- Pa triche -- Lucienne -- Toujours plus femme -- A l'amour -- En passant a Porto-Rico --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.165</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Dust bowl ballads, Guthrie, Woody</unittitle>
  			<unitdate label="copyright">1964</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>New York, N.Y., Folkways Records &amp; Service Corp. All music and text written and performed by Woody Guthrie... Talkin' dust bowl blues -- Blowin' down this road  -- Do re mi -- Dust cain't kill me -- Tom Joad, I -- Tom Joad, II -- The Great dust storm -- Dusty old dust -- Dust bowl refugee -- Dust pneumonia blues -- I ain't got no home in this world no more -- Vigilante men -- </abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.166</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>The English and Scottish popular ballads, Vol. 3, MacColl, Ewan and A.L. Lloyd</unittitle>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, [33 1/3 rpm], 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>New York, N.Y., Bill Grauer Productions. The Battle of Harlaw -- The Dover sailor -- Among the blue flowers and the yellow -- The Golden vanity -- The Douglas tragedy -- The Dowie Dens of Yarrow -- Robin Hood and the Bishop of Hereford -- The Gaindner child -- Gil Morice -- </abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.167</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>The English and Scottish popular ballads, Vol. 3, MacColl, Ewan and A.L. Lloyd</unittitle>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, [33 1/3 rpm], 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>New York, N.Y., Bill Grauer Productions. The Crafty farmer -- Gipsies-o -- Lang Johnnie More -- Long lankin -- The Beggar laddie -- Rob Roy -- The Cherry tree -- The Heir o'Lynne -- Hughie Graeme --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.168</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>The English and Scottish popular ballads, Vol. 4, MacColl, Ewan and A.L. Lloyd</unittitle>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, [33 1/3 rpm], 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>New York, N.Y., Bill Grauer Productions. Jock the leg -- The Daemon lover -- The Earl of Aboyne -- Scarborough fair -- Lord Gregory -- The Bonnie Earl O'Murray -- Henry Martin -- Clyde's water -- The Lover's ghost --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.169</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>The English and Scottish popular ballads, Vol. 4, MacColl, Ewan and A.L. Lloyd</unittitle>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, [33 1/3 rpm], 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>New York, N.Y., Bill Grauer Productions. The Burning o'Auchendoun -- The Banks of Green Willow  -- Bessie Bell and Mary Gray -- Bold Sir Rylas -- Captain Wedderburn's courtship -- Captain Ward and the rainbow -- Dives and Lazarus -- The Cruel mother -- Lord Thomas and fair Eleanor --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.170</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>The English and Scottish popular ballads: The Child ballads, Vol. 6, MacColl, Ewan and A.L. Lloyd</unittitle>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, [33 1/3 rpm], 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>New York, N.Y., Bill Grauer Productions. The Crafty farmer -- Gipsies-o -- Lang Johnnie More -- Long lankin -- The Beggar laddie -- Rob Roy -- The Cherry tree -- The Heir o'Lynne -- Hughie Graeme --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.171</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>The English and Scottish popular ballads: The Child ballads, Vol. 7, MacColl, Ewan and A.L. Lloyd</unittitle>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, [33 1/3 rpm], 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>New York, N.Y., Bill Grauer Productions. Jock the leg -- The Daemon lover -- The Earl of Aboyne -- Scarborough fair -- Lord Gregory -- The Bonnie Earl O'Murray -- Henry Martin -- Clyde's water -- The Lover's ghost --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.172</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>The Cowboy: His songs, ballads &amp; brag talk</unittitle>
  			<unitdate label="copyright">1959</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>New York, N.Y., Folkways Records &amp; Services Corp. Edited by Kenneth S. Goldstein... Morning grub holler  -- The Round-up cook -- The Dally roper's song -- I ride an old paint -- Some cowboy brag talk -- Little Joe the wrangler -- Utah Carroll -- Old iron pants Pete -- The Saddle bum -- Strawberry roan -- I ain't got no use for the women -- Blood on the saddle -- The Ridge running roan -- Roll on, little dogies -- The Hangman's song -- </abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.173</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>The cowboy: His songs, ballads &amp; brag talk, Jackson, Harry</unittitle>
  			<unitdate label="copyright">1959</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>New York, N.Y., Folkways Records &amp; Services Corp. Edited by Kenneth S. Goldstein... Boastin' cowboy -- Tying a knot in the devil's tale -- Clayton Boone -- Old Blue was a gray horse -- Little Joe the wrangler's sister Nell -- The Gal I left behind -- Zebra dun -- When the work's all done this fall -- The Pot wrassler -- Streets of Laredo -- Windy Bill -- Cowboy talking to a bucking horse -- As I went wallking one morning for pleasure -- Cowboy Jack -- Jack of diamonds -- I'm gonna leave old Texas now --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.174</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Favorite gospel songs, West, Harry and Jeanie West</unittitle>
  			<unitdate label="copyright">1957</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>New York, N.Y., Folkways Records and Service Corp. Recorded by Kenneth S. Goldstein...When our Lord shall come again -- Matthew twenty-four -- What are they doing in heaven today -- Sweet bye and bye -- Walking my Lord up Calvary's hill -- He'll set your fields on fire -- Campin' in Canaan's land -- The Man of Galilee -- Oh, hide you in the blood -- Amazing grace -- Preach the gospel -- Only one step more -- Thirty pieces of silver -- The Sea of life -- I'm gonna let it shine -- I'm only on a journey here -- </abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.175</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Folk music of Haiti</unittitle>
  			<unitdate label="copyright">1951</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>New York, N.Y., Folkways Records and Services Corp. Recorded in Haiti by Harold Courlander... Pile pied'm (Morgina Lavache) -- M'pas bwa m'pas mange (Libera Borderau and Ti Yogan) -- Ogoun Balindjo (La France Belvue) -- Ezilie Wedo (La France Belvue) -- La Famille li fai ca (Lina Hibbert) -- Moundongue oh ye ye ye (La France Belvue) -- Ramis loin loin (D:merv:1 servers) -- Ou pas we m'innocent (Aleanne Francois) -- Mainin'm alle (Ti Yogan and Morgina Lavache) -- Cote yo, cote yo (Libera Borderau) -- Crapeau Tingele (Libera Borderau) -- Balance ya ya (Edgar Dersoler) -- Trois fe (Christophe Oxilas) -- Spirit conversation (Cult priest at Leogane) -- General Brise (La France Belvue) -- Mayousse -- Paulette (Sigbrien Bellis and Veneise Maclise) --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.176</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Folk music of Kashmir</unittitle>
  			<unitdate label="copyright">1962</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>New York, N.Y., Folkways Records. Recordings and notes by E. Bhavnian... Santur -- Title music -- Title music -- Love and the beauty of nature -- Instrumental -- Song of the boatmen -- Love duet -- Song of the nightingale -- Instrumental -- Romantic music -- Song of the silk worm -- Beautiful Kashmir -- Song of spring -- </abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.177</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Songs of the Michigan lumberjacks</unittitle>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Library of Congress Division of Music Recording Laboratory. Archive of American Folk Song. Edited by E.C. Beck... Once more a-lumbering go -- Michigan I-O -- The Jam on Gerry's rocks, I -- The Jam on Gerry's rocks, II -- Jack Haggerty -- The Little brown bulls -- Lumberjack's alphabet -- The Falling of the pine -- The Wild Mustard River -- Turner's camp on the Chippewa -- Johnny Carroll's camp --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.178</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Songs of the Papago</unittitle>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Library of Congress Division of Music Recording Laboratory. Archive of American Folk Song. Recorded by Frances Densmore... Copied from cylinders recorded in 1920 from the Smithsonian - Densmore Collection from the Archive of American Folk Songs.. Songs connected with legends: Song of earth magician when disappearing in the ground -- Song of brown buzzard after killing elder brother -- Song before emerging from ashes hill -- Song to put eagle to sleep -- Song of the old women who attended elder brother -- Four fires on the ground -- The girls are approaching -- Song to make the boy invisible -- Songs connected with ceremonies: The Dwelling place of the sun -- Each singer wears a white feather -- Song of the watchers -- Song during rain divination -- A Blue wind -- Song connected with expeditions to obtain salt: The Wind blows from the sea -- Songs connected with treatment of the sick: Sandy loam fields -- Out of the mountains -- Song to a little yellow wasp -- Song of the dawn -- Dream songs: White Mountain birds were singing -- A Black crow -- War songs: Song concerning a wounded Apache -- The Little captive children -- The Eagle is talking -- Song of the kicking-ball race: We must run -- Miscellaneous: I met a Mexican --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.179</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Folksongs of courting and complaint, Seeger, Peggy and Clark Weissman</unittitle>
  			<unitdate label="copyright">1955</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>New York, N.Y., Folkways Records and Service Corp. Sung by Peggy Seeger, with 5-string banjo... Clark Weissman, guitar... Whistle, daughter, whistle -- When I was single -- The House carpenter -- When first unto this country a stranger I came -- All of her answers to me were no -- Young man who wouldn't hoe corn -- The Wagoners lad -- Long lonesome road -- The Butcher's boy -- The Old maid's song -- Katy cruel -- Leatherwing bat --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.180</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Mexican folk songs, Cruz, Alfonso</unittitle>
  			<unitdate label="copyright">1958</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>New York, N.Y., Folkways Records and Service Corp. Recorded in Oaxaca, Mexico... El Yerbero (The Herb-seller) -- Babalu -- Rojociano el Guapangero (The Guasteca is in mourning) -- Echame a mi la culpa (Put the blame on me) -- La Falta un clavo a mi cruz (There is a nail missing in my cross) -- Deja que salza la luna (Let the moon rise) -- La Tortolita -- Ya tu veras (You will see) -- Carinito azucarado (Little sweetheart) -- Mere cumbe (Last night I dreamed of you) -- Tehuanyepec -- La Zandunja -- Cucucurucucu, paloma (Little dove) -- La Molienda y la culebra (The cane harvest and the snake) -- Cachito --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.181</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Folk songs of the Colorado River, Lee, Katie</unittitle>
  			<unitdate label="copyright">1964</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>New York, N.Y., Folkways Records and Service Corp. Muddy River -- The Canyoners -- Drinking song -- Kavitatin' Katie -- Song of the boatmen -- Tale of the Tickaboo -- Pore Colly Raddy -- Rapids ahead -- River lullaby -- The Ghosts of the old San Juan -- Two little flies -- When the Colorado rises -- The Hippopotami -- Through this world -- </abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.182</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Williams, Willie</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>1934</unitdate>
  			<unitdate>1936</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 10 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>The Library of Congress Division of Music Recording Laboratory. Archive of American Folk Song. Issued for the Friends in Music in the Library of Congress ... Sung by Willie Williams at the State Penitentiary, Richmond, VA., May, 1936, and recorded by John A. Lomax: O Lord, don' 'low me to beat 'em -- Sung by a group of Negro convicts at Cummins State Prison Farm, Gould, Ark., October, 1934, and recorded by John A. Lomax: It makes a long time man feel bad --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.183 (10in.)</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, May, Basil and Pete Steele</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>1937</unitdate>
  			<unitdate>1938</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 10 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>The Library of Congress Division of Music Recording Laboratory. Archive of American Folk Song. Issued for the Friends in Music in the Library of Congress ... Recorded by Alan Lomax at Salyersville, KY., 1937: Lady of Carlisle (sung by Basil May, with guitar) -- Recorded by Alan Lomax at Hamilton, Ohio, 1938: Pretty Polly (sung by Pete Steele with 5-string banjo) --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.184 (10in.)</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Cora</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>1944</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>The Library of Congress Division of Music Recording Laboratory. Archive of American Folk Song. Recorded at Jesus Maria, Nayarit, Mexico, 1944, by Henrietta Yurchenco... Son del elote -- Son del vanado -- Son de la siembra (sung with mitote by E. Altamirano) -- Son de cuaresma (played on reed flute by M. Cabrales) -- Son de semana Santa (palyed on reed flute and drum by C. Silverio and M. Daniel) </abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.185</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01><c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Yaqui/Seri</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>1944</unitdate>
  			<unitdate>1946</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>The Library of Congress Division of Music Recording Laboratory. Archive of American Folk Song. Recorded at Vicam, Sonora, Mexico, 1946, by Henrietta Yurchenco... Sung with accompaniment of notched sticks and water drum by L. Tapia and assistants: Baile del vanado - el tecolate -- Baile del vanado - el palo verde -- Recorded at Desemboque, Sonora, Mexico, 1944, by Henrietta Yurchenco: Cancion del marinero cansado (sung by Antonio Burgos) -- Cancion de dios (sung by Sara Villalobos) -- Cancion del curandero (sung by Jesus Ibarra) --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.186</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Tarahumara</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>1946</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 10 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>The Library of Congress Division of Music Recording Laboratory. Archive of American Folk Song. Recorded at Guachochic, Chihuahua, Mexico, 1946, by Henrietta Yurchenco... Yumari (sung with accompaniment of rattle by P. Cruz) -- Dutuburi -- Yumari (sung with accompaniment of rattle by H. Ramos) -- </abstract>
  			<unitid>Pre-1980-1/D.187 (10in.)</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Huichol</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>1944</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 10 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>The Library of Congress Division of Music Recording Laboratory. Archive of American Folk Song. Recorded at Huilotita, Jalisco, Mexico, 1944, by Henrietta Yurchenco... Fiesta del peyote (sung by J. de la Cruz and dancers) -- Fiesta de la Calabaza (sung with huehuetl by J. de la Cruz and assistants) -- Fiesta de los enfermos (sung by P. Gonzales and assistants) --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.188 (10in.)</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Tzotzil and Tzeltal</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>1945</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>The Library of Congress Division of Music Recording Laboratory. Archive of American Folk Song. Recorded in the state of Chiapas, Mexico, 1945, by Henrietta Yurchenco... Son de San Juan (played on trumpet, reed flute, and drum by M. Pachitan and A. Perez) -- Son de Fiesta (played on trumpet, reed flute, and drum by S. Geron, A. Guzman, and M. Sandis) -- Son de carnaval -- Anucio de caverus de caballos (played on reed flute and drum by A. Arias and M. Lopez) -- Son de semana Santa (played on reed flute by M. de La Torre) -- </abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.189</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Gladden, Mrs. Texas and Horton Barker</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>1939</unitdate>
  			<unitdate>1941</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 10 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>The Library of Congress Division of Music Recording Laboratory. Archive of American Folk Song. Sung by Mrs. Texas Gladden of Salem, Va., 1941, and recorded by Alan and Elizabeth Lomax: The House carpenter -- Sung by Horton Barker at Chilhowie, Va., 1939, and recorded by Herbert Halput: The Farmer's curst wife --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.190 (10in.)</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections,Ball, E.C. and Mrs. Pearl Borusky</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>1941</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 10 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>The Library of Congress Division of Music Recording Laboratory. Archive of American Folk Song. Sung with guitar by E.C. Ball at Rugby, Va., 1941, and recorded by Alan and Elizabeth Lomax: Pretty Polly -- Sung by Mrs. Pearl Borusky of Antigo, Wis., 1941, and recorded by Charles Draves: The Rich old farmer --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.191 (10in.)</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Gladden, Mrs. Texas</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>1941</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 10 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>The Library of Congress Division of Music Recording Laboratory. Archive of American Folk Song. Sung by Mrs. Texas Gladden of Salem, Va., 1941, and recorded by Alan and Elizabeth Lomax: The Devil's nine questions -- Old Kimball -- One morning in May --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.192 (10in.)</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, DeNoyer, Emery and Alex Moore</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>1940</unitdate>
  			<unitdate>1941</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 10 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>The Library of Congress Division of Music Recording Laboratory. Archive of American Folk Song. Sung by Emery DeNoyer of Rhinelander, Wisconsin, 1941, and recorded by Charles Draves: The Little brown bulls -- Sung by Alex Moore of Austin, Texas, 1940, and recorded by John A. and Bess Lomax: The Sioux Indians --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.193 (10in.)</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections,Terry, Sanders</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>1938</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 10 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>The Library of Congress Division of Music Recording Laboratory. Archive of American Folk Song. Played on the harmonica by Sanders Terry of Durham, N.C., and recorded in New York, N.Y., 1938, by Alan and Bess Lomax: Lost John -- Fox chase --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.194(10in.)</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Steele, Pete and J.M. (Sailor Dad) Hunt</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>1938</unitdate>
  			<unitdate certainty="approximate">1941</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 10 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>The Library of Congress Division of Music Recording Laboratory. Archive of American Folk Song. Sung with 5-string banjo by Pete Steele at Hamilton, Ohio, 1938, and recorded by Alan and Elizabeth Lomax: Pay day at Coal Creek -- Sung by J.M.(Sailor Dad) Hunt of Marian, Va., and recorded in Washington, D.C., 1941, by Alan Lomax --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.195 (10in.)</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Jackson, Aunt Molly</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>1939</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 10 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>The Library of Congress Division of Music Recording Laboratory. Archive of American Folk Song. Recorded in New York, N.Y., 1939, by Alan Lomax, and sung by Aunt Molly Jackson of Clay County, Ky.: The Little dove -- Ten thousand miles --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.196 (10in.)</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Pike, Mr. Russ and Mrs. E.C. Bell, Henry King and family and Thaddeus C. Willingham</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>1941</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 10 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>The Library of Congress Division of Music Recording Laboratory. Archive of American Folk Song. Recorded by Charles Todd and Robert Sankin, and sung by Russ Pike at Visalia, Calif., 1941: Soldier, won't you marry me -- Recorded by Alan and Elizabeth Lomax, and sung by Mr. and Mrs. E.C. Bell at Rugby, Va., 1941: Jennie Jenkins --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.197 (10in.)</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Strong, Luther and W.E. Claunch</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>1937</unitdate>
  			<unitdate>1939</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>The Library of Congress Division of Music Recording Laboratory. Archive of American Folk Song. Recorded by Alan and Elizabeth Lomax and [performed] by Luther Strong at Dalesburg, Ky., 1937: The Last of Callahan -- The Ways of the world -- Glory in the meeting house -- Recorded by Herbert Halpert and [performed] by W.E. Claunch at Guntown, Miss., 1939: Grub Springs -- The Eighth of January -- Sally Gooding --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.198</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Casey, Smith and "Little Brother"</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>1934</unitdate>
  			<unitdate>1939</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>The Library of Congress Division of Music Recording Laboratory. Archive of American Folk Song. Recorded by John A. and Ruby T. Lomax, and sung by Smith Casey at Clemens State Farm, Brazoria, Texas, 1939: Two white horses -- Country rag -- Shorty George -- Recorded by John A, Ruby T. and Alan Lomax, and sung by "Little Brother" at Texas State Penitentiary, Huntsville, Tex., 1934: Blues -- </abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.199</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Reed, Dock, Henry Reed, Vera Hall and Willie Williams</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>1936</unitdate>
  			<unitdate>1937</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>The Library of Congress Division of Music Recording Laboratory. Archive of American Folk Song. Recorded by John A. and Ruby T. Lomax, and Ruby Pickens Tartt and sung by Dock and Henry Reed and Vera Hall at Livingston, Ala., 1937: Trouble so hard -- Choose your seat and set down  -- Handwriting on the wall -- Recorded by John A. Lomax and sung by Willie Williams and group at State Penitentiary, Richmond, Va., 1936: The New buryin' ground -- </abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.200</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Dennis, Wash, Charley Simms, Jimmie Strothers, Joe Brown, Washington Brown and Austin Coleman</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>1934</unitdate>
  			<unitdate>1936</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>The Library of Congress Division of Music Recording Laboratory. Archive of American Folk Song. Recorded by John A. Lomax and sung by Wash Dennis and Charley Simms at Parchman, Miss., 1936: Lead me to the rock -- Sung by Jimmie Strothers at State Farm, Va., 1936; The Blood stained banders -- Recorded by John A. and Alan Lomax and sung by Joe and Washington Brown at Jennings, La., 1934: Run old Jeremiah --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.201</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Williams, Ernest, Clyde Hill, "Lightning" and Kelly Pace</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>1933</unitdate>
  			<unitdate>1934</unitdate>
  			<unitdate>1939</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>The Library of Congress Division of Music Recording Laboratory. Archive of American Folk Song. Recorded by John A. and Ruby T. Lomax and sung by Ernest Williams and group at Central State Farm, Sugarland, Tex., 1933: Ain't no more cane on this Grazos -- Sung by Clyde Hill and group at Clemens State Farm, Brazoria, Tex., 1939: Long hot summer days -- Recorded by John A. and Alan Lomax and sung by "Lightning" and group at Darrington State Farm, Sandy Point, Tex., 1934: Long John -- Recorded by John A. Lomax and sung by Kelly Pace and group at Cumins State Farm, Gould, Ark., 1934: Jumpin' Judy --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.202</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Baker, James (Iron Head) and Arthur Bell</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>1934</unitdate>
  			<unitdate>1939</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 10 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>The Library of Congress Division of Music Recording Laboratory. Archive of American Folk Song. Recorded by John A. and Alan Lomax and sung by James (Iron Head) Baker and group at Central State Farm, Sugarland, Tex., 1934: The Grey goose -- Recorded by John A. and Ruby T. Lomax and sung by Arthur Bell at Cumins State Farm, Gould, Ark., 1939: John Henry -- </abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.203 (10in.)</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Webb, Jeff, Frank Jordan and Allen Prothero</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>1933</unitdate>
  			<unitdate>1934</unitdate>
  			<unitdate>1936</unitdate>
  			<unitdate>1937</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 10 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>The Library of Congress Division of Music Recording Laboratory. Archive of American Folk Song. Recorded by John A. Lomax and sung by Jeff Webb and group at State Penitentiary, Parchman, Miss., 1937: Rosie -- Sung by Frank Jordan and group at Penitentiary, Parchman, Miss., 1936: I'm going to Leland -- Recorded by John A. and Alan Lomax and sung by Allen Prothero at State Penitentiary, Nashville, Tenn., 1933: Jumpin' Judy -- Sung by group at State Reid Farm, Boykin, S.C., 1934: Look down that long lonesome road --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.204 (10in.)</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Henry, Jim, Charlie Butler, Irwin Lowery and Vera Hall</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>1931</unitdate>
  			<unitdate>1939</unitdate>
  			<unitdate>1940</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 10 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>The Library of Congress Division of Music Recording Laboratory. Archive of American Folk Song. Recorded by John A. Lomax and sung by Jim Henry at Parchment, Miss., 1937: I don't mind the weather -- Sung by Charlie Butler at Parchman, Miss., 1937: Diamond Joe -- Sung by Irwin Lowery at Gould, Ark., 1939: Joe the grinder -- Recorded by John A. and Ruby T. Lomax and Ruby Pickens Tartt and sung by Vera Hall at Livingston, Ala., 1940: Another man done gone -- Boll weevil blues --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.205 (10in.)</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Morganfield, McKinley</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>1941</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 10 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>The Library of Congress Division of Music Recording Laboratory. Archive of American Folk Song. Recorded by Alan Lomax and John Work and sung with guitar by McKinley Morganfield at Stovall, Miss., 1941: Country blues -- Be's troubled --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.206 (10in.)</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Godfrey, H., O.D. Graham, K. Shipp, C. Shipp, H. McClintock, Joe McDonald, Mrs. Jos. McDonald and Moses Platt</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>1933</unitdate>
  			<unitdate>1934</unitdate>
  			<unitdate>1939</unitdate>
  			<unitdate>1940</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>The Library of Congress Division of Music Recording Laboratory. Archive of American Folk Song. Recorded by John A. and Ruby T. Lomax and Herbert Halpert and [sung] by H. Godfrey, Livingston, Ala., 1940: All hid -- Led by O.D. Graham at Drew, Miss., 1939: Little girl, little girl -- Pullin' the skiff -- K. and O. Shipp [at] Byhalia, Miss., 1939: Old Uncle Rabbitt -- Sea lion woman -- Group, Atmon, Ala., 1934: Ain't gonna sing no more -- Led by O.D. Graham: Shortenin' bread -- Recorded by John A., Ruby T., and Alan Lomax and Ruby Pickens Tartt and sung by H. McClintock at Livingston, Ala., 1940: Poor little Johnny -- Go to sleep -- Sung by Mr. and Mrs. Joe McDonald at Livingston, Ala., 1939: Rosie -- Sung by H. McClintock: Gon' knock John Booker to the low ground -- Sung by Moses Platt at Central State Farm, Sugarland, Tex., 1933: Run, nigger, run --  </abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.207</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Pryor, David, Henry Lundy, Elizabeth Austin and Nassau String Band</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>1935</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 10 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>The Library of Congress Division of Music Recording Laboratory. Archive of American Folk Song. Recorded by Alan Lomax and Mary E. Barnicle and sung by David Pryor and Henry Lundy, and group at Nassau, Bahamas, 1935: Dig my grave -- Round the Bay of Mexico -- Bowline... Led by Elizabeth Austin at Old Bight, Cat Island, Bahamas, 1935: Sail gal... Sung with drum by group at Nassau, Bahamas, 1935: Hallie Rock... Sung and played by Nassau String Band at Nassau, Bahamas, 1935: Bimini gal...</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.208 (10in.)</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Hofpauir, Elida</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>1934</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>The Library of Congress Division of Music Recording Laboratory. Archive of American Folk Song. Recorded by John A. and Alan Lomax and sung by Elida Hofpauir and sister at New Iberia, La., 1934: Le Plus jeune des trois -- Sept ans sur la mer -- Les Clefs de la prison --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.209</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Perry, Wayne, Joe Segura and Ogdel Carrier</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>1934</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>The Library of Congress Division of Music Recording Laboratory. Archive of American Folk Song. Recorded by John A. and Alan Lomax and played on the fiddle by Wayne Perry at Crowley, La., 1934: Acadian waltz -- Sung with fiddle by Joe Segura at Delchambre, La., 1934: Acadian blues -- Sung with accordion by Ogdel Carrier at Angola, La., 1934: O chere 'tite fille -- Sung with fiddle by Joe Segura at Delchambre, La., 1934: Joe Ferail --  </abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.210</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, </unittitle>
  			<unitdate>1934</unitdate>
  			<unitdate>1939</unitdate>
  			<unitdate>1940</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>The Library of Congress Division of Music Recording Laboratory. Archive of American Folk Song. Sung by Ricardo Archuleta at Cerro, New Mexico, 1940, and recorded by Juan B. Rael: El Tecolote... Sung with guitar by Jose Suarez at Brownsville, Tex., 1939, and recorded by John A. and Ruby T. Lomax: La Batalla del ojo de aqua... Sung by Josephine Gonzales, Aurora Gonzales, Pearl Menchaco, Adela Flores and Belia Trujillo at San Antonio, Texas, 1934, and recorded by John A. and Alan Lomax: Mexican children's games  --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.211</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Miranda, Franquilino and Ricardo Archuleta</unittitle>
  			<unitdate certainty="approximate">193?</unitdate>
  			<unitdate>1940</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>The Library of Congress Division of Music Recording Laboratory. Archive of American Folk Song. Sung by Franquilino Miranda and group at Cotulla, Texas, 193? and recorded by John A. and Alan Lomax: Songs from Los Pastores -- Sung by Ricarco Archuleta at Cerro, New Mexico, 1940, and recorded by Juan B. Rael: Songs from El Nino perdido --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.212</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, John, Chancey Johnny, Joshua Buck, Chief Joseph Logan and Simeon Gibson</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>1941</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>The Library of Congress Division of Music Recording Laboratory. Archive of American Folk Song. Sung with turtle rattle by Chancey Johnny John at Allegany Reservation, N.Y., 1941, and recorded by William N. Fenton: The Creator's songs -- The Great feather dance ('osto'we'gowa) - Seneca... Sung by Joshua Buck, Chief Joseph Logan, Simeon Gibson and Chancey Johnny John at Six Nations Reserve, Canada and Allegany Reservation, N.Y., 1941 and recorded by William N. Fenton: Midwinter festival chants -- </abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.213</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Logan, Chief Joseph</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>1941</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>The Library of Congress Division of Music Recording Laboratory. Archive of American Folk Song. Sung with gourd rattle by Chief Joseph Logan at Six Nations Reserve, Canada, 1941, and recorded by William N. Fenton: Medicine men's celebration (hadihi'dus) - Ononodaga -- The Medicine dance (selections) --  </abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.214</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Buck, Joshua, Simeon Gibson and George Buck</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>1941</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>The Library of Congress Division of Music Recording Laboratory. Archive of American Folk Song. Sung by Joshua Buck and Simeon Gibson at Six Nations Reserve, Canada, 1941, and recorded by William N. Fenton: The False-face company - Six Nations, Canada... Sung by George Buck with companion at Six Nations, Canada, 1941, and recorded by William N. Fenton: Corn song - Cayuga --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.215</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Buck, George, Joshua Buck and Chief Joseph Logan</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>1941</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>The Library of Congress Division of Music Recording Laboratory. Archive of American Folk Song. Sung with water drum and horn rattle by George and Joshua Buck at Six Nations Reserve, Canada, 1941: The Iroquois war dances (wa saa'se') as of 1812 - Cayuga -- The Scalp dance (a modern show song)... Sung with water drum and horn rattle by Chief Joseph Logan at Six Nations Reserve, Canada, 1941: Eagle, or Striking dance (gane'gwa'e) - Onondaga (a variant of the Calumet dance) --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.216</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Buck, Joshua, Simeon Gibson and George Buck</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>1941</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>The Library of Congress Division of Music Recording Laboratory. Archive of American Folk Song. Sung by Joshua Buck and Simeon Gibson at Six Nations Reserve, Canada, 1941, and recorded by William N. Fenton: The Warrior's stomp dance, or Trotting dance - Seneca-Onondaga -- Women's shuffle dance - Modern, Cayuga --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.217</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Begley, Justus</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>1937</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>The Library of Congress Division of Music Recording Laboratory. Archive of American Folk Song. Sung with banjo by Justus Begley at Hazard, Ky., 1937, and recorded by Alan and Elizabeth Lomax: The Golden willow tree, part  1 and 2 -- The Rambling boy --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.218</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Gladden, Mrs. Texas</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>1941</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>The Library of Congress Division of Music Recording Laboratory. Archive of American Folk Song. Sung by Mrs. Texas Gladden at Salem, Va., 1941, and recorded by Alan Lomax: The Two brothers -- The Four Marys --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.219</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Barker, Horton</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>1949</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>The Library of Congress Division of Music Recording Laboratory. Archive of American Folk Song. Sung by Horton Barker at Chilhowie, Va., 1939, and recorded by Herbert Halpert: The Two sisters -- Lord Thomas and fair Ellender --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.220</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Turbyfill, Mrs. Lena Bare, I.G. Greer and Mrs. I.G. Greer</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>1939</unitdate>
  			<unitdate>1941</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>The Library of Congress Division of Music Recording Laboratory. Archive of American Folk Song. Sung by Mrs. Lena Bare Turbyfill at Elk Park, N.C., 1939, and recorded by Herbert Halpert: Bolakins (Lamkin) -- Sung by I.G. Greer of Thomasville, N.C., with dulcimer by Mrs. I.G. Greer, and recorded at Greensboro, N.C., 1941, by Fletcher Collins: The Three babies --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.221</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Greer, I.G., Mrs. I.G. Greer and Hobart Smith</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>1941</unitdate>
  			<unitdate>1942</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>The Library of Congress Division of Music Recording Laboratory. Archive of American Folk Song. Sung by I.G. Greer of Thomasville, N.C., with dulcimer by Mrs. I.G. Greer, and recorded at Greensboro, N.C., 1941, by Fletcher Collins: Sanford Barney -- Sung with guitar by Hobart Smith at Saltville, Va., 1942, and recorded by Alan Lomax: Claude Allen --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.222</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Truvillion, Henry, Sam Hazel and Joe Shores</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>1939</unitdate>
  			<unitdate>1940</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 10 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>The Library of Congress Division of Music Recording Laboratory. Archive of American Folk Song. Sung by Samuel Brooks at Edwards, Miss., 1939: Arwhoolie (Cornfield holler) -- Quittin' time songs 1 &amp; 2 -- Called by Thomas J. Marshall at Edwards, Miss., 1939, and recorded by Herbert Halpert: Mealtime call-- Sung by Henry Truvillion at Burkeville, Tex., 1940, and recorded by John A. and Ruby T. Lomax: Possum was an evil thing -- Come on, boys, and let's go huntin' --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.224 (10in.)</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Platt, Moses (Clear Rock), James (Iron Head) Baker, Will Crosby and R.D. Allen</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>1933</unitdate>
  			<unitdate>1934</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 10 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>The Library of Congress Division of Music Recording Laboratory. Archive of American Folk Song. Recorded by John A. and Alan Lomax... Sung by Moses (Clear Rock) Platt and James (Iron Head) Baker at Central State Farm, Sugarland, Texas, 1934: Old rattler.. Sung by James (Iron Head) Baker, Will Crosby, R.D. Allen and Moses (Clear Rock) Platt at Central State Farm, Sugarland, Texas, 1933: Go down, old Hannah --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.225 (10in.)</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Bradley, Jesse and "Lightening"</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>1934</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 10 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>The Library of Congress Division of Music Recording Laboratory. Archive of American Folk Song. Recorded by John A. and Alan Lomax...Sung by Jesse Bradley and group at State Penitentiary, Huntsville, Texas, 1934: Hammer, ring...sung by "Lightening" and group at Darrington State Farm, Sandy Point, Texas, 1934: I wonder what's the matter...</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.226 (10in.)</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Pryor, David, Kelley Pace and Allen Prothero</unittitle>
  			<unitdate type="inclusive">1933-1935</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 10 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>The Library of Congress Division of Music Recording Laboratory. Archive of American Folk Song. Recorded by Alan Lomax and Mary E. Barnicle and sung by David Pryor and group of Andros Island men at Nassau, Bahamas, 1935: Roll'im on down (Bahamas Launching song)...Recorded by John A. and Alan Lomax and sung by Kelley Pace and group at Cummins State Farm, Gould, Ark., 1934: The Rock Island Line...Recorded by John A. and Alan Lomax and sung by Allen Prothero at State Peniteniary, Nashville, Tenn., 1933: Track-Lining songs...</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.227 (10in.)</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Mann, Thomas</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>1937</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>The Library of Congress Division of Music Recording Laboratory. Archive of American Folk Song. Recorded by Mrs. Sidney Robertson Crowell and played on the dulcimer by Thomas Mann at Ortonville, Iowa, 1937: Haste to the wedding, off she goes (medley) -- Irish washerwoman -- Pigtown fling -- Devil's dream -- Nancy's fancy --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.228</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections</unittitle>
  			<unitdate type="inclusive">1936-1941</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>The Library of Congress Division of Music Recording Laboratory. Archive of American Folk Song. Played by Enos Cansy on the fiddle, Tim Cansy on the mandolin, and Lola Cansy on the guitar at Magee, Miss., 1939: Old blue sow...Recorded by Herbert Halpert and sung with fiddle by Eno Cansy with beating of straws by Jim F. Myers at Magee, Miss., 1939: Where'd you get yo' whiskey? -- Pore little Mary settin' in the corner -- Recorded by Alan Lomax and Elizabeth Lomax and played on the banjo by Justin Bigley of Hazard, KY., 1937: Sally Goodin...Recorded by Fletcher Collins and sung with banjo by O.L. Coffey of Scheull's Mills, N.C., 1936: Oh, fly around, my pretty little miss...</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.229</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections</unittitle>
  			<unitdate type="inclusive">1941-1942</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>The Library of Congress Division of Music Recording Laboratory. Archive of American Folk Song. Recorded by Alan Lomax and John W. Work and played by Nashville Washboard Band at Nashville, Tenn., 1941: Soldiers joy...Recorded by Alan Lennox and played by E.C. Ball and Vlair C. Reedy at Rugby, Va., 1941: Bile dem cabbage down...Recorded by John A. Lomax and played by string band with Oscar Harper; Harman Uem; Homer Peters; Ray Hanby with calling by Bob McClary at Dallas Square Dance Club, Dallas, Tex., 1942: The Girl I left behind me -- Sally Goodin --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.230</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>1937</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>The Library of Congress Division of Music Recording Laboratory. Archive of American Folk Song. Recorded by John A. Lomax...Played by string band: J.C. Fowler, Elie Buckner and Alva Ruffner, with calling by S.C. Simon at Lubbock, Texas, 1937: Devil's Dream -- Mississippi Sawyer --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.231</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Boon, Eva Grace and Anne Williams</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>1937</unitdate>
  			<unitdate>1939</unitdate>
  			<unitdate>1942</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>The Library of Congress Division of Music Recording Laboratory. Archive of American Folk Song.Recorded by John A. Lomax and sung by Eva Grace Boone and group at Brandon, Miss., 1937: We're goin' around the mountain...Recorded by Herbert Halpert and sung by Eva Grace Boone and goup at Brandon, Miss., 1939: Old lady sittin' in the dining room -- Little Sally Walker -- All around the Maypole...Recorded by John A. Lomax and sung by Eva Grace Boone and group at Brandon, Miss., 1937: Sissy in the barn -- Little Rosa Lee...Recorded at Moorehead Plantation, Lula, Miss., 1942, by Alan Lomax and Lewis Jones and sung by Anne Williams and group of Dundee, Miss.: Gwan roun', Rabbit -- Satisfied --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.232</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Stothers, Jimmie and Joe Lee</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>1936</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>The Library of Congress Division of Music Recording Laboratory. Archive of American Folk Song. Recorded by John A. Lomax and Harold Spivacke...Sung with guitar by Jimmie Stothers and Joe Lee at State Farm, Virginia, 1936: Do, Lord, remember me -- Sung by Joe Lee at State Farm, Virginia, 1936: House done built without hands -- Oh, the Lamb of God, the Lord done sanctified me -- Sung with guitar by Jimmie Strothers at State Farm, Virginia, 1936: We are almost down to the shore -- Sung by Joe Lee at State Farm, Virginia, 1936: Shines like a star in the morning --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.233</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Reed, Dock, Bosie Sturdivant, and Vera Hall</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>1940</unitdate>
  			<unitdate>1942</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>The Library of Congress Division of Music Recording Laboratory. Archive of American Folk Song. Recorded by John A. Lomax and Ruby T. Lomax and sung by Dock Reed at Livingston, Alabama, 1940: Down on me -- Recorded by John A. and Ruby T. Lomax and sung by Dock Reed and Vera Hall at Livingston, Alabama, 1940: Certainly, Lord -- Recorded by Alan Lomax and Lewis Jones and sung by Bozie (Bosie) Sturdivant at Silent Grove Baptist Church, Clarksdale, Mississippi, 1942: Ain't no grave can hold my body down --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.234</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Griffin, Sin-Killer</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>1934</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>The Library of Congress Division of Music Recording Laboratory. Archive of American Folk Song. Recorded by John A. Lomax...Spoken by Sin-Killer Griffin with congregational responses and singing at Darrington State Farm, Sandy Point, Texas, 1934: The Man of Calvary (Easter Day services) -- Wasn't that a mighty storm --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.235</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Pace, Kelley</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>1942</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>The Library of Congress Division of Music Recording Laboratory. Archive of American Folk Song. Recorded by John A. and Ruby T. Lomax and sung by Kelley Pace and group at Cumins State Farm, Gould, Arkansas, 1942: Holy Babe, part 1 -- Holy Babe, part 2 --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.236</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Johnson, Turner Junior</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>1942</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>The Library of Congress Division of Music Recording Laboratory. Archive of American Folk Song. Recorded by Alan Lomax and Lewis Jones...Sung with harmonica by Turner Junior Johnson at Clarksdale, Mississippi, 1942: Meet me in Jerusalem -- When I lay my burden down -- In New Jerusalem -- Steal away --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.237</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Music of the world's people, Vol. IV</unittitle>
  			<unitdate label="copyright">1958</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>New York, N.Y., Folkways Records &amp; Service Corp. Complied and edited by Henry Cowell... Ituri forest pygmies -- Borneo (Gamelon) -- Switzerland -- Mexico (Yaqui dance) -- U.S.S.R. (Folk song) -- Estonia -- Rumania (Dance)  -- Ceylon -- Austria -- </abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.261</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Music of the world's people, Vol. IV</unittitle>
  			<unitdate label="copyright">1958</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>New York, N.Y., Folkways Records &amp; Service Corp. Complied and edited by Henry Cowell... Samoa -- Bretagne -- Portugal (Christmas song) -- Venezuela (Dance) -- Armenia (Dance) -- Sweden (Walking tune) -- Java (Classical song) -- Korea (Classical song) -- Kurdistan -- U.S.A. -- </abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.262</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Negro prison camp worksongs</unittitle>
  			<unitdate label="copyright">1956</unitdate>
  			<physdesc></physdesc>
  			<abstract>New York, N.Y., Folkways Records &amp; Service Corp. Recorded by Toshi &amp; Peter Seeger, John Lomax, Jr., Chester Bower and Fred Hellerman at Ramsey and Retrieve State Farms, Texas... Let your hammer ring -- Here, rattler, here -- Chopping in the new ground -- Mighty bright light -- Go down old Hannah -- Grizzly bear -- Lost John -- You got to hurry -- I need more power -- We need another witness -- </abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.263</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Old harp singing, Old Harp Singers of Eastern Tennessee</unittitle>
  			<unitdate label="copyright">1951</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>New York, N.Y., Folkways Records &amp; Service Corp. Sung by the Old Harp Singers of Eastern Tennessee: Ocean No. 159 -- Greenfields No. 16 -- Hightower No. 87 -- Pleasant Hill No. 43 -- Amazing grace -- Western Mount Pleasant No. 206 -- Wondrous love No. 143 -- Morning trumpet No. 99 -- Northfield No. 115 -- Liberty No. 98 -- </abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.264</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Union songs: Talking union, Seeger, Pete and the Almanac Singers</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>1955</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>New York, N.Y., Folkways Records &amp; Service Corp. Sung by Pete Seeger and Chorus: We shall not be moved  -- Roll the union on -- Casey Jones -- Miner's lifeguard -- Solidarity forever -- Join the union -- Hold the fort... The Almanac Singers: Get thee behind me, Satan -- Union maid -- All I want -- Talking union -- Union train -- Which side --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.265</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Riddle me this: Jean Ritchie and Oscar Brand, Ritchie, Jean and Oscar Brand</unittitle>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>New York, N.Y., Bill Grauer Productions Inc. Sung by Jean Ritchie and Oscar Brand: The Cambric shirt -- The Deaf woman's courtship -- I will give my love an apple -- Marching across the green grass -- Riddle me this -- What are little boys made of -- Madam, will you walk -- Big, glass doll -- Soldier, soldier -- My good old man -- Jennie Jenkins -- The Riddle song -- Paper of pins -- Pretty li'l reckless boy -- Who killed Cock Robin -- Billy Boy -- </abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.266</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Robin Hood ballads, House, Wallace</unittitle>
  			<unitdate label="copyright">1953</unitdate>
  			<physdesc></physdesc>
  			<abstract>New York, N.Y., Folkways Records &amp; Service Corp. Sung by Wallace House: Robin Hood's Morris -- Robin Hood and the three squires -- The Jolly Pinder of Wakefield -- Robin Hood and the ranger -- Robin Hood's death and burial -- True tale of Robin Hood -- Robin Hood and Little John -- Robin Hood and the Curtall fryer -- Robin Hood and the tanner -- Robin Hood and Maid Marian --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.267 (10in.)</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Songs of the sea, Mills, Alan and the Four Shipmates</unittitle>
  			<unitdate label="copyright">1957</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>New York, N.Y., Folkways Records &amp; Service Corp. Sung by Alan Mills and the Four Shipmates with guitar accompaniment by B. Lacombe:  Blow boys blow -- Blow the man down -- Clear the track -- Can't you dance the polka -- A Long time ago -- New Bedford whalers -- Fire down below -- The Sailor's grave -- Boney was a warrior -- Santy Anna --  The Chesapeake and Shannon -- Home, Dearie, home -- Goodbye, fare ye well -- Hilo somebody -- Galloping pandy dandy o -- Leave her, Johnny -- Rio Grande -- Haul away Joe -- Sally Brown -- Chee'ly men -- Johnny Boker -- Paddy Doyle -- Dead horse -- Salt horse -- A-roving -- Tom's gone to Hilo -- Ten thousand miles away -- Shenandoah -- Billy Boy -- Lowlands -- Drunken sailor --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.268</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Spanish and Mexican folk music of New Mexico</unittitle>
  			<unitdate label="copyright">1952</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>New York, N.Y., Folkways Records &amp; Service Corp. Recorded by J.D. Robb in New Mexico and sung by James Trujillo and Sam and Modesto Garcia: Matachines dances -- Sung by Garcilian Pacheco: Huapango -- Sung by Felix Ortega: Entriega de novios -- [Sung by] Librado Leyba and Eddie Ortiz: Polka -- Sung by Alfred Campos and Edwin Lobato: La Luna se va me tiendo -- Cuarto caminos -- Sung by Arthur L. Campa: El Zapatero -- Sung by Daniel Lopez: Grasshopper waltz --Sung by Jacobo Maestas: Cancion ingles -- Sung by congregation: Hymn of farewell -- Sung by Felix Ortega and Consuelo Ortega: Corrida de Elena -- Sung by Vidal Valdez and Lupe Rodriguez: Para queme sirvo el vino -- Sung by: Arvino Martinez: Trovo del viego vilmas -- [Sung by] Jacobo Maestras and Victor Frescas: Cuna --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.269</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Hudde Ledbetter Memorial, Leadbelly, Woody Guthrie, Cisco Houston, Oleander Quartet, Anne Graham, and Sonny Terry</unittitle>
  			<unitdate label="copyright">1950</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 10 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>New York, N.Y., Folkways Records &amp; Service Corp. Recording supervisor Moses Asch... Reels and blues: Green corn -- Yellow gal -- You can't lose me cholly -- Laura -- Good morning blues -- Leaving blues -- Big fat woman -- Work songs and spirituals: Gray goose -- Pick a bale of cotton -- Take this hammer -- Bring me a little water, Silvy -- Moaning -- Meeting at the building -- We shall walk through the valley -- Irene --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.270 (10in.)</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Songs of the Mormon pioneers, Sorrels, Rosalie</unittitle>
 			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Festival Records. Rosalie Sorrels sings songs of the Mormon pioneers with the Singing Saints: None can preach the gospel like the Mormons do -- The Gospel news -- Poor wayfaring man of grief -- Tittery-irie-ay -- On the road to California -- The Lonesome roving wolves -- The Dying Californian -- The Handcart song -- The Unknown grave -- Whoa! Haw! Buck and Jerry boy -- Hard time's come again no more -- Don't you marry the Mormon boys -- Blue Mountain -- Once I lived in Cottonwood -- Seagulls and crickets -- Zack, the Mormon engineer -- Echo Canyon -- St. George and the drag-on -- Mormon Yankee Doodle --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.272</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Spirituals with Dock Reed and Vera Hall, Reed, Dock and Vera Hall</unittitle>
  			<unitdate label="copyright">1953</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 10 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>New York City, N.Y., Folkways Records &amp; Service Corp. Spirituals with Dock Reed and Vera Hall, and recorded in Alabama by Harold Courlander and assisted by Ruby Pickens Tartt &amp; Emma Courlander: I'm going home on the morning train -- My God ain't no lying man -- Where the sun will never go down -- Troubled Lord I'm troubled -- Look how they done my Lord -- Job Job -- What month was Jesus born in -- Somebody's talking about Jesus -- Death is awful -- I'm climbing up the hills of Mt. Zion -- Low down the chariot and let me ride --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.273 (10in.)</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>900 miles and other R.R. songs, Houston, Cisco</unittitle>
  			<unitdate label="copyright">1953</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 10 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>New York City, N.Y., Folkways Records &amp; Service Corp. Recorded by Moses Asch... Sung by Cisco Houston with guitar: The Brave engineer -- The Gambler -- The Rambler -- R.R. Bill -- Worried man blues -- 900 miles -- 'Gettin Up' holler -- The Roamer -- Wreck of the '97 -- Hobo Bill -- The Great American bum --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.274 (10in.)</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Skiffle bands, The Mobile Strugglers, Virgil Perkins, The Memphis Jug Band and Gus Cannon</unittitle>
  			<unitdate label="copyright">1957</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>New York City, N.Y., Folkways Records &amp; Service Corp. Recorded by Samuel B. Charters... The Mobile Strugglers recorded July 18, 1954, Mobile, Ala....Musicians include: Tyler Jackson, washtub bass; Moochie Reeves, guitar; Ollie Crenshaw, kazoo and guitar: Raise a ruckus tonight -- Rock me, baby -- My bonnie lies over the ocean -- Trouble, trouble followed me all of my days... Interview with Virgil Perkins and songs recorded Nov. 6, 1955, Houston, Texas: Interview -- Goin around the mountain, darlin' Bessie -- John Henry... The Memphis Jug Band with Gus Cannon, and interview with Gus Cannon, recorded December 5, 1956, Memphis, Tennessee... Musicians include: Will Shade, harmonica and guitar; Charlie Burse, tenor guitar; Gus Cannon, 5-string banjo and jug: Harmonica blues -- Tippin' round -- Old John Booker -- Interview -- You call that gone -- Kansas City blues -- Shade and Burse -- Interview -- Take your fingers off it --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.275</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Jack tales, Long, Mrs. Maud Gentry</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>1957</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Library of Congress Division of Music Recording Laboratory. The Folklore Collection. Recorded at Washington D.C., 1947, by Duncan Emrich... Jack tales told by Mrs. Maud Gentry Long of Hot Springs, North Carolina: Introduction to Jack tales -- Jack and the drill -- Jack and sop dog -- Jack and the bull -- </abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.276</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Song of the Mormons; Songs and ballads of the West</unittitle>
  			<unitdate type="inclusive">1938-1949</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Library of Congress Division of Music Recording Laboratory. The Folklore Collection. Songs of the Mormons performed by various people, and recorded in various locations in Utah during the 1940's: On the road to California, or the Buffalo bull fight -- Bull fight -- The Handcart song -- Tittery-ire-aye -- Echo Canyon  -- The Utah iron horse -- St. George... Songs and ballads of the West performed by various people, and recorded in various locations in California, Missouri, Arkansas and Arizona in the 1930's and 1940's: Root hog or die -- Starving to death on a government claim -- Joe Bowers -- Custer's last charge -- Sam Bass -- The Brazos River -- Freighting from Wilcox to Globe --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.277</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Singing across the land with Sam Hinton, Hinton, Sam</unittitle>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>New York City, N.Y., Decca Records. The Old-world heritage: Bryan O'lynn -- Our goodman -- The Farmer's curst wife -- Early America: Springfield Mountain -- Johnny Sands -- Jolly Old Roger -- The Greenland fishery -- The Southern mountains: Old Joe Clark -- Ground hog -- Buffalo boy -- The Barnyard song -- The Midwest: Nine hundred miles -- Frankie and Johnny -- Gambler's blues -- The Deep South: Old boastun was dead -- Travelin' man blues -- Tell Old Bill -- The Far West: Echo Canyon -- Doney gal -- Sierra Peaks -- Night herder's song --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.278</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Jazz, Vol. 10: Boogie woogie and jump</unittitle>
  			<unitdate label="copyright">1953</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>New York City, N.Y., Folkways Records &amp; Service Corp. Records from the collection of Frederic Ramsey, Jr.... Boogie woogie: Jim Jackson's jamboree, part I -- Jim Jackson's jamboree, cont'd. -- Hastings Street -- St. Louis blues -- Honky tonk train -- Brown skin gal -- Yancey stomp -- Jump and Kansas City: Let 'em jump -- Toby -- Froggy bottom -- Boogie woogie -- Hootie blues -- Lester leaps in -- Dickie's dream --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.284</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>This land is my land: A collection of American folk songs, Guthrie, Woody, Pete Seeger and Leadbelly</unittitle>
  			<unitdate label="copyright">1951</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 10 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>New York City, N.Y., Folkways Records &amp; Service Corp. Sung by Woody Guthrie: This land is my land... Sung by Sam Eskin: Lumbermen's alphabet... Sung by Bill Bonyon: Down the hatch... Sung by Harry McClintock "Mac": Jerry go and oil that car... Sung by Pete Seeger: Young man who wouldn't hoe corn... Sung by Woody Guthrie: Columbia River... Sung by Cisco Houston: Old Blue -- Down in the mines -- Whoopee ti yo yo... Sung by Leadbelly: Old man -- Haul away Joe --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.285 (10in.)</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>American industrial ballads, Seeger, Pete</unittitle>
  			<unitdate label="copyright">1956</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>New York City, N.Y., Folkways Records &amp; Service Corp. Recorded by Moses Asch... Sung by Pete Seeger, with 5-string guitar, Songs from 1800 to 1924: Peg and awl -- The Blind fiddler -- Buffalo skinners -- Eight hour day -- Hard times in the mill -- Roll down the line -- Hayseed like me -- The Farmer is the man -- Come all you hardy miners -- He lies in the American land -- Casey Jones -- Let them wear their watches -- Weaver room blues -- Songs from the 1920's to the 1940's: Cotton mill colic -- Cotton and 40c. meat -- Mill mother's lament -- Fare ye well, old Ely Branch -- Beans, bacon and gravy -- The Death of Harry Simms -- Winnsboro cotton mill blues -- Ballad of Barney Graham -- My children are seven in number -- Raggedy, raggedy are we -- Pittsburgh town -- 600/0 parity -- </abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.286</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Negro folk music of Africa and America</unittitle>
  			<unitdate label="copyright">1951</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>[New York, N.Y.], Folkways Records &amp; Serv. Corp. Various African songs performed by various groups: South Africa (Zulu); French Equatorial Africa (Badouma); Nigeria (Yoruba and Ibo); Sudan; Zanzibar (Swahili); Eritrea (Tigrai); Ethiopia (Amhara)</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.287</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Mexican corridos</unittitle>
  			<unitdate label="copyright">1956</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 10 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>New York City, N.Y., Folkways Records &amp; Service Corp. Recorded in Mexico... Corrido de Cananea -- La Rejeca   -- El Arreglo religioso -- Toma de gelava -- Andava ausente Simon --Prietita de ojos negros -- La Vaquilla (Corrido de Pancho Villa) -- El Minero --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.288 (10in.)</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Spain: Flamenco music of Anadalusia</unittitle>
  			<unitdate label="copyright">1956</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>New York City, N.Y., Folkways Records &amp; Service Corp. Recorded by Walther Hennig... Flamenco dance song -- Bulerias -- Soleares -- Malaguenas -- Andalusian folk song -- Soleares for guitar -- Cuadro flamenco -- Saeta (Andalusian religious folksong) -- Anadulasian folksong -- Anadulasian folksong -- Song from Malaga -- Malaguenas -- Peteneras -- Rumores de la caleta -- Recuerdos de la Alhambra --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.289</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Folk music of Palestine</unittitle>
  			<unitdate label="copyright">1951</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>New York City, N.Y., Folkways Records &amp; Service Corp. Recorded by the Anthropological Institute of Israel and produced through the cooperation of the Wenner-Gren Foundation... Songs are Hebrew, Arabic, Bokharian and Persian... Gulait dore -- Al matcha anora -- Tulkum -- Raftam rayi -- Taki chasma -- Recitation from Firdausi's shahname -- Ve eem lo asksahv -- Bible recitation on Sabbath -- Kedusha -- Kether -- Song of Moses -- Ceremonial song -- Prophet's birthday song -- Song of Ramadan -- Recitation from the Koran -- Love song --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.290</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Mariachi aguilas de Chapala</unittitle>
  			<unitdate label="copyright">1960</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>New York City, N.Y., Folkways Records &amp; Service Corp. Mariachi music from the Mexican state of Jalisco recorded in Chapala, Jalisco, with notes on mariachi music by Charles M. Bogert &amp; Martha R. Bogert... Atotonilco -- Las Olas -- La Negra -- Jarabe Tapatio -- La Bamba -- Chapala -- Tecalitlan -- La Adelita -- Las Bicicletas -- Ojos Tapatios -- Ay, Jalisco no te rajes -- Las Mananitas -- El Carretero se va -- </abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.292</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Two-way trip: American, Scots and English folksongs, Seeger, Peggy and Ewan MacColl</unittitle>
  			<unitdate label="copyright">1961</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>New York City, N.Y., Folkways Records &amp; Service Corp. Sung by Peggy Seeger and Ewan MacColl: Waly, Waly -- Richie story (Child #232) -- The Crafty farmer (Child #283) -- The Barring of the door (Child #275) -- Jenny Nettles -- Old Lady All Skin and Bones -- Tullochgorum -- The Two brothers (Child #49) -- Just as the time was flowing -- Jackaro -- The Carrion crow -- Matty Groves (Child #81) -- The Bartley explosion -- The Devil's nine questions (Child #1) --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.293</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>American play-parties, Seeger, Pete, Mika Seeger and Larry Eisenberg</unittitle>
  			<unitdate label="copyright">1959</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Mazoo, mazoo -- Skip to my lou -- Shake them 'simmons down -- Alabama bound -- Sally down the alley -- Turn the glasses over -- Goodbye Liza Jane -- Git along home -- Paw paw patch -- Betty Larkin -- Jolly is the miller -- Pig in the parlor -- Great big house in New Orleans -- Sent my brown jug down town --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.294</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Negro folk music of Africa and America</unittitle>
  			<unitdate label="copyright">1951</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>New York City, N.Y., Folkways Records &amp; Service Corp. Edited by Harold Courlander... Recorded by Harold Courlander, Ricardo Alegria and Melville J. and Frances S. Herkovits... Songs are from Cuba, Trinidad, United States, Brazil, Colombia, Haiti, and Puerto Rico... Lucumi song -- Shango cult song -- Beli dance -- What shall I do to be saved -- Didn't you hear my Lord when He called -- My name has been written down -- Move members move -- Jesha for Oshun -- Cowherds' festival -- Worksong -- Juba dance -- Nago dance -- Meringue -- Gallinita toma tu maiz -- </abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.295</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Trio Calaveras</unittitle>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 10 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Mexico, D.F., RCA Victor Mexicana SA. Performed by Trio Calaveras (Pepe, Raul y Miguel)... Cancion: Palomita (Pedro Galindo), from the film, "Una Cancion en la Noche"... Huapango: Quiereme chiquita (Lorenzo Barcelata) --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.296 (10in.)</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Hermanos Chavarria</unittitle>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 10 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Columbia. Mexican vocal duo: Hermanos Chavarria, [accompanied by guitars]: Corrido, Los Tequileros, part I and part II (by Jose Garcia) --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.297 (10in.)</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Escobarete, Leopoldo y Torres</unittitle>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 10 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Columbia. Performed by vocal duo: Leopoldo Escobarete y Torres, [accompanied by guitars]: Corrido del bajo -- El Pajaro carpintero --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.298 (10in.)</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Hernandez, Luis and Leonardo Sifuentes</unittitle>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 10 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Camden, N.J., Victor Talking Machine Co. Performed by Luis Hernandez and Leonardo Sifuentes, [with two guitars]: El Contrabando de El Paso, parts I and II --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.299 (10in.)</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Agustin Irusta y Orquesta Americo Caggiano</unittitle>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 10 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Mexico, D.F., RCA Victor Mexicana SA. Performed by Agustin Irusta y Orquesta Americo Caggiano... Tango: Encuentro (Miguel Buoino) -- Cancion: Las Mentiras de Jose (Robledo, Riveroll y Cabral) --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.300 (10in.)</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Potpourri de bailes mexicanos; Boogie woogie, Orq[uestra] de Juan S. Garrido</unittitle>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 10 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Mexico, D.F., Discos Peerless. La Raspa -- Hamp's boogie woogie (Lionel Hampton) --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.301 (10in.)</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>El Caiman; Los Arbolitos, Trio Calaveras</unittitle>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 10 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Mexico, D.F., RCA Victor Mexicana, SA. El Caiman -- Los Arbolitos (Chucho Martinez Gil) --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.302 (10in.)</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>La Calandria; Las Tres huastecas, Los Trovadores Plateados</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>April 7, 1921</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 10 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>[Mexico, D.F.], Peerless. Huapango: La Calandria (Nicandro Castillo) -- Las Tres huastecas (Nicandro Castillo) --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.303 (10in.)</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>El Barzon; La Mula bronca, Guerrero, Lalo and El Mariachi Imperial</unittitle>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 10 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>El Barzon (Jose Rodriguez) -- La Mula bronca (Victor Cordero) --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.304 (10in.)</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Trio Nava</unittitle>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 10 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>New York, Columbia Phonograph Company, Inc. Corrido - Acomp. de guitarra (Jesus Leal) -- Corrido - Acomp. de guitarra (Heraclio Bernal) --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.305 (10in.)</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Hay un lirio; Los Gavilanes, Trio Jaliciense</unittitle>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 10 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Voralion. The Trio Jaliciense is a male trio, with violin, guitar, and clarinet... Hay un lirio (There is a lily, I.M. Valle) -- Pespunte: Los Gavilanes (The Sparrow-hawks, I.M. Valle)... Disc is broken...</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.306 (10in.)</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Corrido de Jesus Garcia, Posada y Molina</unittitle>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 10 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>New York, N.Y., Columbia Phonograph Company, Inc. Corrido de Jesus Garcia (El Hero de Nacozari), Parts I and II (E. Perez) --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.307 (10in.)</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections</unittitle>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm, 10 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Rigas. Titles and performers listed in Russian</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.308 (10in.)</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>El Celoso; Margarita, Trio Ramirez-Valles-Fierro and Orquesta Acosta</unittitle>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 10 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>New York, N.Y., Columbia Phonograph Company, Inc. El Celoso (Ed. Tavo) -- Margarita (Ed. Tavo) --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.309 (10in.)</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Owen, Dock, Paine Denson, Lee Wells, and L.P. Odem</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>1942</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>The Library of Congress Division of Music Recording Laboratories. Archive of American Folk Song. Recorded by Alan Lomax and George Pullen Johnson of Birmingham, Alabama, August, 1942...Led by Dock Owen of Marshall County, Alabama: Windham -- Led by Paine Denson of Birmingham, Alabama: Mear -- Led by Lee Wells of Jasper, Alabama: Wondrous Love -- Led by L.P. Odem of St. Joseph, Tennessee: Lover of the Lord --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.238</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Posey, Mrs. Delilah Denson, Paine Denson, Mrs. Maude Moncrief, and Mrs. M.L. Mann</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>1942</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>The Library of Congress Division of Music Recording Laboratories. Archive of American Folk Song. Recorded by Alan Lomax and George Pullen Jackson of Birmingham, Alabama, August, 1942... Led by Mrs. Delilah Denson Posey of Birmingham, Alabama: Northfield... Led by Mrs. Maude Moncrief of Birmingham, Alabama: Mount Zion...  Led by Mrs. M.L. Mann of Opelika, Alabama: Milford...</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.239</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Posey, Mrs. Delilah Denson, John M. Dye, Euna Vee Denson Nail, and Ernestine Tipton</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>1942</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>The Library of Congress Division of Music Recording Laboratories. Archive of American Folk Song. Recorded by Alan Lomax and George Pullen Jackson of Birmingham, Alabama, August, 1942...Led by Ernestine Tipton of Birmingham, Alabama: Ballstown... Led by Mrs. Delilah Denson Posey of Birmingham, Alabama: Edom... Led by John M. Dye of Birmingham, Alabama: Stratfield... Led by Euna Vee Denson Nail of Birmingham, Alabama: Evening shade...</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.240</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Tipton, Ernestine, Dock Owen and A. Marcus Cagle</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>1942</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>The Library of Congress Division of Music Recording Laboratories. Archive of American Folk Song. Recorded by Alan Lomax and George Pullen Jackson of Birmingham, Alabama, August, 1942... Led by Ernestine Tipton of Birmingham, Ala.: Fillmore... Led by Dock Owen of Sand Mountain, Marshall County, Ala.: Sardis... Led by A. Marcus Cagle of Atlanta, GA.: Mission -- Vain world adieu --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.241</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Denson, Paine, Howard Denson and R.M. Hornsby</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>1942</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>The Library of Congress Division of Music Recording Laboratories. Archive of American Folk Song. Recorded by Alan Lomax and George Pullen Jackson of Birmingham, Alabama, August, 1942... Led by Paine Denson of Birmingham, Ala.: Heavenly vision... Led by Howard Denson of Tuscaloosa, Ala.: David's lamentation... Led by R.M. Hornsby of Clay County, Ala.: Sherburne...</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.242</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Edna Ritchie, Ritchie, Edna</unittitle>
  			<unitdate label="copyright">1962</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Huntington, VA., Folk Legacy Records, Inc. May day carol -- Gentle fair Jennie -- The riddle song -- Old Tyler -- Old Crumley -- Aunt Sal's song -- Foreign landes -- Dear companion -- Old King Cole -- Somebody's tall and handsome -- Down came an angel -- The Cuckoo -- Old chimney sweeper -- Fair and tender ladies -- Blackest crow -- I wonder when I shall be married -- An Old man came courting me -- Jackero -- As Joseph was a-walking --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.243</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Haul on the bowlin' and other shanties &amp; foc'sle songs, Lloyd, A.L. Ewan MacColl and Harry Corbett</unittitle>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Stinson Records. Haul on the bowlin'(A.L. Lloyd &amp; chorus) -- Row bullies, row (Ewan MacColl) -- The coast of Peru (A.L. Lloyd) -- The black ball line (Ewan MacColl &amp; chorus) -- The Ship in distress (A.L. Lloyd) -- The Ganger (Ewan MacColl) -- Blow the man down (Harry Corbett &amp; chorus) -- Do me ama (A.L. Lloyd) -- Santy Anna (A.L. Lloyd and chorus) -- The Flying cloud (Ewan MacColl) -- A Hundred years ago (A.L. Lloyd &amp; chorus) --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.244</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Hawaiian chant, hula and music, Kiona, Kaulaheaonamiku</unittitle>
  			<unitdate label="copyright">1962</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>New York, NY., Folkways Records &amp; Service Corp. Recorded in Hawaii by Jacob Feuerring with vocals by Kaulaheaonamiku Kiona accompanied by native instruments... Kauka Hali'a I ka -- Kahiki Lan Lani -- He Wahini Holo Lio -- Pihanakalani -- Heeia -- Hilo E -- Hela Mai A Kalani -- Au'a la E Kama Moku -- Hole Waimea -- Maika' I Kaua'I -- Kona Kai Opu -- Auhea Wale Ana 'Oe -- Kauliua I Ke Anu Waialeale -- Ohe Hano Ihu --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.245</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Marie Hare</unittitle>
  			<unitdate label="copyright">1962</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Huntington, VT., Folk-Legacy Records, Inc. Green Valley -- Patrick O'Donnell -- Green grows the laurel -- Maid of the east -- The Jam on Gerry's rocks -- The Banks of the Miramichi -- The Wexford lass -- Billy Grimes -- Jenny dear -- Peter Emberley -- Her mantle so green --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.246</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Mountain music bluegrass style</unittitle>
  			<unitdate label="copyright">1959</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>New York, NY., Folkways Records &amp; Service Corp. Recorded and annotated by Mike Seeger... Katy Hill (Tex Logan) -- Short life of trouble (Earl Taylor &amp; the Stoney Mtn. Boys) -- Katy Cline (Don Stover, Chubby Anthony, B. Lilly and E. Pegdon) -- The Philadelphia lawyer (Bob Baker and the Pike Country Boys) -- Natchez under the hill (Tex Logan) -- Ain't nobody gonna miss me (Lilly - Stover) -- Old Joe Clark (Mike Seeger - Bob Yellin) -- Little Willie (Bob Baker, etc.) -- Whitehouse blues (Earl Taylor, etc.) -- Nine pound hammer (Smiley Hobbs) -- Cricket on the hearth (Anthony - Stover) -- All the good times have passed &amp; gone! (Earl Taylor, etc.) -- New River train (Anthony - Mike Seeger) -- Leather britches (Smiley Hobbs) -- Fox chase (Earl Taylor, etc.) -- Feast here tonight (Bob Baker) -- Bile em cabbage down (Stover, etc.) -- Rocky run (Jerry Stuart, Smiley Hobbs, and Pete Roberts) -- Snow dove (Bob Baker, etc.) --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.247</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Duet songs of French Canada, Baillargeon, Helen and Alan Mills</unittitle>
  			<unitdate label="copyright">1955</unitdate>
  			<physdesc></physdesc>
  			<abstract>New York, N.Y., Folkways Records &amp; Service Corp. J'entends le moulin -- Fringue, fringue! -- J'ai tant danse -- Aupres de ma blonde -- La Plume qui s'envle au vent -- Mon pere avait 500 moutons -- La-bas sur ces montegnes -- Le P'tit avocat -- C'est le bon vin qui danse -- Marie Madelaine -- Le Retour du marin -- Pambelibelo -- Voila la recompense -- C'est a boire -- Le Petit mousse -- I went to the market --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.248 (10in.)</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Creole songs of Louisiana, Van Wey, Adelaide and Robert N. Hill</unittitle>
  			<unitdate label="copyright">1956</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 10 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>New York, N.Y., Folkways Records &amp; Service Corp. Remon -- Salangadon -- Lu-Lu-Lu -- Aine, De, Toue -- Paw' Piti' Mom'zelle Zizi -- Jacques, Jacques -- Compere lapin -- Papa va peche -- Tan' siro' E Dou' -- Maison Denise -- Street cries -- Hominy man -- Sand caller -- Pepper pot -- Rag man -- Horseradish seller -- Flower vendor -- Cantelope [vendor] -- Paralline seller -- Scissors grinder --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.249 (10in.)</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>The Rambling Irishman, Brandon, Tom</unittitle>
  			<unitdate label="copyright">1962</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Huntington, VT., Folk-Legacy Records, Inc. The Rambling Irishman -- The Irish soldier boy -- There is a lady in this town -- Muskoka -- The Maid of the mountain brow -- The "Lady Leroy" -- The Flying cloud -- The Trans-Canada highway -- The Rock Island Line -- The Croppy boy -- Kevin Barry -- Patrick Sheehan -- The Blarney stone -- My bonny black Bess -- Jack Haggerty --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.250</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>This Land is my land, Guthrie, Woody, Sam Eskin, Bill Banyon, Harry McClintock "Mac", Pete Seeger, Cisco Houston and Leadbelly</unittitle>
  			<unitdate label="copyright">1951</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 10 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>New York City, NY., Folkways Records &amp; Service Corp. Sung by Woody Guthrie: This land is my land... Sung by Sam Eskin: Lumbermen's alphabet... Sung by Bill Banyon: Down the hatch... [Sung by] Harry McClintock "Mac": Jerry go and oil that car... Sung by Pete Seeger: Young man who wouldn't hoe corn... Sung by Woody Guthrie: Columbia River... Sung by Cisco Houston: Old blue -- Down in the mines -- Whoopee ti yi yo... Sung by Leadbelly: Old man -- Haul away Joe --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.251 (10in.)</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pennsylvania Dutch Folk Singers, Britton, George</unittitle>
  			<unitdate label="copyright">1955</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 10 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>New York, NY., Folkways Records and Service Corp. Hei lie, Hei Lo -- Lauterbach -- Alle Yahr En Kindlein -- Wie Kumm ich an des Grosswadder's haus -- Unser Saiwi -- Schloof bobbeli Schoof -- Joe Ratel -- Reide, Reide, geile -- Des bucklich mennli -- Eiei, rete, ridd'eoo -- in Einem Kiehlen grunde -- Schpinn, schpinn -- Siss net alli daag luschdich leewe -- Meedli, Widdu Heiere? --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.252 (10in.)</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Music of the Sioux and Navajo</unittitle>
  			<unitdate label="copyright">1949</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>New York, NY., Folkways Records &amp; Service Corp. Recorded by Willard Rhodes at Wanblee and Pine Ridge, SD., The Sioux: Rabbit dance -- Peyote cult dance -- Love song -- Sun dance -- Omaha dance -- Love song -- Honoring song... Recorded at Fort Wingate, NM., Pine Springs, Toadalena and Lukachukai, AZ., Mesa Verde National Park, CO., The Navajo: Riding song -- Song of happiness -- Spinning dance -- Spinning dance -- Corn grinding song -- Squaw dance -- Silversmith's song -- Night chant --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.254</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Music of the World's People</unittitle>
  			<unitdate label="copyright">1951</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>New York, NY., Folkways Records &amp; Service Corp. Edited by Henry Cowell... Russian Gypsy -- Bali -- Arabia -- Tahiti -- Tibet (Chant-lament for the dead) -- United States (Pretty Polly) -- Iceland (Song of greeting - Hlidarendakoti) -- Spain (Panteras) --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.256</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Music of the world's peoples, vol. 2</unittitle>
  			<unitdate label="copyright">1952</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>New York, NY., Folkways Records &amp; Service Corp. Selected by Henry Cowell... Cuba (Sutileza) -- Finland (Velisurmaaja) -- Ukraine (There's a well in the field) -- Canada (Gaspian Bay): Adieu donc mes chers parents -- American Indians (Sioux): Courting melody -- Serbia (Ugasnule Oci Cerne) -- China (Hu-K'in melody) -- Italy (La novena dinatle) --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.257</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Music of the world's peoples, vol. 2</unittitle>
  			<unitdate label="copyright">1952</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>New York, NY., Folkways Records &amp; Service Corp. Selected by Henry Cowell... Cuba (Sutileza) -- Finland (Velisurmaaja) -- Ukraine (There's a well in the field) -- Canada (Gaspian Bay): Adieu donc mes chers parents -- American Indians (Sioux): Courting melody -- Serbia (Ugasnule Oci Cerne) -- China (Hu-K'in melody) -- Italy (La novena dinatle) --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.258</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Music of the world's peoples, vol. III</unittitle>
  			<unitdate label="copyright">1955</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>New York, NY., Folkways Records &amp; Service Corp. Compiled and edited by Dr. Henry Cowell... Mexico -- England (As I went out one May morning) -- Peru (Maraypatapi) -- Philippines ('Urukay chant) -- Philippines (Kalipay merrymaking) -- Puerto Rico (Baquine) -- Viet Nam (Instrumental) -- Bularia (Instrumental) -- Dahomey -- Washington Coast Indians (Bone game) -- Washington Coast Indians (Bone game) --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.259</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Music of the world's peoples, vol. III</unittitle>
  			<unitdate label="copyright">1955</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>New York, NY., Folkways Records &amp; Service Corp. Compiled and edited by Dr. Henry Cowell... Argentina -- Hungarian gypsy (Instrumental) -- Trinidad (fire brigade) -- Zululand (Instrumental) -- Yugoslavia (Epic song) -- Brazil (Bambo Du Bambu) -- Thailand (Classical music drama) -- Turkey (Gazel Niguie Gultchini) -- Egypt (Ya Bougaitha Hatll Gaddarah) --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.260</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections and Interview, Baird, Amy Hancock</unittitle>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 12 in</physdesc>
  			<abstract>University of Arizona Folklore Archive. Includes interview with Amy Hancock Baird, Safford, Arizona, on how she learned songs... Songs include: My sweet anoxa from Arizona -- Oh Rubin they tell me you are going away -- Where are you going, my pretty maid --</abstract>
  			<origination label="collector">Frances Gillmor</origination>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.375</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Baird, Amy Hancock</unittitle>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Amy Hancock Baird of Safford, Arizona sings: Young man who wouldn't hoe his corn -- Valley of Custer -- See a weary band of pilgrims -- O'er rugged hills and plains of sage -- Recorded by Frances Gillmor...</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.379</unitid>
  		</did> 
  		<custodhist><p>Original Collector: Frances Gillmor</p></custodhist>
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Gardner, Gail</unittitle>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>The Dude wrangler -- The Cowman's troubles -- Syerry Petes -- Moonshine steer --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.380</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Sea shanties, Borwn, Noble B. and Sailor Dad Hunt</unittitle>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Recorded by the University of Wisconsin Recording Project and sung by Noble B. Borwn, Millsville, Wisconsin, 1946: A Yankee ship came down the river (Blow boys blow)...  Recorded by Herbert Halpert and sung by Sailor Dad Hunt, Marion, Virginia, 1939: Blow the man down...</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.381</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Lewis, Phyllis and Margaret Eagle</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>1946</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Wisconsin Dells, University of Wisconsin Recording Project. Buffalo song. Zuni. (Phyllis Lewis, age 10) -- Buffalo song with drum. Zuni. (Phyllis Lewis, age 10) -- Corn grinding song (Margaret Eagle, age ca. 40) Scraping of feet indicates the sound of grinding corn. This is one of the few work songs -- Navajo riding song (Margaret Eagle). Sung by the men as they ride ponies -- Navajo night chant #1 (Margaret Eagle playing drum and shaking rattle) -- Navajo night chant #2 (Margaret Eagle). Both men and women sing this song -- Navajo night chant #3 (Margaret Eagle) --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.382</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Interview, Jones, Alden</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>April 8, 1956</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Sells, AZ. Byrd Granger interviews Alden Jones et al. on Papago place names...Recording was made during a tribal council meeting in Sells, Arizona, April 8, 1956...</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.385</unitid>
  		</did>
  		<custodhist><p>Original Collector: Frances Gillmor</p></custodhist>
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections and Narratives, Johnson, Molly</unittitle>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>There was a man -- other unidentified songs... Johnson briefly discusses how she learned these songs...</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.388</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections and Interviw</unittitle>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Man sings with banjo accompaniment... Robin Hood and the peddler -- Interview -- Interview -- Sweet William and little Margaret -- I haven't a house in Baltimore -- Old Uncle Ned tune --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.389</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Narratives</unittitle>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Anonymous man, interviewed by anonymous woman, lectures and translates Navajo words into English...</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.390</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections</unittitle>
  			<physdesc>4 sound discs, analog, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Soundcraft. Pre-1980-1/D.391-/D.406 are black, 12 inch discs...Each appears to have been cut, but no information is available on their contents...</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.391 - /D.406</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Ray, Mrs. John A.</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>May, 1948</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>: 1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Mesa, AZ. Recorded by Frances Gillmor for the University of Arizona Folklore Archive... Sung by Mrs. John A. Ray: Mein heart is broken all into little bits -- The Fallen leaf --</abstract>
  			<origination label="collector">Frances Gillmor</origination>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.23</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Ray, Mrs. John A.</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>May, 1948</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Mesa, AZ. Recorded by Frances Gillmor... Sung by Mrs. John A. Ray: The Union soldier's grave -- They tell me the valley is smiling and fair -- The Toad said to the bumble bee -- </abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.24</unitid>
  		</did>
  		<custodhist><p>Original Collector: Frances Gillmor</p></custodhist>
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 - Narratives, Anderson, M.F., Dr.</unittitle>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Tucson, AZ. Dr. M.F. Anderson of Tuscon, AZ, recalls legends and stories... Spoken in Swedish...</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.80</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections</unittitle>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 10 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>New York, N.Y., Columbia Phonograph Company, Inc. Corrido: El Caballo Mojino (by A. Reza and Ed. Tavo; performed by Pena, Dominquez, Valles, Gomez, the Cancioneros "Acosta", the Orquesta Acosta) -- Cancion: Oye las suplicas (by Ed. Tavo; performed by Valles, Fierio, Gomex, the Cancioneros "Acosta", the Orquesta Acosta) -- </abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.310 (10in.)</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Gonzalez, Pastor, y Cervantes</unittitle>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 10 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Columbia Phonograph Company. La Pajarera (Gonzalez, Pastor y Cervantes) -- No llores (Pastor y Cervantes) --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.311 (10in.)</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>La Virgencita, [Parts I and II], Posada, L. and P.J. Gonzalez</unittitle>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 10 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>New York, Columbia Phonograph Company, Inc. La Virgencita, 1a parte (J. Peralta) -- La Virgencita, 2a parte (J. Peralta) --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.312 (10in.)</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections</unittitle>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 10 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>New York, Okeh Phonograph Corporation. Recitations for Horacio C. Archilla: Palido, blanco y negro -- Adoracion --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.313 (10in.)</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Gardel, Carlos</unittitle>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 10 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Columbia [Phonograph Company, Inc.]. "Tomo y obligo" tango: Luces de Buenos Aires (Carlos Gardel and Manuel Romero) -- Tango: Como abrazado a un rencor (R. Rossi and Antonio M. Podesta) --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.314 (10in.)</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Mariachi Tapatio</unittitle>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 10 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Mexico, D.F., RCA Victor Mexicana, S.A. Huapango: Cana de azucar (Lorenzo Barcelata) -- Cancion Ranchera: La Rosita (unknown)... Both songs are from the film, "Bajo el cielo de Mexico"...</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.315 (10in.)</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Reyes, Lucha</unittitle>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 10 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Mexico, D.F., RCA Victor. Disc is cracked and chipped... In Spanish... La Tequilera, by Alfredo D'Orsay (Lucha Reyes y Orquesta Armando Rosales) -- Traigo un amor, by E. Cortazar and M. Esperon (Lucha Reyes con el Mariachi Vargar de Tecalitla) --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.316 (10in.)</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Guthrie, Woodie and Rebecca Tarwater</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>1936</unitdate>
  			<unitdate>1940</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 10 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>The Library of Congress Division of Music Recording Laboratory. Archive of American Folk Song. Recorded in Washington, D.C., 1940, by Alan Lomax and sung with guitar by Woodie Guthrie of Okemah, Oklahoma: The Gypsy Davy -- Recorded in Washington, D.C., 1936, by Charles Seeger and sung by Rebecca Tarwater of Rockwood, Tennessee: Barabara Allen --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.317 (10in.)</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Lee, Buck, Jimmy Denoon and Booth Campbell</unittitle>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>From paper insert: Recorded by Austin E. Fife and sung by Buck Lee, Clearfield, Utah, 1946: Billy Veniro, part 2.  This is the second half of a poem by Eben Rexford in "Youth's Companion".  Part 1 is on Pre-1980-1/D.356... Recorded by Vance Randolph and sung by Jimmy Denoon, Bradleyville, Missouri, 1942: Little old sod shanty... Sung by Booth Campbell, Cane Hill, Arkansas, 1942: Good old Rebel, or Unreconstructed Rebel. "Orginally a poem written by Innes Randolph, friend of Sidney Lanier, and has passed into folk tradition"...</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.318</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Anderson, Mrs. Eugenia Blount, and Bascom Lamar Lunsford</unittitle>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>From paper insert: Recorded by Duncan Emrich, Washington D.C., 1947, and sung by Mrs. Eugenia Blount Anderson, formerly of Macon Georgia, now of Baltimore, Maryland: Waillie, waillie or Cockle shells -- Careless love... Recorded by Artus M. Moser and sung by Bascom Lamar Lunsford at Swannanoa, North Carolina, 1946: Jesse James --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.319</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Mobeley, Pleaz</unittitle>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>From paper insert: Recorded by Artus M. Moser, Etowah, North Carolina, 1946, and sung by [?]: I believe in the good old Bible... Recorded by Artus M. Moser, 1946, and sung by Pleaz Mobeley of Manchester, Kentucky: Wayfaring stranger... Recorded by Artus M. Moser, Renfro Valley, Kentucky, 1946, and sung by [?]: John Reilly... Recorded by Artus M. Moser, 1946, and sung by Pleaz Mobeley of Manchester, Kentucky: Darling Corey...</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.320</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Eagle, Margaret</unittitle>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>From paper insert: Performed by Margaret Eagle (age ca. 40): Zuni rain dance song. Opening song of the rain dance, "Maybe this year I will have a good crop; watermelons on this side, corn on this side. Look in the sky, - a cloud is appearing and will bring rain." -- Lullaby. Zuni. "Go to sleep my little baby while I work. Father will bring in the sheep soon." -- Zuni-Comanache song. Pleasure dance song. Has no words, only chanted syllables. -- Zuni-Comanche song. Pleasure dance song #2 --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.321</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Jones, Lewis w. and L.M. Hilton</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>1946</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>The Library of Congress Division of Music Recording Laboratory. Recorded by Austin E. Fife, 1946... Sung by Lewis W. Jones of Monroe, Utah (age 77): Brighan, Brigham Young... Sung by L.M. Hilton of Ogden, Utah: Handcart song -- Pioneer Mormon --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.322</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Schaupp, Marianna and Mrs. May Kennedy McCord</unittitle>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>From paper insert: Recorded by Alan Lomax, Washington D.C., 1941, and sung by Marianna Schaupp of Knoxville, Tennessee: Robin Hood and Little John... Recorded by Vance Randolph, 1941, and sung by Mrs. May Kennedy McCord, Springfield, Missouri: The Brown girl -- Lord Thomas and Fair Eleanor --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.323</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Grover, Mrs. Carrie</unittitle>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>From paper insert: Recorded at Washington D.C., by Alan Lomax, 1941, and sung by Mrs. Carrie Grover of Gorham, Maine: The Loss of New Columbia, sea ballad from New England -- The Bay Biscay --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.324</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Hermanos Huesca</unittitle>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 10 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Mexico, D.F., Peerless. In Spanish... El Jarabe -- El Pajaro carpintero --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.325 (10in.)</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Tona la Negra [con] Orq. de Noe Fajaido</unittitle>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 10 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Mexico, D.F., Peerless. In Spanish... El Apagon (Esperon - Cortazar) -- Que hombre tan simpatico (Esperon - Cortazar) --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.326 (10in.)</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>La Mariquita; El Zopilote Mojada, Mariachi Vargas de Tecalitlan</unittitle>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog 10 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Mexico, D.F., RCA Victor Mexicana, S.A. El Zopilote mojado -- La Mariquita --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.327 (10in.)</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>CanCan; Paludismo Agudo, Alfonso, Esteban, and Hermanos Dominguez</unittitle>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 10 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Mexico, D.F., RCA Victor Mexicana, S.A. Paludismo Agudo -- Lira de San Cristobal -- CanCan -- Lira de San Cristobal -- Record is damaged...</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.328 (10in.)</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Himno Nacional; Historia del Himno Nacional de Guatemala, Santacoloma, German Boyer, Rafael Alvarez and J. Joaquin [Poma]</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>1949</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Ministerio de Educacion Publica; Republica de Guatemala. Historia del Himno Nactional de Guatemala, narada por German Bayer Santacolona -- Himno Nacional, lerra de J. Joaquin [Poma], musica de Rafael Alvarez, Orq. y Coro de la Opera Nacional, dirreccion: Miguel Sandoval --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.329</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Swann, Wallace, Chub Parham, Wade Ward, Herbert Snoke, and Pete Steele</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>1941</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Library of Congress Division of Music Recording Laboratory. Archive of American Folk Song. Recorded by Alan and Elizabeth Lomax... 5 string banjo tunes: Old Joe Clark (Wade Ward) -- Chilly winds (Wade Ward)  -- Cripple Creek (Herbert Snoke) -- Cole Creek March (Pete Steele)... Recorded by Alan Lomax and played by Wallace Swann and his Cherokee String Band, with square dancing, at Asheville Folk Festival, Asheville, N.C., 1941: John Henry... Recorded by Alan Lomax and played on the harmonica by Chub Parham, with clogging, at Asheville Folk Festival Festival, Asheville, N.C., 1941: The Train -- </abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.330</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>May 12, 1949</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Library of Congress Recording Laboratory. Sing-tra-la-loo-loo (Casa Grande) -- He was only just a cowboy (Phoenix) --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.331</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>May 12, 1949</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Library of Congress Recording Laboratory. Banks of the sweet Dundee -- Old man Crumble (Casa Grande) -- Under yonders tree (Casa Grande) --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.332</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Hilton, L.M.</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>1946</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Library of Congress Recording Laboratory. Recorded by Austin E. Fife and sung by L.M. Hilton of Ogden, Utah, 1946: Hard times -- Echo Canyon --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.333</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Watkins, Joseph H.</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>1946</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Library of Congress Recording Laboratory. Recorded by Austin E. Fife and sung by Joseph H. Watkins, age 85, of Brigham City, Utah: Utah Iron Horse -- Tittery-irie-aye --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.334</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Trio Tariacuri con El Mariachi Vargas de Tecalitlan</unittitle>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 10 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Mexico, D.F., RCA Victor Mexicana, S.A. In Spanish... No puedo contigo (Teddy Fregosa) -- No hay derecho (Chucho Monge) --  </abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.335 (10in.)</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Trio Tariacuri </unittitle>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 10 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Mexico, D.F., RCA Victor Mexicana. In Spanish... Revancha (Hmos. Martinez Gil) -- Coplas de Michoacan (Juan Mendoza) -- </abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.336 (10in.)</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Lucha Reyes con la Orquesta de Armando Rosales</unittitle>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 10 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Mexico, D.F., RCA Victor Mexicana. In Spanish... La Ranchita (Joaquin Pardave) -- Juan Colorado (F. Bermejo - A. Esparza Oteo) -- </abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.337 (10in.)</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Hermanas Padilla con Los Charros de Atotonilco</unittitle>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 10 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Columbia. In Spanish... Por un amor (Gilberto Parra) -- Cocula (Esperon y Cortazor) -- </abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.338 (10in.)</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music, Hmos. Sanchez y Linares con guitares</unittitle>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 10 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Decca. In Spanish.. Corrido de Joaquin Murrieta (Sanchez - Leal) -- </abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.339 (10in.)</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Los Tres Vaqueros</unittitle>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 10 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Mexico, D.F., RCA Victor Mexicana. In Spanish... La Bamba -- Pelea de gallos en San Marcos (Juan S. Garrido) -- </abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.340 (10in.)</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Trio Tariacuri con El Mariachi Vargas de Tecalitlan</unittitle>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 10 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Mexico, D.F., RCA Victor Mexicana. In Spanish... Ya semos dos (Cucho Monge) -- El Cupido (Son Jarocho)  -- </abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.341 (10in.)</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Rubio y Martinez, Duo</unittitle>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 10 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>New York, N.Y., Columbia Phonograph Company, Inc. Direction by A. Esparza Oteo... In Spanish... Mi gusto es (Alfonso Esparza Oteo) -- El Novel y deapuntado (arranged by Ernesto Rubio) -- </abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.342 (10in.)</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Tanco, Ernesto and Carlota Flores</unittitle>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 10 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Camden, N.J., Victor Talking Machine Co. Los Marihuanoas - dialogo callejero (The Dope fiends)  -- Mamorto el griago - dialogo callejero -- In Spanish...</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.343 (10in.)</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Niles, John Jacob</unittitle>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 10 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Camden, N.J., RCA Victor Division of Radio Corporation of America. Collected and arranged by J.J. Niles and [performed by] John Jacob Niles, mountaineer tenor, with dulcimer accompaniment: The Wife of Usher's Well -- The Death of Queen Jane --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.344 (10in.)</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Niles, John Jacob</unittitle>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 10 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Camden, N.J., RCA Victor Division of Radio Corporation of America. Collected and arranged by J.J. Niles... Little Mattie Groves (John Jacob Niles, mountaineer tenor, with dulcimer accompaniment) --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.345 (10in.)</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>The Folk songs of Britain: Volume 5, The Child ballads</unittitle>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in. </physdesc>
  			<abstract>New York, N.Y., Caedmon Records Inc. The Royal forester -- The Baffled knight -- Johnie Cock -- Robin Hood and Little John -- The Jew's garden -- The Battle of Harlaw -- The Four Maries -- The Gypsy laddie -- Georgie -- The Dowie Dens of Yarrow -- Glenlogie -- The Grey cock -- Henry Martin   -- Lang Johnny More -- Willie's fate -- Our goodman -- The Farmer's curst wife -- The Jolly beggar -- The Auld beggarman -- The Keach in the creel -- The Golden vanity -- The Trooper lad -- </abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.347</unitid>
  		</did>
  		<custodhist><p>Original Collector: Peter Kennedy and Alna Lomax</p></custodhist>
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Folk songs of Britain; Volume VI: Sailormen and Servingmaids</unittitle>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>New York, N.Y., Caedmon Records Inc. Paddy West -- The Liverpool packet -- The Green banks of Yarrow -- Our gallant ship -- The Alehouse -- Rosemary Lane -- Ratcliffe highway -- The Lowlands of Holland -- The Quaker -- Kishmul's gallery -- The Whale fishery -- The Grey silkie -- Warlike seamen -- The Boat that first brought me over -- The Handsome cabin boy -- The Unst boat song -- The Smacksman -- Sweet Willie -- The Campanero -- Andress Ross -- The Bold princess royal -- The Boatie rows -- Our ship is ready -- Nancy from Yarmouth --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.348</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Folk songs of Britain; Volume VIII: A Soldier's life for me</unittitle>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>New York, N.Y., Caedmon Records Inc. List, bonnie laddie -- Swansea barracks -- The Dying soldier   -- Willie O'Reilly -- The Bonnet o' blue -- Recruiting song  -- William Taylor -- Johnny Harte -- The Soldier and the sailor -- Bold General Wolfe -- Muddley barracks -- Handsome Polly -- The Deadly wars -- McCaffery -- Drink old England dry -- Prince Charlie Stuart -- Ny son Tim -- Napoleon Buon-le-Parte -- The Bonny bunch of Roses O -- Napoleon's dream -- The Forfar soldier --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.349</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Song plays and play party games for the elementary school, The Folkrafters</unittitle>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, [45 rpm], 7 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Newark, N.J., Folkraft Records. Performed by The Folkrafters, Frank L. Kaltman, director... Project supervised by Olga Kulbitsky, Hunter College, New York City... Round and round the village (Go in and out the window) -- Bridge of Avignon (French song play) -- A-hunting we will go (English song play) --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.350 (7in.)</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Briceno, Alcides y Jorge Anez</unittitle>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 10 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Camden, N.J., Victor talking Machine Co. Performed by Alcides Briceno y Jorge Anez, [with orchestra]... Son popular: La Higuerita (The Honey girl, by Victor Mendoza) -- Cancion: La Pielera (The Railroad girl) --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.351 (10in.)</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Cueto, M. and C. Mejia</unittitle>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 10 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Camden, N.J., Radio-Victor Corp. of America. Performed by M. Cueto and C. Mejia, [with orchestra]... Corrido: El Vacilon (The High stepper, by J. Cordova Cantu) -- Corrido: El Ingrato (The Ungrateful one, arr. by J. Cordova --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.352 (10in.)</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Trio Calaveras</unittitle>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 10 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Mexico, D.F., RCA Victor Mexicana SA. Performed by Trio Calaveras... Cancion: La Barca de oro (Abundio Martinez), [from the film] "Las Abandonadas" -- Cancion ranchera: Copitas de Mezcal (Chucho Palacios) --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.353 (10in.)</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Chaves y Lugo</unittitle>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>New York, Columbia Phonograph Company, Inc. Performed by Chaves y Lugo, [accompanied by guitars]... Corridos: El Lavaplatos, part 1 and part 2 (Jesus ?) --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.354</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Lunsford, Bascom Lamar, Estelle Morris and Russ Pike</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>1941</unitdate>
  			<unitdate>1946</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Sung by Bascom Lamar Lunsford at Swannanoa, North Carolina, 1946, and recorded by Artus M. Moser: The Death of Queen Jane (child ballad) -- Wake, oh, wake, you drowsy sleeper... Sung by Estelle Morris of Franklin, Tennessee, and recorded by Artus M. Moser at Renfro Valley, Kentucky: The Knoxville girl (Development of "The Wexford girl", "Oxford girl", or "The Cruel miller", "The Wittam miller")... Sung by Russ Pike at Visalia, California, and recorded by Charles Todd and Robert Sonkin, 1941: The Railroader -- </abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.355</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Paytiamo, James (Flaming Arrow) and Buck Lee</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>1946</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Two social dances performed by James Paytiamo "Flaming Arrow", and recorded at Wisconsin Dells, Wisconsin, by University of Wisconsin Recording Project: Hopi corn song, "At the time of the new moon setting in the West, comes the rain. Four days later, plant the corn. Four days later comes the shoot. When the tassle ripens, I reap abundant" -- Hey - come my friend (Navajo)... Sung by Buck Lee, Clearfield, Utah, 1946, and recorded by Austin E. Fife: Billy Veniro, part I -- </abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.356</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Golden slumbers: Lullabies from near and far</unittitle>
  			<unitdate label="copyright">1973</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, (34:26), analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Performers include: Oscar Brand, Pete Seeger, Jean Ritchie, Frank Cooke, Juanita Cascone, Ruth Welcome, Elizabeth Knight, Wallace House, Robin Roberts... All the pretty horses -- Twinkle, twinkle, little star -- Sleep, little one, sleep  -- Raisins and almonds -- Go to bed first -- Dance to your daddy -- Rock-a-bye baby -- Hush lit'l baby -- Simba -- Bye, baby bunting -- Petit chat noir -- Golden slumbers -- Pretty boy in the country-o -- Bye'n bye -- Sleep, baby -- Coventry carol -- Cuc-a-nandy -- Kiowa lullaby -- Lalo -- Can ye sew cushions -- Who killed cock robin --Dance to your daddy -- Little Pierrot -- Sleep, baby, sleep -- </abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.357</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Blues roots: Mississippi</unittitle>
  			<unitdate label="copyright">1966</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Compiled and edited by Samuel Charters... Canned heat blues (Tommy Johnson) -- Bif fat mama blues (Tommy Johnson) --- Big road blues (Tommy Johnson) -- Barbeque bust (Mississippi Jook Band) -- My grey pony (Joe Williams) -- Cigaret blues (Bo Carter) -- All around man (Bo Carter) -- I believe I'll dust  my broom (Robert Johnson) -- Honeymoon blues (Robert Johnson) -- That lonesome train took my baby away (Charlie McCoy) -- Whiskey head man (Tommy McClennan) -- Bertha Lee blues (Robert Petway) -- Miss Louise blues (Sonny Ray Williamson) -- Until my love comes down (Sonny Ray Williamson) --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.358</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Larry Richardson, Red Barker and the Blue Ridge Boys</unittitle>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Let me fall (Happy Smith) -- You left me so blue (Larry Richardson) -- More pretty girls than one (arr. Larry Richardson) -- I don't love nobody (P.D.) -- Paul and Silas (arr. Larry Richardson and Red Barker) -- John Henry (arr. Larry Richardson) -- Pain in my heart (Larry Richardson and Bob Osborne) -- Little Pal (arr. Larry Richardson) -- Liberty (P.D.) -- Wild over me (arr. Larry Richardson) -- Sad and lonesome day (arr. Larry Richardson and Red Barker) -- My home's across the Blue Ridge Mountains (arr. Larry Richardson and Red Barker) --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.359</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Songs and dances of Great Lakes Indians</unittitle>
  			<unitdate label="copyright">1956</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>New York City, N.Y., Folkways Records and Services Corp. Ethnic Folkways Library. Musical selections by various performers include: Algonquians, Iroquis animal and war dances, Food spirit dances, and Future prospects... Tribes represented include Ojibwa, Ottawa, Meskwaki, Onondaga, Cayuga, Ontario, Huron and Seneca...</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.360</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Spanish and Mexican folk music of New Mexico</unittitle>
  			<unitdate label="copyright">1952</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>[New York, N.Y.], Folkways Record &amp; Service Corp. Ethnic Folkways Library. Recorded by J.D. Robb in New Mexico... Matachines dances (James Trujillo, Sam and Modesto Garcia) -- Huapango (Garcilian Pacheco) -- Entriega de novios (Felix Ortega) -- Polka (Librado Leyba and Eddie Ortiz) -- La Luna se va matiendo (Alfred Campos and Edwin Lobato) -- Cuatro caminos -- (Alfred Campos and Edwin Lobato) -- El Zapatero (Arthur L. Campa) -- Grasshopper waltz (Daniel Lopez) -- Cancion Ingles (Jacobo Maestas) -- Hymn of farewell (Congregation with violin and guitar) -- Corrido de Elena (Felix Ortega and Consuela Ortega) -- Jesusita (Vidal Valdez and Lupe Rodriguez) -- Para que me sirvo el vino (Daniel Lopez and Lupe Rodriguez) -- Trova del viego vilmas (Arvino Martinez) -- Cuna (Jacobo Maestras and Victor Frescas) --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.361</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Music of La Raza, Vol. 1, Los Pinguinos del Norte</unittitle>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Tradition Music Co. Produced by Chris Strachwitz and Rumel Fuentes... El Contrbando del paso (Juarez and Gaytan) -- Jacinto Trevino (Juarez and Gaytan) -- El Gallito (Rueben Juarez) -- Dos hermanos (Juarez and Gaytan) -- Mexico Americano (Rumel Fuentes) -- El Desperado (R. Juarez and H. Gaytan) -- Gregorio Cortez (Juarez and Gaytan) -- Benjamin Argumedo (Juarez and Gaytan) -- Carga blanca (Gaytan and Escalante) --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.362</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Slim Critchlow, Cowboy songs: The Crooked trail to Holbrook, Critchlow, Slim</unittitle>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Produced by Chris Strachwitz and Barry Oliver: The Crooked trail to Holbroook -- Borax Bill -- The Trail to Mexico -- Forty a month and found -- The Brazos River --   D-Bar-2 horse wrangler -- Windy Bill -- Goodbye Old Paint -- Bucking bronco -- I'd like to be in Texas -- The Buffalo skinner -- The Cowboy's lament -- Wild buckaroo -- Snag tooth Sal -- The Trusty lariat -- John Garner's trail herd -- Whiskey Bill -- The Last wagon --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.363</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Authentic cowboys and their Western folksongs</unittitle>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>RCA Corporation. The Old Chisolm Trail ("Mac" McClintock) -- Powder River, let 'er buck (Powder River Jack and Kitty Lee) -- Following the cow trail (Carl T. Sprague) -- Zebra dun (Jules Allen) -- Bill was a Texas lad (J.D. Farley) -- Utah Carroll (Carl T. Sprague) -- There's a brown skin girl down the road (A.C. "Eck" Robertson) -- The Cowboy's dream (Jules Allen) -- When the work's all done this fall (Carl T. Sprague) -- Bucking broncho, my love is a rider (Mildred and Dorothy Good) -- Sam Bass ("Mac" McClintock) -- Tying a knot in the devil's tail (Powder River Jack and Kitty Lee) -- Texas Ranger (Cartwright Brothers) -- The Mormon cowboy (Carl T. Sprague)   -- The Night guard (Jack Webb) -- Haunted hunter (Billie Maxwell) --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.364</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Ellie Mao sings Chinese folk songs, Mao, Ellie and Anna Mi Lee</unittitle>
  			<unitdate label="copyright">1963</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>[New York, N.Y.], Folkways Records and Service Corp. The Sweeping wind -- In a far-away place -- The Funny old man -- Heartache -- A Festive song -- The Embroidered purse -- Digging potatoes -- Wu Ke tends the sheep -- Hanging red lanterns -- Lo-ho-ho -- The Nine-ring puzzle -- Clear is the river -- Kite-flying -- When the gardenias bloom -- Bean sprouts, scallions and garlic cloves --The Washerwoman -- My love is like a dragon in the sky -- The Mule driver's song -- A Guessing song -- Riding up the hill -- The Little birds -- Song of the wagon driver -- The Little swallow -- Majira -- The Happy fisherman -- The Little cabbage -- The Bamboo flute -- Flower drum song --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.365</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Lithuanian folk songs in the United States</unittitle>
  			<unitdate label="copyright">1955</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>New York, N.Y., Folkways Record &amp; Service Corp. Ethnic Folkways Library. Recorded by Dr. Jonas Balys... Sutartine (Choral round) -- Volungele (The Little golden oriole) -- Vidur Lauku (In the midst of the field) -- Nesigraudyk, merguzele (Do not be sorrowful little girl) -- Kaip as per zalia girela (Riding across a forest of green) -- Vai leidzia duoda (Oh, he is giving away) -- Oi as isejan an dvara (I go into the yard) -- Oi smutnas luidnas (Oh, how low sad and mournful) -- Vaikscio' mociute ( The Mother was walking) -- Vai broli (Oh, brother) -- Susapnavu dimna sapna (I dreamed a strange dream) -- Mergele grazi (Oh, beautiful girl) -- Oi stovi stovi (Oh there are standing) -- Oi klevi kleveli (Oh you little maple) -- Vai kaip as buvau (Oh, when I lived) -- Ulijana (Julia) -- SIle pusynai (In the conifer forest) -- Is karcmuzeles (Leaving an inn) -- Vaikseiojo tevulis (The Father was walking) -- Jau saulele teka (The Sun is rising) -- </abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.367</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Folk music of Ghana</unittitle>
  			<unitdate label="copyright">1964</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>New York, N.Y., Folkways Record and Service Corp. Ethnic Folkways Library. Recorded in Ghana by Ivan Annan -- Akonodey -- Adaarve -- Ataa oblanyo -- Simpa -- Agbaja -- Agbaja -- Kumi 'na gyaemi -- Gome (Mr. Jacobson) -- Gome (Janja) -- Akorah anumah -- Abosuan -- Asafo -- Asaaye -- Kolomashie --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.368</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Lappish joik songs from Northern Norway</unittitle>
  			<unitdate label="copyright">1956</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>New York City, N.Y., Folkways Record &amp; Service Corp. Ethnic Folkways Library. Recorded by Wolfgang Laade and Pieter Christensen... Various folk songs by various performers from Northern Norway...</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.369</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Jazz, Vol. 10: Boogie woogie and jump</unittitle>
  			<unitdate label="copyright">1953</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>[New York], N.Y., Folkways Records &amp; Service Corp. Records from the collection of Frederic Ramsey, Jr..... Boogie woogie: Jim Jackson's jamboree, part 1 -- Jim Jackson's jamboree, cont'd. --  Hastings Street -- St. Louis blues -- Honky tonk train -- Brown skin gal -- Yancey stomp -- Jump and Kansas City: Let 'em jump -- Toby -- Froggy bottom -- Boogie woogie -- Hootie blues -- Lester leaps in -- Dickie's dream --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.370</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>The Unquiet grave: American tragic ballads, Summers, Andrew Rowan</unittitle>
  			<unitdate label="copyright">1952</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>New York City, N.Y., Folkways Record &amp; Service Corp. Performed by Andrew Rowan Summers accompanying himself on the dulcimer: The Unquiet grave -- Searching for lambs -- Pretty Sally -- The True lover's farewell -- The Cruel brother -- Geordie -- At the foot of Yonders Mountain -- The House carpenter --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.371</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre 1980 Folk music. Selections</unittitle>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>From paper insert, "The two ladies &amp; the man with the concertina from the Jewish Cultural Center"...</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.372</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre 1980 Folk music. Selections</unittitle>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Recorded [in the] Wisconsin Dells by University of Wisconsin Recording Project, 1946... Performed by Margaret Eagle (age ca. 40) and Phyllis Lewis (age 10): Eagle dance. Zuni -- Dance song, "When the dance is over you must wait for me; I will take you home in my barrow [on my burro]. When the dance is over you must wait for me; I will take you home in my flivver." -- Lullaby. Zuni... Performed by James Paytiamo (Flaming Arrow): Wedding sosngs. Acoma... From the Tusque Pueblo: Buffalo dance song -- 2nd Buffalo dance song --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.373</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre 1980 Folk music. Selections, Hinton, Sam and Pleaz Mobeley</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>1947</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Recorded by Duncan Emrich and George Steele, Washington, D.C., 1947... Sung by Sam Hinton of La Jolla, California: Mary Hamilton (The Four Marys) -- Katy Cruel... Recorded by Artus M. Moser at Renfro Valley, Kentucky, 1946, and sung by Pleaz Mobeley of Manchester, Kentucky: My parents raised me tenderly --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.374</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre 1980 Folk music. Selections, Baird, Amy Hancock</unittitle>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Safford, AZ. Recorded by F. [Frances] Gillmor... I'll hang my heart on a willow tree and off to the wars again -- God pity Bessie, the drunkard's love child -- God pity Bessie, the drunkard's love child -- Tis of a young sailor with courage stout and bold --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.376</unitid>
  		</did>
  		<custodhist><p>Original Collector: Frances Gillmor</p></custodhist>
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre 1980 Folk music. Selections, Baird, Amy Hancock</unittitle>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Safford, AZ. Recorded by [Frances] Gillmor... I should dearly love to marry -- As I was walking one morning in May --  As I was walking one morning in May -- </abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.377</unitid>
  		</did> 
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre 1980 Folk music. Selections, Baird, Amy Hancock</unittitle>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Safford, AZ. Recorded by Frances Gillmor -- The Hunter winds his bugle horn -- Green Bill -- I was born in Boston -- Willie Gray -- My grandmother lived on yonder little green --</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.378</unitid>
  		</did> 
  		<custodhist><p>Original Collector: Frances Gillmor</p></custodhist>
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Interview, Upplegger, Dr. [Francis] (1867-1964)</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>March 25, 1956</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>San Carlos, AZ. Byrd Granger interviews Dr. Upplegger on Apache place names on March 25, 1956 in San Carlos, AZ....</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.383</unitid>
  		</did> 
  		<custodhist><p>Original Collector: Byrd Granger</p></custodhist>
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Interview, Upplegger, Dr. [Francis] (1867-1964)</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>March 25, 1956</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>San Carlos, AZ. Byrd Granger interviews Rev. Upplegger on Apache names on March 25, 1956 in San Carlos, AZ....</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.384</unitid>
  		</did>
  		<custodhist><p>Original Collector: Byrd Granger</p></custodhist>
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Interview, Upplegger, Dr. [Francis] (1867-1964)</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>March 25, 1956</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Byrd Granger interviews Dr. Upplegger on March 25, 1956 regarding the Hopi place names... Do not transcribe...</abstract>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.386</unitid>
  		</did> 
  		<custodhist><p>Original Collector: Byrd Granger</p></custodhist>
  	</c01>
  	<c01> 
  		<did> 
  			<unittitle>Pre-1980 Interview, Upplegger, Dr. [Francis] (1867-1964)</unittitle>
  			<unitdate>March 25, 1956</unitdate>
  			<physdesc>1 sound disc, analog, 12 in.</physdesc>
  			<abstract>Byrd Granger interviews Dr. Upplegger on March 25, 1956 regarding the Hopi place names... Do not transcribe...</abstract>
  			<origination label="collector">Byrd Granger</origination>
  			<unitid>SWF PRE1980.1/D.387</unitid>
  		</did> 
  		<custodhist><p>Original Collector: Byrd Granger</p></custodhist>
  	</c01>
  </dsc> 
</archdesc></ead>